<Document>
  # Path of Flesh
  The Path of Flesh focuses on summoning player-controlled minions and demons to do your bidding. Heretics on this path gain almost no offensive or defensive abilities, and rely heavily on stockpiling corpses and organs to complete rituals.

  Despite this, it offers many fun and powerful tools to those who can make it to the end, making it a difficult (but satisfying) path overall for inexperienced Heretics. Ascending allows you to shed your human form and become something much greater. 

  ## Principle of Hunger
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HereticBladeFlesh" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Opens up the Path of Flesh to you.

  Allows you to transmute a knife and a pool of blood into a Bloody Blade.

  ## Grasp of Flesh
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TouchSpellMansus" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Your Mansus Grasp gains the ability to create a ghoul out of corpse with a soul.

  Ghouls have only 50 health and look like husks to the heathens' eyes, but can use Bloody Blades effectively.

  ## Imperfect Ritual
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodPoppy" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Allows you to transmute a corpse and a poppy to create a Voiceless Dead.

  The corpse does not need to have a soul.

  Voiceless Dead are mute ghouls and only have 100 health, but can use Bloody Blades effectively.

  ## Mark of Flesh
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TouchSpellMansus" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Your Mansus Grasp now applies the Mark of Flesh. The mark is triggered from an attack with your Bloody Blade.

  When triggered, the victim violently spills all it's blood on the ground.

  ## Knitting of Flesh
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanHeart" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Grants you the spell Knit Flesh. This spell allows you to remove organs from victims without requiring a lengthy surgery. This process is much longer if the target is not dead.

  This spell also allows you to heal your minions and summons, or restore failing organs to acceptable status.

  ## Raw Ritual
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGhoulProphet" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Allows you to transmute a pair of eyes, a stomach, and a pool of blood to create a Raw Prophet.

  Raw Prophets have a long range jaunt and the ability to link minds to communicate with ease, but are very fragile and weak in combat.

  ## Bleeding Steel
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HereticBladeFlesh" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Your Bloody Blade now causes enemies to bleed heavily on attack.

  ## Lonely Ritual
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGhoulStalker" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Allows you to transmute a heart, a stomach, lungs and a pen to create a Stalker.

  Stalkers can jaunt, release EMPs, and are strong in combat.

  ## Priest’s Final Hymn
  The ascension ritual of the Path of Flesh. Bring 4 corpses to a transmutation rune to complete the ritual.

  When completed, you gain the ability to shed your human form and become the Lord of the Night, a supremely powerful creature.

  Just the act of transforming causes nearby heathens great fear and trauma.

  While in the Lord of the Night form, you can consume the living to heal.
</Document>
