<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 gluesniffler <159397573+gluesniffler@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Organ Manipulation
These surgeries allow you to remove or replace organs from a patient for healthy ones. Which can help treat conditions on their bodies.

## Anatomy
Normally a body has the following organs:

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanBrain" Caption="brain"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanEyes" Caption="eyes"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanHeart" Caption="heart"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanKidneys" Caption="kidneys"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanLiver" Caption="liver"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanLungs" Caption="lungs"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanStomach" Caption="stomach"/>
</Box>

Certain species might have more or less organs, such as Diona having a combined organ that serves multiple functions, but this is the rough outline of what you'll see.
To remove an organ, you'll need to apply the respective Organ Removal surgery on it, which will then remove it without harming the patient.

However if you want to transplant an organ, you'll need to apply the respective Organ Transplant surgery where it originally was.

## What does each organ transplant do?

- Transplanting a [color=#a4885c]brain[/color] will allow the patient to take over another body. An excellent alternative to cloning if you can afford to spare another body.
- Transplanting a [color=#a4885c]liver[/color] will cure severe poisoning from a patient's body.
- Transplanting [color=#a4885c]lungs[/color] will help cure patients from severe asphyxiation.
- Transplanting a [color=#a4885c]heart[/color] will cure a patient's body of rot and decay.
- Transplanting [color=#a4885c]eyes[/color] will allow the patient to see again, and heal any eye damage.

## Where do I get more organs?

Normally when your patients come in needing new organs, they'll need to get a new one, as their old ones will be either missing, or damaged beyond repair.
For this you can use the Medical Biofabricator with some Biomass. Which can manufacture Biosynthetic organs for all species.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBiofabricator" Caption="medical biofabricator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBiofabMachineBoard" Caption="biofabricator board"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialBiomass" Caption="biomass"/>
</Box>

By default, every Chief Medical Officer has access to a Medical Biofabricator board in their locker.

## Why didn't the organ transplant
## do anything?

Your patient's body rejected the organ as it is in a bad shape, try using a fresh organ from a donor, or getting a new one from the Medical Biofabricator.

</Document>
