<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 gluesniffler <159397573+gluesniffler@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Piras314 <p1r4s@proton.me>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 SX-7 <92227810+SX-7@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Part Manipulation
  This is how you will turn Tajaran into humans, or vice versa if you're feeling particularly cruel.

  ## Anatomy
  Normally a body has 11 main parts. Those being:

  <Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HeadHuman" Caption="head"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RightHandHuman" Caption="right hand"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RightArmHuman" Caption="right arm"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChestHuman" Caption="torso"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GroinHuman" Caption="groin"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LeftArmHuman" Caption="left arm"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LeftHandHuman" Caption="left hand"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RightFootHuman" Caption="right foot"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RightLegHuman" Caption="right leg"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LeftLegHuman" Caption="left leg"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LeftFootHuman" Caption="left foot"/>
</Box>

Certain species might have more or less parts, such as tails, wings, or extra limbs, but this is the rough outline of what you'll see.
To detach a limb, you'll need to apply the Remove Part surgery on it, which will then remove it without harming the patient.

However if you want to reattach the limb, you'll need to apply the Attach Part surgery where you want it attached.
Hands are attached to the arms, feet are attached to the legs. And everything else is attached to the torso.


## Where do I get more parts?

Normally when your patients come in needing new limbs, they'll need to get a new one, as their old ones will be either missing, or damaged beyond repair.
For this you can use the Medical Biofabricator with some Biomass. Which can manufacture Biosynthetic limbs for all species.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBiofabricator" Caption="medical biofabricator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBiofabMachineBoard" Caption="biofabricator board"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialBiomass" Caption="biomass"/>
</Box>

By default, every Chief Medical Officer has access to a Medical Biofabricator board in their locker.

## I reattached my patient's limb, but
## it's not working?

Your patient has taken enough damage to the point that their limb's nerves were badly damaged, and they need to be healed properly before it can work again.
For this you can try the Tend Wounds surgeries, or letting them use topicals on their wounds.

</Document>
