<Document>
# Plant Genetics
Like all other forms of life known to NanoTrasen, plants pass traits to offspring in their genes. By manipulating plant genetics, botanists can produce plant varieties with desirable mutations that increase plant health and yield.

## Traits
The phenotype, or set of observable characteristics and traits of a plant, can be determined through careful observation and study. A few common traits include:

- [color=lightgreen]Bioluminescence[/color]: plants with this trait glow in the dark
- [color=lightgreen]High yield[/color]: plants with this trait yield more fruit per harvest
- [color=lightgreen]Less water[/color]: plants with this trait require less water than normal to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Ligneous[/color]: plants with this trait require sharp tools to harvest
- [color=lightgreen]Long life[/color]: plants with this trait live for more harvest cycles before dying
- [color=lightgreen]Low light[/color]: plants with this trait need less light than normal to grow
- [color=lightgreen]Pest resistance[/color]: plants with this trait are more resistant to pests
- [color=lightgreen]Seedless[/color]: plants with this trait do not produce viable seeds
- [color=lightgreen]Weed resistance[/color]: plants with this trait suppress weed growth

You can determine the phenotype of a plant simply by growing them and observing them! This is how Gregor Mendel, father of genetics, studied them in 1866.

## Mutations
Plants treated with [color=cyan]unstable mutagen[/color] will experience random genetic mutations, which can alter their genes and result in changes to their traits. You can save the plants with mutations you want by harvesting their seeds.

The more unstable mutagen you use, the more mutations you will get. Since many genes are vital to a plant's survival, most mutations will cause a plant to die.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="UnstableMutagenChemistryBottle"/>
</Box>

## Cross-Pollination
You can use a [color=cyan]sterile swab[/color] to transfer pollen from one plant to another. Plants that are cross-pollinated have a chance to transfer traits. Be careful re-using swabs; pollen is sticky!

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BoxMouthSwab"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DiseaseSwab"/>
</Box>

</Document>
