<Document>
# Command

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignHead" Caption="" />
  </Box>

Space Station 14 is commanded by its Captain and a set of Department Heads, who together are referred to as the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] department. Department Heads are often called "Heads of Staff" or, simply, "Heads".

Department Heads have access to their own special equipment and, usually, their own rooms aboard the station. They are often wanted dead by the Syndicate and other agents hostile to Nanotrasen.

## Personnel
The following roles on the Station are part of the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] department, in addition to any other department they are part of:

- The [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color]
- The [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color]
- The [color=#cb0000]Head of Security[/color]
- The [color=#5b97bc]Chief Medical Officer[/color]
- The [color=#f39f27]Chief Engineer[/color]
- The [color=#c96dbf]Research Director[/color]
- The [color=#b18644]Quartermaster[/color]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineCaptain" Caption="Captain"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineHeadOfPersonnel" Caption="HoP"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineHeadOfSecurity" Caption="HoS"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineChiefMedicalOfficer" Caption="CMO"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineChiefEngineer" Caption="CE"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineResearchDirector" Caption="RD"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineQuartermaster" Caption="QM"/>
  </Box>

All Department Heads share the role of keeping Space Station 14 vaguely tolerable to work on. The Captain functions as the head of [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] department, guiding and resolving disputes between Department Heads.

## Taking Charge
Congratulations on your promotion! Your new [color=#a4885c]responsibilities[/color] include:

- The shift-to-shift running of your department
- Making plans, prioritizing activities and responding to changes to the station
- Keeping your personnel safe and happy and, more importantly, keeping Nanotrasen's equipment safe from damage or loss
- Approving or denying requests from staff, which tends to involve stamps and [color=#9fed58]blessed paperwork[/color]
- Not being assassinated by the Syndicate
- Not being overthrown by your subordinates in a mutiny
- Recruiting new staff to department roles
- Slacking off while your cronies do all the work

But don't forget, you're still a member of your department! Your fancy title doesn't earn you the shift off; you need to fill in for any staffing shortages, help out struggling staff, and teach department newbies the ropes. You might get away with just sitting around and bathing in your staff's resentment, but it's smarter to stay active and work alongside them. It also gives you witnesses if anyone tries to kill you.

You should allow your staff to work on what they like doing, or what they do best, provided that the important responsibilities of your department are fulfilled. You may also need to discipline your staff, or suspend them from duty, if they have been unusually bad for the department's functionality (even by Nanotrasen's rock-bottom standards).

## The Captain

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatCaptain" Caption="The most fashionable and sought-after headpiece in local spess." />
  </Box>

The Captain is the most senior member of staff on Space Station 14, and are the Department Head of the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] department. They are the sole role on the station that is only a member of the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] department. Their job is to make sure Space Station 14 does what Nanotrasen wants, directing and leading the Department Heads as needed to do so, rather than micromanaging the station's departments. Otherwise, the Captain is concerned with keeping the Bridge, their personal domain, in good condition. In general, the Captain should only be picking up a welding torch or fighting a space dragon as a last resort.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobFoxRenault" Caption="Not a Vulpkanin." />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHamsterHamlet" Caption="Do not microwave." />
  </Box>

The Captain has access to some very powerful, shift-impacting equipment and items. The most important of these is the nuke disk. This contains the authentication codes required to arm the station's nuke, which functions as Space Station 14's self-destruct mechanism. For obvious reasons, do not allow the nuke disk to fall into enemy hands.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NukeDisk" Caption="THIS IS YOUR MOST IMPORTANT POSESSION, SECURE DAT FUKKEN DISK!" />
  </Box>

As Captain, it's important to remember that, when the station is operating normally and everyone is doing their jobs, your job in turn is to be seen and available, not to act like the protagonist. Leave micromanagement of each department to their Department Head. Instead, make sure that each department is working nicely with the others. Do not spend your time roaming the maintenance tunnels looking for trouble.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CaptainSabre" Caption="This is a symbol of office, not an excuse to go valid-hunting." />
  </Box>

The Captain should also attempt to keep all Department Head roles filled. The Captain is not expected to perfectly understand how all Department Heads do their own jobs, and should not be expected to fill in themselves except when absolutely neccessary.

## Your Locker

To help with your new exciting, dangerous and/or soul-crushing tasks, every Department Head is given special items to fulfil their duties with. Most of your tools can be found in your [color=#a4885c]locker[/color].
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerHeadOfPersonnel" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerCaptain" Caption="Goodies contained inside."/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerHeadOfSecurity" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

Your [color=#a4885c]door remote[/color] is a simple but powerful tool. Door remotes can open and close [color=#a4885c]airlocks[/color], spin a door's [color=#a4885c]bolts[/color] to lock them, and enable or disable [color=#a4885c]emergency access[/color]. It can even do these actions from a distance. Don't let the clown steal it!
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteCommand" Caption="Door stuck? Not anymore!"/>
  </Box>

The door remote influences where people move around. Department Heads can lock staff out of dangerous areas, secure the department in times of crisis, or let people in to grab something quickly.

## Command Radio

All Command staff have access to the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] radio channel. This radio channel is a powerful tool to communicate across departments quickly and co-ordinate the station in emergencies. Everyone on the Command channel has [color=#a4885c]entire departments[/color] at their fingertips. The station AI is also available to talk to on the channel.

Use the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] channel to communicate with other Department Heads and represent what your staff want or need.

The [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color] and the [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color] get access to the lucrative [color=#a4885c]master encryption key[/color], letting them tune into every radio channel on the station. This is extremely valuable, as you can coordinate between departments yourself.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyStationMaster" Caption="Don't waste this vital advantage!"/>
  </Box>

## Paperwork

To make the swamp of paperwork (that will definitely overwhelm you) even harder to deal with, you have generously been given a [color=#a4885c]stamp[/color] in your locker. Use this to sign paperwork. After you stamp a paper, it definitely, absolutely, cannot be further edited by anyone. Probably. Remember to look over any paperwork before you stamp it. For obvious reasons, [color=#a4885c]don't lose your stamp![/color]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RubberStampCaptain" Caption="Generates infinite symbols of your AUTHORITEH."/>
  </Box>

## Disciplining Staff

As a Department Head, the efficient operation of your department is your priority. From time-to-time you will need to manage one or more members of your staff that have managed to discover an exciting new depth of stupidity or malice.

Generally speaking, a warning will suffice to spook a member of staff into line. You can also confiscate items from your subordinates, should you feel they are incapable of using them competently.

In extreme circumstances, you might need to suspend a member of staff from their role. Staff may also choose to quit their role during the shift.

Suspending a member of staff does not require a lengthy dismissal proceedure or a frog-marching over to the Head of Personnel's desk. Instead:

- Inform the member of staff that they have been suspended.
- Inform other members of the department that the staff member has been suspended.
- Remove any department equipment they possess.
- Ensuring their ID card's access rights are revoked. This may require use of the ID card console on the Bridge, or the assistance of the Head Of Personnel, Head of Security, or Captain.
- Escort them from the department.
- Inform the Head of Personnel and other Department Heads via the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] channel that you have suspended them. You can also issue a stamped paper saying you have suspended the staff member.

You should put any items taken from the suspended staff member aside, so you can return them to the staff member if you lift their suspension.

Depending on the circumstance, you might want to ask a member of the Security team to be present whilst you enact the suspension.

The Captain should always make an effort, should they suspend a Department Head, to fill the new vacancy with another member of that Department. Departments without a Head tend to lack co-ordination and the use of some of their key equipment.

## Chain of Command

Being a Department Head means you're part of the station's command-and-control structure that reports, via the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color], to Central Command. It is vitally important that you, in the conduct of your duties, [color=#a4885c]do not oppose the will of Centcomm![/color] This will lead to unfortunate consequences for your career.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHelmetHardsuitDeathsquad" Caption="Picture unrelated."/>
  </Box>

In normal operations, Department Heads should come to a general consensus on the best actions to take to manage their departments and the station more widely, with the Captain providing a final say if no consensus can be reached.

In times of crisis, the station [italic]can[/italic] operate under a formal chain-of-command to facilitate rapid response and a continuation of leadership in the event the Captain is suddenly unavailable, such as when consumed by a horrible monster, blown up by a wizard, or beaten to death by an angry mob.

One common chain-of-command on Space Station 14 is as follows:

- Firstly the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color],
- Then the [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color],
- And finally the [color=#cb0000]Head of Security[/color].

This prioritizes the Department Heads with most access to control the station's access authorization systems. However, depending on the type of emergency, different Department Heads may be more apprpriate to be part of the chain. For example, the CMO would be an appropriate Department Head to step up to manage the station in the event of a viral outbreak, and the Chief Engineer is the right Head to rely on if the atmospherics system is compromised. It's good to agree on the chain-of-command early in the shift, so that, should the worst happen, the station can continue to have leadership.

Should the chain-of-command run out of members, remaining surviving Department Heads should, by consensus, agree to appoint one of their own as acting Captain, or, if no consensus is reachable and the station is in crisis, act to orderly evacuate the station to Centcomm.

If the chain-of-command has completely failed, with all Department Heads missing or dead, the station's AI should act to orderly evacuate the station to Centcomm.

The Captain or, holder of the chain-of-command, can second their authority to an appropriate Department Head on a temporary basis. For example, the Captain may second their authority to the CMO in the event of a viral outbreak.

## Crisis Management

In the event of a crisis befalling Space Station 14, which is absolutely not going to happen, Department Heads are responsible for ensuring the safety of their staff, the functioning of the station and, if neccessary, the co-ordinated evacuation of all staff on the evacuation shuttle.

In a crisis, there are a few good things to keep in mind:
- You should be clear on the chain-of-command is, and what your responsibilities are, before the crisis hits. If you are not, rectify this quickly.
- Your staff will depend on you for advice and to organize relief efforts. As such, you should listen in, and communicate on, both your department's radio channel and the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] radio channel.
- Whilst your first instinct may be to hide in a locker and wait for the evac shuttle to arrive, there is safety in crowds, and being present is a signficiant motivating factor for your staff to remain at their posts.
- When all else fails, only you have access to the best tools in your department. In particular, you can take advantage of any and all weaponry, armour, hardsuits, and so on, that your department uses. Along with your door remote, these can give you a vital edge in staying alive and getting your staff to safety. Even the tools of a lowly Chef or Botanist could save your department's skins, exoskeletons, and shiny metal posteriors.
- The Bridge, which is accessible by all Command members, is a useful nexus point. It contains many useful computer consoles and is quite defensible. In particular, the Bridge contains the consoles that allow for the issuing of communication announcements and the summoning of the Evacuation Shuttle, both of which are essential tools in an emergency.
- The station AI is usually able to work with Department Heads, provided it is functional, and can easily be contacted via the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] radio channel. The station AI is a powerful ally, able to quickly issue communication announcements and access almost any computer console on the station.
- Whilst your designated pet(s) are adorable, and entirely dependent on you for their survival, they are technically not a priority to rescue ahead of your staff.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCorgiIan" Caption="Ian may need to fend for himself."/>
  </Box>

</Document>
