<Document>
# Command
The heads of each department come together to form the [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] department, a force to be reckoned with and the handlers of the station. They usually have access to special equipment and their own rooms. They are often wanted dead.

## Personnel
[color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] is made up of the heads of each department, being the [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color], the [color=#cb0000]Head of Security[/color], the [color=#5b97bc]Chief Medical Officer[/color], the [color=#f39f27]Chief Engineer[/color], the [color=#c96dbf]Research Director[/color], the [color=#b18644]Quartermaster[/color] and above all else, the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color].
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineCaptain" Caption="Captain"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineHeadOfPersonnel" Caption="HoP"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineHeadOfSecurity" Caption="HoS"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineChiefMedicalOfficer" Caption="CMO"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineChiefEngineer" Caption="CE"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineResearchDirector" Caption="RD"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineQuartermaster" Caption="QM"/>
  </Box>

## Taking Charge
Congratulations on your promotion! Besides all the extra paperwork, your new [color=#a4885c]responsibilities[/color] include running your department, making changes and choosing priorities, keeping personnel and equipment safe as well as slacking off while your cronies do all the work.

Don't forget, you still have a job! Your fancy tools don't earn you a day off, you still have to fill in for any staffing shortages, helping out struggling workers and teaching the newbies.

You might get away with just sitting around and letting people resent you, but it's wiser to get active and work alongside them.
Remember to move your workers around to have them do what they like doing or what they do best.

## Your Locker

To deal with your new soul-crushing tasks, every head is given special items to lead your subordinates. Most of your new shiny tools can be found in your [color=#a4885c]locker[/color].
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerCaptain"/>
  </Box>

Your [color=#a4885c]remote[/color] is very simple but profoundly underestimated. A small but mighty force, your remote can open and close [color=#a4885c]airlocks[/color], spin the [color=#a4885c]bolts[/color] to lock them, or toggle [color=#a4885c]emergency access[/color]. It can do this from a distance.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteCommand"/>
  </Box>
The remote influences where people move around. Heads can lock personnel out of dangerous areas or let people in to grab something really quickly.

You also have access to your very own [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] channel, like every other department. However, yours is particularly special as the people who can hear you have [color=#a4885c]entire departments[/color] at their fingertips.
Use this to communicate with other heads and be a representative of what your workers want or need.

The [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color] and the [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color] get access to the lucrative [color=#a4885c]master encryption key[/color], letting them tune into every radio channel on the station. This is extremly valuable, as you can coordinate between departments yourself.
[color=#a4885c]Don't waste this vital advantage![/color]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetCommand"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyStationMaster"/>
  </Box>

To make the swamp of paperwork (that will definitely overwhelm you) even harder to deal with, you have generously been given a [color=#a4885c]stamp[/color] in your locker. Use this to sign paperwork. After you stamp it, it can't be edited. Look it over first.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RubberStampCaptain"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
