<Document>
# Glossary

This page contains most slang terms you might encounter on the station and throughout the community !

# In-Character Slang

These are terms you might encounter in-game.

## AOS
Arrest on sight.

## AA
All Access, or an ID which has every access on the station. The captain is the only person who will have this kind of access under normal circumstances.

## Atmos
Short for Atmospherics.

## Atmosian
A term for Atmospheric Technicians, or generally anyone who spends most of their time or is particularly skilled with Atmospherics.

## Bolted
An airlock that will never change states. It will stay permanently open or permanently closed until it is unbolted. Closed and bolted airlocks have solid red lights.

## Borg
Short for cyborgs, player-controlled robots.

## Braindead
Refers to a user who has disconnected from the game. Disconnected users may still reconnect to the server and assume control of their character again.

## Brig
The main area of the security department. This is where prisoners are brought and held for their punishment. The Warden is in charge of the brig's smooth operation.

## Cap
Short for Captain.

## Cargonia
Reference to cargo declaring independence. Against the rules.

## CE
Short for Chief Engineer, the head of the Engineering Department.

## CentComm/Central Command
An administrative agency which oversees the Nanotrasen space station you inhabit.

## CMO
Short for Chief Medical Officer, the head of the Medical Department.

## Crit/Critical
Refers to the health state at which you fall unconscious and unable to move. While in critical, your health slowly decays until you die, unless you happen to get outside assistance.

## Emag
  Refers to the Syndicate cryptographic sequencer. "Emagged" usually refers to airlocks or lockers that are bolted open, but also any other device hacked into by an Emag.

## Emergency Access/EA
  An airlock that can be opened by anyone, even without access or an ID at all. Airlocks that are set to emergency access have blinking yellow lights.

## ERT
An Emergency Response Team. These may be dispatched by Central Command for a number of purposes.

## Flukie
A portmanteau of "Fluke" and "Nukie" used to (usually derogatorily) refer to a team of Nuclear Operatives who fail their objective. May also appear as "Fluke Ops".

## God(s)
An IC term representing a Server Administrator. CentComm is also sometimes used in this manner.

## Greytide/Greyshirt/Tider/Assistant
Typically utilized to refer to a Passenger due to the color of their standard uniform, though this may be used to negatively refer to other crew members (not only passengers) who act unruly or commit various minor crimes.

## HoP
Short for Head of Personnel, head of the Service Department. Can also refer to the HoP's office, where IDs are given or changed.

## HoS
Short for Head of Security, head of the Security Department.

## Insuls
Short for Insulated Gloves. These are the yellow gloves most often worn by Engineers. They are offer complete protection from getting electrocuted from shocked things. Vastily more effective than their budget variety.

## Jani
Short for Janitor.

## KOS
Kill on sight. Someone has commited such a serious crime that they are deemed not even worth arresting.

## Mats
Materials. Usually steel, plastic, plasteel, glass, silver and gold.

## Nanotrasen/NT
Nanotrasen is the company which owns the space station you inhabit.

## Newkie
A portmanteau of "New" and "Nukie" used to refer to an inexperienced player in the role of a Nuclear Operative.

## Nukie
A slang/shorthand term of a Nuclear Operative. May sometimes also appear as "Nuke Op".

## Perma
Short for Permanent Brig. This is for the most serious crime and means that a prisoner will never be released. Most stations have a dedicated, separate area of security for the permanent brig.

## QM
Short for Quartermaster, the head of the Cargo department.

## RD
Short for Research Director, the head of the Science Department.

## Robust
A word used to describe someone who is particularly adept in combat, or endured through a tough fight.

## Salv
Short for Salvage tech.

## Sci
Short for Science.

## Sec
Short for Security.

## Secoff
Short for Security Officer.

## Shift
In-Character way to refer to rounds.

## Singulo
A shortening of the Singularity Engine. A Singulo can create infinite power for the station but is very dangerous.

## Singuloose
A Singularity that has grownth too much and breached it's containment. It will rip through the station causing massive damage.

## Spacing
An event which causes an area to lose air pressure, i.e. a hull breach.

## Spess
An intentional mis-spelling of "Space", sometimes used as a portmanteau of "space" and "mess". May also appear in words such as "Spessmen".

## SSD
Short for Sudden Sleep Disorder or Space Sleep Disorder. This is an in-character way to refer to a player who has disconnected and is no longer responding.

## Syndie/Syndi/Syndicate
A catch-all reference to anyone employed by the Syndicate. This ranges from (suspected) Syndicate Agents to Nuclear Operatives.

## TC
A telecrystal, which is a currency used by Syndicate Agents to purchase restricted contraband such as weapons and other illegal equipment.

## Wardenloose
A joke term referencing a Singuloose. A wardenloose is when the Warden is seen outside of the brig.

## Xenoarchaeology
Study of artifacts, usually performed by science.

# Out-Of-Character Slang

These are terms you should only be using in OOC chat or outside the game.

## Admeme
An event hosted or caused by an admin.

## AHelp/Admin Help
A relay used to report rulebreaking behavior or other issues to administrators.

## Antag
Short for Antagonists, which are specifically picked individuals designed to drive the round into chaos.

## Bwoink
The noise made when an admin-help is received. Pray this isn't a ban.

## Ick Ock
A phrase usually shouted in OOC when somebody reveals IC current round information, or "in-character, out-of-character".

## LOOC/OOC
Local out-of-character and (global) out-of-character respectively. They are text channels that allow players to talk to other players outside of roleplay. LOOC is enabled during rounds, while OOC is typically only on after the round ends.

## LRP
Low Roleplay. Servers marked LRP typically have relaxed roleplaying rules.

## MRP
Medium Roleplay. Servers marked MRP usually have a decent basis of roleplaying rules and generally require players to act as their character would realistically in a given situation. Less leeway is afforded to behavior such as openly defying Security or your boss.

## HRP
High Roleplay. Servers marked HRP generally have extensive rules on what is and is not constituted while playing a character. You are generally required to act as your character would, have a character backstory, and follow protocol on the station. Some HRP servers may create their own lore or settings to further facilitate the type of server they wish to host.

## Self-Antag
A term for a player who engages in antagonist-like activity without actually being an antagonist. This encompasses a wide variety of behavior, but is typically used to describe annoying behavior or actions which are greatly detrimental to other players for no purpose. Self-antagonism is a bannable offense. Sometimes used in IC. DO NOT DO THIS.

## Upstream
The baseline version of the game. Any changes to Upstream will "flow" down to all other forks of the game. All official Wizard's Den servers work off of Upstream.

## Validhunter
A player who hunts down "valids", as in people that are valid to kill, even though this person isn't security.

</Document>
