<Document>
# Jobs

SS14 has a large number of jobs, divided into seven major departments:

## Service
[color=#9fed58]Service[/color] is a diverse department that includes the head of personnel and other jobs who exist to serve the station.

It primarily functions as folks who entertain, clean, and serve the rest of the crew, with the exception of passengers who have no particular job beyond getting lost in maintenance.

## Cargo
[color=#b18644]Cargo[/color] consists of the cargo technicians, salvage specialists, and the quartermaster. As a department, it responsible resource distribution and trade, capable of buying and selling things on the galactic market.

For the most part, this means they scrounge around the station and assorted wrecks to find materials to sell and redistribute, and purchase materials other departments request.

## Security
[color=#cb0000]Security[/color] consists of the security cadets, lawyers, detective, security officers, warden, and the head of security. As a department it is responsible for dealing with troublemakers and non-humanoid threats like giant rats and carp.

As a result of this, and the need to walk a fine line, security sometimes is overwhelmed by angry crew (don't kill the clown), and it is important for its members to try and stay on their best behavior.

## Medical
[color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] consists of the medical interns, chemists, medical doctors, and the chief medical officer. As a department it is responsible for taking care of the crew, treat and/or clone the wounded and dead, treat disease, and prevent everyone from dying a horrible, bloody death in a closet somewhere.

Medical is one of the more well-equipped departments, with the ability to locate injured crew using the crew monitor, a nigh infinite supply of chems should chemistry be on-par, and the ability to rapidly diagnose and vaccinate contagious diseases.

## Science
[color=#c96dbf]Science[/color] consists of research assistants, scientists, and the research director. As a department it is responsible for researching technologies and artifacts, upgrading machines, and printing new and useful devices.

Scientists should seek out new artifacts to study, as well as solicit departments to help upgrade their machines.

## Engineering
[color=#f39f27]Engineering[/color] consists of technical assistants, station engineers, atmospheric technicians, and the chief engineer. As a department it is responsible for keeping the station powered, its structure intact and its air supply working.

Engineering is readily equipped to go safely into space, and as such they should always attempt to repair uninhabitable parts of the station.

## Command
[color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] consists of every department head. It is responsible for keeping the station and its departments running efficiently.

Command members should always be relatively competent in their respective departments and attempt to delegate responsibility and direct work.

# Getting Your Job Changed
The [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color] is the person in charge of changing ID accesses and handing out encryption keys. Head over to their office and let them know what job you'd like to work instead.

Often, they'll want you to go get a paper [color=#a4885c]stamped[/color] by a department head. Don't sweat it, just find them and hand them the paper.
</Document>
