<Document>
# Races

SS14 has a variety of races to choose from. Each of them has some (relatively) minor differences that you should keep in mind when playing as and interacting with one.

## Human
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHuman" Caption="A boring human.">
</Box>
Your average baseliner, humans are the most intuitive race.

## Reptile
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobReptilian" Caption="Tailed folk with cold blood.">
</Box>
Lizards have a lisp, a tail and other reptile-like features.

Main differences:
- When bare handed, they use their pointy claws to attack instead of their fists.
- Their tail allows them to drag objects without ocuppying their hands.
- Have a pretty restrictive diet which consists mostly of meat and fruits but have an easier time metabolizing poisonous substances.
- Their cold blood makes them more vulnerable to low temperatures.
- Their scales are minimally better at protecting against cuts, and minimally worse against blunt hits.

Notes:
- If you're having issues keeping your temperature, a scarf can help you stay comfortable.

## Slime
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobSlimePerson" Caption="Slimy life forms.">
</Box>
</Document>
Humanoids with a looser, slimy body.

Main differences:
- They breath nitrogen instead of oxygen.
- Their bodies have an easy time absorbing blunt hits, but other kinds of physical damage are extra harmful.
- Their loose body-mass makes them specially susceptible to damage from low pressure.
- The lack of flesh and blood but grants them resistance to poisons and a near immunity to damage to their genetic code.
- When spilled, their sticky slime slows down creatures walking over it.
- They never rot after death.

Notes:
- Keep in mind that attempting to breath with an oxygen tank will merely cause you to asphyxiate.

## Diona
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiona" Caption="Living trees.">
</Box>
Diona are essentially living plants, with most of their anatomy resembling one.

Main differences:
- Capable of breathing carbon dioxide AND oxygen.
- They have roots instead of feet, making them unable to wear shoes or boots.
- Their bark is fairly resistant to most physical damage.
- Being plant-like, fire and electric shocks are extra deadly to them.
- Can also metabolize plant-related chemicals and be affected like a plant would.
- They require more water to live and also "bleed" water when harmed.

Notes:
- While robust harvest is a very benefficial chemical for a Diona, overdosing on it can have severe consequences.

## Dwarf
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDwarf" Caption="Stout and...">
</Box>
Excluding their smaller stature. Dwarves are pretty much identical to humans.
</Document>

## Arachnid
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobArachnid" Caption="Large spider-like creatures.">
</Box>
Hardy insectoids, very similar to actual spiders.

Main differences:
- Their exo-skeleton is resistant to cuts, but vulnerable to other types of physical damage.
- They are specially sensitive to changes in temperature and air. But are highly resistant to extreme pressures.
- When attacking bare handed, their attacks cut targets instead of bashing them.
- A more efficient metabolism makes them require less food and water.
- Can produce webs which can be used to build furniture and clothing.

## Moth
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobArachnid" Caption="Fluffy, big-eyed insects.">
</Box>
Moths are pretty much a larger version of the kind you'd find on earth.

Main differences:
- Their lightweight bodies and wings grant them excellent mobility in zero-g enviroments.
- Can only consume silk and cloth (including most clothing) due to their tube-like mouths. Which serve as nutrition.
- Their fur makes them attuned to the cold.

Notes:
- You may still take pills by diluting them in a liquid, like with soda can.

</Document>
