<Document>
# Roleplaying
Roleplaying is a very broad topic, and there's never perfect agreement on how to go about it. For the absolute beginner, it's a daunting task and it may seem hard to get into.

While it would be a quite rude to shove our own ideas of ideal roleplay down your throat, we can give you some do's and don'ts that most people agree upon.

## Do: Put in effort.
It's hard to help any person who isn't at least trying to be better. Get out there, talk to people. Be your character. At the bare minimum, be willing to have a conversation, even if somebody else starts it.

## Don't: Make yourself stand out obnoxiously.
It's not often two engineer coworkers having a nice conversation enjoy getting interuppted by Lord Imsupaspecial Andawesome The Third, Liberator of Cargo.
Think about who you wouldn't want to meet in-game, and strive to not be that person.

## Do: Be courteous.
We were all newbies once, so even if you've got the experience under your belt or you slightly outrank someone else, that doesn't mean you need to treat them like dirt.
You and your coworkers are all stuck in a space station thousands of miles from home, an already difficult situation. You'll lose sanity fast enough as it is.

## Don't: Criminalize yourself as a non-antag.
This is referred to as "self-antagging", and you've probably heard all about it by now.
We assure you, all parties lose when you break into engineering and kill everybody, even the actual antagonists.

Nobody will respect you. Nobody will think you're funny. You will be smited, and then forgotten.

## Do: Be willing to take on new ideas.
You can't accomplish anything by pushing everyone away. Be willing to get out of your comfort zone, be taught new things and appreciate the people who want to help you.
SS14 has many diffuclt aspects to learn, but they all pay off in the end. Stick through it and see what you can do.

## Don't: Ask for OOC help in IC.
Use the TAB key to switch the kind of message you're about to send. Local, Whisper, and Emote is for saying/doing stuff in-character. LOOC, OOC and Dead chat is for asking questions and sometimes goofing off.
On the other hand, don't be afraid to ask IC questions in IC. You could learn your job by asking in LOOC, but where's the fun in that? Ask a coworker or supervisor and see what happens.
</Document>
