<Document>
  # Slang Terms
  Space Station 14 players tend to use a lot of slang in their language to cut down on time spent typing.

  ## Common IC (In Character) terms
  - [color=#a4885c]Atmos[/color]: Shorthand for the atmospherics department.
  - [color=#a4885c]Braindead[/color]: Used to describe someone who has not been present at their computer for a while (AFK). They may come back.
  - [color=#a4885c]Cap[/color]:  Shorthand for Captain, the supreme authority of the station.
  - [color=#a4885c]CentComm[/color]: Shorthand for Central Command, the agency which oversees station operations.
  - [color=#a4885c]CE[/color]: Shorthand for Chief Engineer, head of the engineering and atmospherics departments.
  - [color=#a4885c]CMO[/color]: Shorthand for Chief Medical Officer, head of the medical department.
  - [color=#a4885c]Critical[/color]: Used to describe someone who has fallen unconscious due to damage. If any creature is in this state, they are either near death, on some kind of sedative medicine, or just sleeping.
  - [color=#a4885c]ERT[/color]: Shorthand for the Emergency Response Team, which central command may send to the station in the event of a crisis.
  - [color=#a4885c]HoP[/color]: Shorthand for Head of Personnel, head of the service department and second in command under the captain.
  - [color=#a4885c]HoS[/color]: Shorthand for Head of Security, head of the security department.
  - [color=#a4885c]RD[/color]: Shorthand for Research Director, head of the R&D department.
  - [color=#a4885c]QM[/color]: Shorthand for Quatermaster, head of the supply department.
  - [color=#a4885c]Greyshirt/Greytide/Assistant[/color]: Slang term for passenger.
  - [color=#a4885c]Nukie/NukeOp[/color]: Shorthand for Nuclear Operative, a syndicate antagonist tasked with blowing up the station via nuclear bomb.
  - [color=#a4885c]SSD[/color]: Abbreviation for Sudden Sleep Disorder or Space Sleep Disorder; an in-character way to describe someone who has left the game, and is likely not coming back.
  - [color=#a4885c]Syndicate[/color]: A terrorist organization bent on bringing chaos to the station.
  - [color=#a4885c]Syndie[/color]: Slang term for a Syndicate Agent, an antagonist tasked with a variety of both evil and innocent tasks to complete.
  - [color=#a4885c]Nanotrassen/NT[/color]: The company that owns the station, and by proxy, who you work for.
  - [color=#a4885c]Spess[/color]: A portmanteau of "Space" and "Mess", commonly refering to both.
  - [color=#a4885c]Spessman[/color]: Slang term for Spaceman.
  - [color=#a4885c]Spacing[/color]: Alternate term for "hull breach". A location that has been "Spaced" is totally devoid of an atmosphere and exposed to space.
  - [color=#a4885c]TC[/color]: Shorthand for Telecrystals, a currency which syndicate agents and nuclear operatives use to buy items and weapons.

  ## Common OOC (Out Of Character) terms
  - [color=#a4885c]Antag[/color]: Shorthand for antagonist; the various people,creatures, and other abominations who pose a threat to the station and crew.
  - [color=#a4885c]Newkie/Flukie[/color]: Slang term for nuclear opperatives who are very, very bad at their job.
  - [color=#a4885c]Self-Antag[/color]: When a non-antagonist player engages in griefing. [color=#ff0000]This is a bannable offense.[/color]

</Document>
