<Document>
# Station and Shifts

Every round of SS14 is a [bold]self-contained shift[/bold] that takes place on one of many different stations.

Rounds typically last from [color=cyan]45 to 90 minutes[/color], but players are free to leave and join at any point during a round.

## Shuttle Terminal
If you join in the middle of a shift, you will likely spawn on the [color=lime]shuttle terminal[/color].
Here you can grab drinks, conversate with other players, and wait for the shuttle to take you to the station.

Screens on the walls will give you an ETA for the shuttle.
When it arrives, simply walk on to be transported to the station.

Make sure to stay inside the terminal and to not stand in the shuttle landing zone. [color=#EB2D3A][bold]You can be crushed by shuttles flying in[/bold][/color]

## Navigation
Every station has a wide variety of locations to visit.
These range from specific departments where work happens to common areas where you can relax and chat with others.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StationMap"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignDirectionalDorms" Caption="Directional Signs"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignBridge" Caption="Marker Signs"/>
</Box>

[color=cyan]Station maps[/color] give you an overview of the entire station with colored markers denoting locations of different things.
Regular [color=cyan]signs[/color] on walls can point you to different departments.

## Leaving the Station
At the end of the shift [color=gray](barring a [color=red][bold]nuclear disaster[/bold][/color])[/color], you will leave the station via the [color=lime]evac shuttle[/color].
When it's called, an announcement will play on the station alerting the crew and signaling its [color=cyan]arrival in 10 minutes.[/color]
Once it arrives, you'll need to make your way over to it, board it, and then survive the trip to [bold]Central Command[/bold].

The round doesn't officially end until you reach [bold]Central Command[/bold]

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CryogenicSleepUnit"/>
</Box>

If you need to leave a round early, you can do so through a [color=lime]cyrogenic sleep unit[/color].
Simply going inside and leaving the game will store your belongings and ensure that they are not stolen or misused.

## More Info
Learning the controls? [textlink="Click here to read about the different controls" link="Controls"]

Don't know how to perform a job? [textlink="Click here to jump to a list of departments" link="Jobs"]

Keep dying? [textlink="Click here to see a survival guide" link="Survival"]

</Document>
