<Document>
# Survival

It is generally wise to avoid situations that will cause you harm, because medical can only heal you so much when there's nuclear operatives on your doorstep.

## Identifying your situation
Your PDA contains both a vessel name and list of crew currently active in your vessel, a reminder for your name if needed, and your assigned job for the shift, allowing you to quickly assess the situation.

## Emergency Treatment
In the event of a serious emergency, there's a few things you can do to help ensure your long-term survival, including:

- If entering critical condition, use the emergency medipen from your emergency box, it'll make sure you don't end up unable to do anything. Emergency medipens can also be used to revive people currently in crit on the floor, and to prolong the amount of time you have to deal with poisons/etc.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyMedipen"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SpaceMedipen"/>
</Box>
- Your emergency box contains a breath mask and oxygen tank, which can help you survive longer in a spacing situation.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingMaskBreath"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyOxygenTankFilled"/>
</Box>
- If actively bleeding out, or simply wishing to prepare, it's possible to slice up cloth items with a knife or other sharp object and use the resulting cloth to create gauze to stem bleeding with.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialCloth"/>
</Box>
- In lieu of an actual health analyzer, simply examining yourself and using the detailed examine is a good way to figure out what wounds you have.
- If going blind, carrots are another way to treat the issue (as they contain Oculine, the chemistry drug used to treat blindness) should they be available.
- Well-made meals (cooked food not from a vending machine) is generally much better for your overall health and can help heal smaller wounds more quickly.
- Simple bed rest cures the majority of diseases and also allows wounds to close up on their own. Medical beds are best for this, providing a sterile surface and support for all damaged body parts, but any bed works. Even sitting down helps, if only a little.

</Document>