<Document>
  # Influences

  Culists begin with two powerful inflences, and will gradually unlock more as they progress the Monument through its three stages.

  Once the Monument reaches its second stage, any time a cultist uses an influence, they have a chance to generate a telltale [color=#4cabb3]Malign Echo[/color]. These will fade after a short time, but may alert outsiders to the presence of your cult prematurely!

  Using Siphon Entropy will never generate a Malign Echo.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicEchoVfx" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  ## Starting Influences
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Siphon Entropy:[/bold][/color] Silently siphon entropy from your target, dealing some damage in the process.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Null Glare:[/bold][/color] Emit a horrific pulse of cosmic light, slowing and disorienting everyone around you.

  ## Unlockable Active Influences
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Abberant Lapse:[/bold][/color] Lapse your target's corporeal form, temporarily rendering it immutable, impassible, and frozen in place.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Shunt Subjectivity:[/bold][/color] Shunt your target's mind out of their body and unto the cosmic dark, temporarily rendering their body mindless.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Force Ingress:[/bold][/color] Use a concentrated blast of power to force a secure doorway open.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Astral Nova:[/bold][/color] Hurl a large and disruptive blast of astral energy.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Vacuous Imposition:[/bold][/color] You negate any incoming damage for a short time.

  ## Unlockable Passive Influences
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Eschew Metabolism:[/bold][/color] Your corporeal needs of hunger and thirst are sundered - you no longer need to eat or drink.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Unbound Step:[/bold][/color] You move relative only to the starless black - your movement is no longer affected by gravity.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Astral Stride:[/bold][/color] Astral energy invigorates your every move, subtly hastening your speed.
  - [color=#4cabb3][bold]Vacuous Vitality:[/bold][/color] The starless emptiness of The Monument overwhelms your mind and body. Your corporeal form slowly regenerates while in its presence.
</Document>
