<Document>
    # SANDWICHSTATION RULES

    Welcome to [bold][color=#00FF00]Sandwich[/color][color=#E8BA71]Station![/color][/bold]

    Space Station 14 is unlike most games. Roleplay is the focus of this game, as such most rules are written to support that - however not all rules are intuitive.

    Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play.

    Some of our rules are [color=#FF0000]zero tolerance rules[/color], meaning that a violation will result in an indefinite ban without any warning.

    If you are ever unsure of a rule, you can ask an admin in-game by pressing F1 - or by asking in our Discord server.

    Game admins will treat you as if you have read and understood the rules, even if you have not.

    ## ULTIMATE AUTHORITY

    The most important rule. You can only accept it.

    - [textlink="0. Admins have the final say." link="SandwichRuleUA0"]

    ## CORE RULES

    These rules apply to everyone at all times.

    - [textlink="1. You MUST be 18 or older to join this server." link="SandwichRuleC1"]
    - [textlink="2. You MUST only use English." link="SandwichRuleC2"]
    - [textlink="3. Don't be a dick." link="SandwichRuleC3"]
    - [textlink="4. Be civil in chat." link="SandwichRuleC4"]
    - [textlink="5. Be fun for everyone, not just yourself." link="SandwichRuleC5"]
    - [textlink="6. ERP is discouraged, but Sexual Content is allowed." link="SandwichRuleC6"]
    - [textlink="7. Do not use out of game methods to communicate with other players." link="SandwichRuleC7"]
    - [textlink="8. Do not attempt to evade bans." link="SandwichRuleC8"]
    - [textlink="9. Do not use multiple accounts, or alt accounts, and do not share accounts." link="SandwichRuleC9"]
    - [textlink="10. Do not abuse or ignore admin messages." link="SandwichRuleC10"]
    - [textlink="11. Do not threaten to ahelp other players or argue with them about rules." link="SandwichRuleC11"]
    - [textlink="12. Use realistic character names, and do not use names of famous people." link="SandwichRuleC12"]
    - [textlink="13. Do not use LOOC or OOC to share current round information." link="SandwichRuleC13"]

    ## IN GAME & ROLEPLAY RULES

    These rules apply to everyone the moment the round starts and until the lobby screen reappears.

    The deathmatch and sandbox gamemodes are exempt from these rules. Players who choose to not follow these rules are entirely responsible for knowing if an exempt game mode is active.

    Players who are inside the Murderbox are exempt from these rules.

    Players in the Ghost Bar must adhere to the Ghost Bar rules.

    Roleplay rules do not apply to ghosts/spectators/observers while they are ghosts/spectators/observers. Dead chat is considered to be an in-game out of character chat channel.

    See the list of role types for more information about the different types of roles.

    - [textlink="1. Crew must follow their Job Expectations." link="SandwichRuleR1"]
    - [textlink="2. Silicons must follow Silicon Rules." link="SandwichRuleR2"]
    - [textlink="3. Familiars must obey their Master." link="SandwichRuleR3"]
    - [textlink="4. Roleplay as a reasonable, normal person." link="SandwichRuleR4"]
    - [textlink="5. Do not act like an antagonist, unless the game tells you that you are one." link="SandwichRuleR5-0"]
    - [textlink="5.1. Antagonists must exercise acceptable collateral damage." link="SandwichRuleR5-1"]
    - [textlink="6. Do not End-of-Round Grief (EORG)." link="SandwichRuleR6"]
    - [textlink="7. Do not Metagame, obey the Metashield." link="SandwichRuleR7"]
    - [textlink="8. Follow reasonable escalation." link="SandwichRuleR8"]
    - [textlink="9. Do not interfere with Arrivals." link="SandwichRuleR9"]
    - [textlink="10. Do not stall the round." link="SandwichRuleR10"]
    - [textlink="11. Do not Powergame." link="SandwichRuleR11"]
    - [textlink="12. Do not Validhunt." link="SandwichRuleR12"]

    ## SANDBOX SPECIFIC RULES

    You are free to do as you wish, however, causing massive damage to the station, the arrivals system, and other players' builds is strictly prohibited. It is also strictly prohibited to spawn large amounts of entities, as too many entities can cause severe lag.
</Document>

