<Document>
# Ghost roles
Ghost roles are characters and creatures that can show up after the start of a round, controlled by observing or deceased players. Their individual goals differ, but the intent of all ghost roles is to add more variety to a shift, as well as giving deceased players something to do if their character is unlikely to be revived.

Depending on the organism, ghost roles may not always be occupied by a player, instead acting as an NPC. Even if a player is not inhabiting a character at the beginning of the round, it might be occupied later on.

This section of the guidebook is not exhaustive - It mostly covers non-antagonist ghost roles that present unique mechanics or roleplay considerations.

## Rules
All ghost roles, regardless of their role or their rules text, follow the "new life rule:"

[color=#ffa500]"You don't remember any of your previous life, and you don't remember anything you learned as a ghost."[/color]

Beyond that, their rules are determined by the text that will pop up when you attempt to take that role.

Here are some of the major types of ghost roles that you'll encounter:

## Non-Antagonist:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMonkeyPunpun" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobApidBotanist" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Non-Antagonist ghost roles are not explicitly "good guys," but should avoid harming the station and its crew, directly or otherwise.

## Free Agent:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobSkeletonCloset" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGoblinStowaway" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMouse" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitMercenary" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Free Agent ghost roles are free to act as they please, with some limitations. [color=red]They are not allowed to cause excessive destruction or death without proper escalation.[/color]

## Familiar:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiscworldLuggage" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBatRemilia" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGoblinKnight" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Familiar ghost roles have a "master" and must serve their interests, regardless of what those may be. [color=yellow]If a familiar's master is an antagonist, that familiar is also an antagonist.[/color]

## Antagonist:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatKing" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRevenant" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Ghost roles can be outright Antagonists, but those are all covered in the [textlink="Antagonists" link="Antagonists"] section of the guidebook, in particular the [textlink="Minor Antagonists" link="MinorAntagonists"] entry.
</Document>
