<Document>
# Ghostroles
Ghostroles are supplementary characters and creatures that can show up throughout a shift and be "taken over" by spectators. Their goals vary, but generally they're there to spice up the shift and make things more interesting for living players.

This section of the guidebook is not exhaustive - It mostly covers non-antagonist ghostroles that present unique mechanics or roleplay considerations, most of which are custom content developed for this server. 

## Rules
All Ghostroles, regardless of their role or their rules text, follow the "new life rule:"

[color=#ffa500]"You don't remember any of your previous life, and you don't remember anything you learned as a ghost."[/color]

Beyond that, their rules are determined by the text that will pop up when you attempt to take that role. 

Here are some of the major types of Ghostrole that you'll encounter:

## Non-Antagonist:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMonkeyPunpun" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Non-Antagonist Ghostroles are not explicitly "good guys," but should avoid harming the station and its crew, directly or otherwise.

## Free Agent:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobSkeletonCloset" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGoblinStowaway" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMouse" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Free Agent Ghostroles are free to act as they please, with some major limitations. [color=red]They are not allowed to cause excessive destruction or death without proper escalation.[/color] If you're not sure what that means, you should not be causing excessive death or destruction as a free agent.

## Familiar:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiscworldLuggage" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBatRemilia" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGoblinKnight" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Familiar Ghostroles have a "master" and must serve their interests, regardless of what those may be. If a familiar's master is an antagonist, that familiar is also an antagonist. 

## Antagonist:
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatKing" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRevenant" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Ghostroles can be explicit Antagonists, but those are all covered in the [textlink="Antagonists" link="Antagonists"] section of the guidebook, in particular the [textlink="Minor Antagonists" link="MinorAntagonists"] entry.
</Document>
