<Document>
  # History

  Around the range of year 100,000 and 200,000 A.D located in the old world, a ship with 10,000 passengers was launched into the abyss packed with technology equivalent to 2300 A.D alongside with an FTL drive. The length of how long the ship sailed for, why the ship set sail or even what happened to the old world, however a few years after the ship crashed onto some foreign world - the Post Ruina years began, starting at zero. Amongst the years since 0, humanity has restarted technological progress, matching the industrial revolution around 47 years later than the old word did. Despite the scientific holdbacks, we managed to soar into space to meet the locals of the local galaxy. This wasn't our first time meeting alien species - it would've been much more bloody, then. After a couple decades, the stars were seeded with life. Many wars, skirmishes, civil unrest and more cannot all be documented and thus will not be listed here.

  ## Important Technologies
  Important technologies that provide use to spacers in this day and age. The technology has reached the technological equivalent of 21st century Earth, alongside with more. These are simply the more important technologies that are much more common in space.
  - Cryosleep: Developed around the year ~2100, it allowed the ability to keep mass amounts of people in stasis by freezing their body and reviving their frozen corpse. Many cheap versions of cryosleep fail to revive cryofrozen crewmembers, and thus are notorious for causing the deaths of cheap spacers.
  - Coil-spin drive: Developed some time before ~2100, it is the most affordable way of setting sail. By spinning a "spinavi crystal" through an electromagnetic coil, and reaching a stable RPM between ~4750 and ~5250, it will be able to rip a hole in space just enough for the ship to fit into spinspace.
  - High light projectiles: Projectiles made of high intensity light enough to cause third degree burns, and when enough power output is provided to the laser, can cause minor explosions or pierce through the hull.
  - Personal Digital Assistant: A PDA for short, is a small electronic device used for multiple uses such as linking to a crew's manifest or being able to message and call others. It's roots reach up to old world's 20th century, however have been re-invented by CoreGov around 2267 to make tracking crewmembers aboard ships easier.

  ## The Decline
  The Decline is a vague term for multiple events. However, many people simply use "the decline" to refer to either the events leading to the war, the war on independent crews, or the aftermath of the war.
  
  Around the year 2498, groups such as ACKs, Frontier Stability Corporation, IncSek, and A2B began enforcing heavy tariffs and taxes upon independent imports and export, severely crippling independent crews. This caused a lot of independent crews to attempt bargaining with the factions - however they refused to budge even when threatened with hostilities, except A2B, which backed down immediately on the threats upon seeing the amount of independent crews they pissed off. These crews began to form the "Independent Resistance", a conglomerate of independent crews that wished to see a change in these groups, after a month after all bargaining was met with either insistence that they will not change or being ghosted, the crews began to attack the ships of these groups. The war begun.
  
  On one side were companies who wished for money:
  - ACKs
  - Frontier Stability Corporation
  - IncSek
  While the other were civilians who wanted to see a change:
  - Independent Resistance
  
  The war lasted less than 6 years. The last of the resistance fled to the edge, and even those who weren't part of the resistance had to flee as well - or face being imprisoned or recruited to the groups. You are part of those crews, you're in a desperate need of a job, or something else. It's your choice. The year is 2523, now begins your story.
</Document>
