<Document>
[color=#ff0000]SECURITY & COMMAND RULES[/color]

[color=#ff0000]MRP Only[/color]: Space Law, Standard Operating Procedure and Alert Procedure policy/guidelines are expected to be adhered to.

[color=#ff0000]Other RP[/color]: As there is no space law, Security/Command acts to maintain the safety of the station and its inhabitants, as well as Nanotrasen assets.

If you regularly play Security or Command roles and got this far, we applaud you for reading. These rules also apply to any individual who is promoted or is acting in the place of a Security/Command role (unless they are an antagonist).

Command and Security are held to a higher standard of play.
    - Be competent in your job and department. Failure to know the basics of your department is liable to result in a job ban.
    - Do not willingly and openly cooperate with terrorists/antagonists. Do not give away your objective items. Some leeway is given to making deals with antagonists if the deal benefits the safety or situation of the station as a whole and not just yourself.
    - Uphold the Law & maintain order. Do not engage in lawbreaking activity or troublemaker behavior. Security is expected to intervene into criminal activity where possible. Heads of Staff are at minimum expected to report criminal activity to Security.
    - Do not immediately abandon your position as a Command role and go do whatever you want instead of managing your department/the station. Do not abuse your position or use it to make arbitrary choices to the detriment of the station.
    - Do not hire random crew to be your bodyguards or promote random to Captain or a Head of Staff at random. If you need bodyguards, talk to your security department. If you need a new Command role, talk to the personnel in that related department.
    - '''Do not abandon the station during Nuclear Operatives. You are supposed to protect the station, not let operatives kill everyone on it without a fight.'''

Security/Command should try to remain non-lethal and effect arrests, except in the following special circumstances, where they may choose to use lethal force:
    - Lethal force is used against you (ex: firearms, lasers, disabling/stunning weapons with intent to kill, deadly melee weapons)
    - Suspect is wearing clothing or showing immediately dangerous equipment only used by enemy agents/antagonists (ex: Syndicate EVA Suit, Bloodred Hardsuit, Holoparasite, C-20R, etc.).
    - You determine that your life or the life of an innocent is in immediate danger.
    - The suspect is unable to be safely detained by less-lethal means. This includes suspects who continually resist efforts to be cuffed or continually manages to escape.
    - If no other reasonable options are readily available and allowing the suspect to continue would be an unreasonable danger to the station/crew.

Security/Command will be expected to answer for use of lethal force. Security/Command will be expected to effect arrests on criminals and prevent them from dying while in custody, even if lethal force is used. Security/Command is strongly required to clone antagonists and effect a sentence as deemed appropriate by Space Law.

Security/Command are expected to protect detainees in their custody to the best of their ability so as long as it does not come to unreasonable risk to themselves, the crew, or the station at large to do so.
    - Brig times should generally not exceed 20 minutes unless stated otherwise in Space Law. Repeat offenders or antagonists may be permabrigged in accordance with Space Law.
    - Security may choose to confiscate dangerous items (weapons, firearms) as well as items used to commission crimes or items that prove problematic in possession of the detainee (tools, insulated gloves, etc.).
    - Detainees that die in your custody must be cloned unless they have been (legally) executed, suicide, or there is strong reason to believe they are an antagonist.
    - Executions must be for an executable crime and approved by the Captain/Acting Captain, who will answer for approving it alongside Security's chain of command. Those who willingly attempt to damage/destroy or escape from the permabrig may be executed.
    - Any prisoner may be borged with their consent. Borging may be offered as an alternative to execution, but cannot be forced if the prisoner is able to consent.
    - Detainees in the brig have the right to know what they are being charged with, as well as basic medical aid, at least to the point they are no longer at risk of dying.
</Document>