<Document>
[color=#ff0000]SILICON RULES[/color]

These rules also apply to any individual who is a silicon, including cyborgs and AI. As with other rules, more details are available on our wiki at [color=#a4885c]wiki.spacestation14.io[/color].

[color=#a4885c]23.[/color] You must follow your laws
    - Silicons without any laws are free from any restrictions that would normally be placed by laws, but self-antagging rules still apply unless they are also antagonists.
    - The order of your laws determines law priority. Law 1 takes priority over laws 2 and 3, and so on.
    - Each individual silicon must remain consistent in their interpretations of laws through the round.
    - Any silicon role not following their laws, or having laws that are a danger to the crew or station may be disabled or destroyed. Any silicon role posing a danger or disruption to the crew may be disabled or destroyed if there is no other reasonable and less severe way of dealing with them.
    - Characters who are turned into cyborgs can remember their former lives, however they are still bound to their laws.
    - Syndicate Agents and Revolutionaries are considered "crewmembers" for the purpose of laws that refer to crewmembers. Generally speaking, if the person appears on the crew manifest, they can be considered a crewmember. The captain or acting captain may hire or fire crewmembers by making it clear that they are no longer crew. Simply demoting someone to passenger is not sufficient to consider them fired.
    - "Harm" is at minimum seen as physical violence or damage against someone or something. If the player wishes, they may choose to interpret psychological harm or similar aspects as harm as well. If two actions are likely to cause harm via action or inaction, silicons will be expected to try and pursue the option with the least potential for harm, however silicons instructed to prevent harm are still forbidden from directly causing harm. You can take an action or not act in cases that might result in eventual harm if it minimizes harm, but you cannot do so if it results in immediate harm. Silicons should default to inaction if neither action nor inaction can prevent harm.
    - When receiving orders or directives from crewmembers and with a law that instructs you must obey, conflicting orders typically defer the choice to the silicon player of which directive you choose to obey if they conflict (taking into account the priorities of your other laws).
    - Orders to silicons that are clearly unreasonable or obnoxious are a violation of the "Don't be a dick" rule. They can be ignored and can be ahelped.
</Document>