<Document>
[color=#ff0000]STANDARD OPERATING PROCEDURE[/color]

[color=#ff0000]MRP Only[/color]

This page covers the standardized guidelines and procedures on board the station. Note that these are not laws, and the Captain may alter them as they see fit. Make sure to look at Alert Procedure for guidelines that change based on the alert level. 

Line of succession

If the captain dies and is unrecoverable for whatever reason, then a new captain must be selected. this follows a fairly simple ruling which has a step by step guide:

    Step 1: Is captain still alive? if so proceed to step 5, if not proceed to the next step.
    Step 2: Is hop still alive? if so proceed to step 5, if not proceed to the next step.
    Step 3: All heads may vote on a head to make captain, then should proceed to step 5, If all heads are dead proceed to the next step.
    Step 4: Call the shuttle and set the alert level to code red.
    Step 5: That person is now Captain.

High Security Areas

This covers High Security Areas and who should be accessing them. High security areas are restricted, and on alert levels or under threat, bolted. Useful for when determining if someone's committed secure trespass.

    AI Core and Upload: All command usually have access. Can be bolted under threat of direct sabotage.
    Armory: Any security officer with Warden or Head of Security's approval. Can be bolted on any alert level.
    Atmospherics: Only atmospheric technicians have access. Can be bolted under threat of direct sabotage.
    Bridge: All command staff have access. Can be bolted under direct and immediate threat.
    Camera Servers: Only Engineering personnel usually have access. Can be bolted under threat of direct sabotage.
    Gravity Generation: Only Engineering personnel (sometimes Chief Engineer exclusively) have access normally. Can be bolted under threat of direct sabotage.
    Head Offices: Dependent on the head. Can be bolted under threat of break in.
    Research Server: Only the Research Director has access. Can be bolted under threat of direct sabotage.
    Telecommunications: Only Engineering personnel (sometimes Chief Engineer exclusively) have access normally. Can be bolted on Red Alert or when under threat of direct sabotage.
    Vault: All command staff have access. Can be bolted under threats of terrorism.

Docking and Visitors

Visitors

    The station is encouraged to allow non-hostile visitors permission to dock or otherwise come aboard during normal operating conditions.
    If an individual commits a crime aboard a Nanotrasen station, and then flees to an actively in-use unaffiliated vessel, habitat, or station, it is up to that organisation to offer or reject a request for asylum.
    The Captain may grant or deny asylum at his discretion.
    Visitors may be granted whatever access the Captain deems appropriate.
    Visitors may be assigned an escort or searched upon entrance at the Captain’s discretion, however at no times should the crew enter a visitor’s vessel without permission, search a visitor’s vessel, or otherwise infringe on their sovereignty.
    Visitors aboard an NT Vessel are subject to Space Law. Likewise, if a visitor breaks the law and then immediately flees to their own vessel, the "hot pursuit" doctrine applies and security may board to detain.

Vessels

    Any personnel aboard a vessel are under the legal authority of that vessel and may be legally fined, arrested, detained, and otherwise punished for infractions of the visitor's laws.
    Vessels belonging to organisations at war with Nanotrasen, or vessels which attack a Nanotrasen facility or ship are not protected by these regulations, nor are vessels engaged in blatant criminal activities such as human slavery.

Medical Evaluation

The procedure for demoting on-duty personnel due to medical or psychological reasons involves several steps and input from multiple parties. The Chief Medical Officer may declare any on-duty personnel unfit for duty and remove them from their position, including the Captain. This standard operating procedure may not be overruled by the Captain.

    Identification of the issue: The medical or psychological issue that is preventing the person from effectively performing their duties must be identified. This may involve input from medical or psychological professionals on the station, or from the person themselves.
    Assessment of the situation: The situation has to be assessed by the head of personnel, or another designated person, to determine the severity of the issue and the impact it is having on the department and the overall functioning of the station.
    Discussion with the person: The person has to be informed of the issue and the proposed demotion, and given the opportunity to provide their input and perspective on the situation.
    Decision-making: A decision is to be made, with input from all relevant parties, on whether the person should be demoted and if so, what would be the suitable alternative role, if any. In order for a medical evaluation to be considered correct, two heads, one of which must be the CMO, must agree that the specified crewmate is unfit for duty and the head of personnel must agree in order for their demotion.
    Implementation: The demotion has to be implemented, with the person being reassigned to a different role or department. The new person must be trained and brought up to speed on the department's operations.
    Follow-up: The medical or psychological issue that led to the demotion has to be closely monitored, and if necessary, appropriate steps needs to be taken to ensure the well-being of the person and to prevent a recurrence of the issue.


    To be able to demote a crew member despite lack of leadership, the following reporting chain must be followed:
        Chief Medical Officer ⇒ Psychologist ⇒ Doctor ⇒ Head of Security ⇒ Warden

    If there is no Head of Personnel, the following reporting chain must be followed:
        Head of Personnel ⇒ (Acting) Captain ⇒ Head of Security ⇒ Warden

Important

It should be noted that two different persons must always participate in this decision process, otherwise the demotion is to be treated as invalid. 

Research Operations

Science employees are permitted to use their lab spaces as they see fit with the following exceptions:

    Any human experimentation must be done with the consent of the test subject, and must not have an undue risk of life. The Captain or RD may terminate any experiment for safety or ethical purposes at their discretion.
    Self-Experimentation is prohibited and is chargeable with endangerment.
    Testing of any explosives with risk of penetrating the hull or causing mass destruction must be done at an off-station site.
    Small arms and larger weapons must also be tested at an off-station site if there is risk to the hull.
    Distribution of experimental technology to research personnel for testing is permitted.
    Science employees are not subject to laws regarding Controlled Substances or Items while using said items in the course of research. The RD or captain may veto this at any point.
    Experimental technology may be provided to crew departments for testing and use with the approval of the department head.

Contraband Lists

Contraband is gear or items made illegal under Space Law. Any crewmate using these will answer heavily for it according to Space Law. The current list of contraband is as follows:

    Any hostile corporation technology. Anything that has been produced by a hostile force that is completely it's own design or items that are similar NT tech but are designed to differ in substantial ways.
    Biological or Chemical Weapons, such as neurotoxin grenades. Plasma gas is considered a chemical weapon when used offensively.
    Hacking software which allows a person to subvert access to ship systems, bypass access restrictions or attack a vessels computer network.
    Military Explosives when not in use by Security or otherwise authorized entities. Note that constructive explosives, such as any charges used for mining are not subject to this restriction. Plasma-based explosives are considered military weapons.

Controlled Substances are any chemicals that have been restricted or made illegal under Space Law. This includes items or foods that contain any illegal substance. These can be used with permission from both the Chief Medical Officer and Head of Security. The current list of controlled substances is as follows:

    Any explosive or pyrotechnic compound outside of Science. Excluding welding fuel contained in welders. (Anything in the in-game guidebook listed under Pyrotechnics.)
    Any lethal toxin or toxic substance/compound outside of Science. (Anything in the in-game guidebook listed under Toxins.)
    Chloral hydrate, Impedrezene, Ipecac, and Pax, when used outside of medical procedures or medicinal prescriptions.
    Mindbreaker toxin.
    Mute toxin.
    Nocturine.
    Norepinephirc acid.
    Romerol.
    Space drugs.
    Stimulants. Both the plain chemical itself and chemicals like Desoxyephedrine or Ephedrine.

Restricted Gear is equipment that has been restricted to a specific station job or department. Exceptions can be made with proper authorization, usually a signed paper by the involved department head. The current list is as follows:

    [Security] Disabling technology. Stun batons, disablers, and improvised stunning weapons. (Exceptions: Head of Personnel's disabler.)
    [Security] Flash technology. Handheld flashes, flash bangs, and auto flashers. (Exceptions: Heads of staff's flashes. Roboticist's flashes)
    [Security] Firearms. Any gun or laser. (Exceptions: Bartender's shotgun. Salvage's Proto Kinetic Accelerators. Captain's laser gun.)
    [Security] Protective vests, helmets, shields, and chest rigs. (Exceptions: Bartender's bullet proof vests. Captain's carapace.)
    [Security] Restraining gear. Handcuffs, zip ties, bolas, and improvised restraints.
    [Security] Security eye protection and informational heads up displays. Security glasses, and security HUDs.
    [Engineering] Engineering goggles.
    [None] Improvised weaponry. Spears, baseball bats, shivs, etc.
</Document>