<Document>
  # Core Rule 10 - Do not abuse or ignore admin messages
  Admin help, or "ahelp", is the system used by admins to communicate with specific players in the game. Only use admin help for things requiring admin attention. If you ignore messages admins send to you via ahelp, or disconnect during an ahelp, you may be banned. If you urgently need to leave during an ahelp, you may do so but will likely need to continue the ahelp on the forums. Do not admin check, be hostile/aggressive, request events, or spam. IC methods of contacting admins, like prayers, faxes, red phones, and banana phones, should be used when there is not an issue.

  Admins are not always online, but all ahelps are automatically relayed to discord. For various reasons, admins might not respond to an ahelp even if they've handled it. A lack of response does not necessarily mean that an ahelp was ignored.

  ## Should I ahelp X?
  You can ahelp anytime you genuinely think a player is breaking a rule. Not all ahelps end up being for something that an admin needs to intervene in, but that's ok, admins would rather have people occasionally report things that turn out to not be an issue than miss reports for actual issues because someone was unsure, or get those reports late because someone waited until the end of the round to be more sure.

  The most common reason players give for not ahelping issues is that they don't want to waste admin time, but it only takes a few seconds for an admin to check if someone is an antagonist. If you are ahelping too many things, an admin will let you know. If you're not being told to stop reporting something or to report less things, then you can safely assume that you aren't causing any issues.

  # What should I include in an ahelp?
  At a minimum, admins need to know what the issue is to be able to address an ahelp. Don't send ahelp messages with no information about what your question or the issue is. Messages like "hello" are often considered admin checking.

  If you can, an ideal ahelp message includes what the issue is along with who is causing it and their character's name if possible.

  # Examples
  Appropriate uses of ahelp:
  - reporting people who you think are violating rules,
  - asking questions about rules,
  - asking for a temporary exemption from a rule, and
  - request a minor gimmick, like a TC trade or item spawn.

  Inappropriate uses of ahelp:
  - checking if an admin is online, including sending messages without any information about the issue like "hello" or incomprehensible messages,
  - being hostile or aggressive,
  - requesting events, and
  - spamming messages about the same issue.
</Document>
