<Document>
  # Core Rule 13 - Use realistic character names, and do not use names of famous people
  - No names of people or characters from the real world
  - No titles/honorifics
  - Must follow all other rules (no slurs/sexual names/etc)
  - Usernames, objects, random characters, very "low effort" names, "meta" names, or otherwise implausible names cannot be used as names. See examples below.
  - Admin rulings on IC names are final and disputes should be done through the forums, not by refusing to comply with an admin

  ## Clarification on "Meta" Names
  Meta names are ones which attempt to take advantage of some game mechanic or game design choice. "Urist McHands" is a meta name because it is the default name used for admin spawned humans. "Operator Whiskey" is a meta name because it follows the naming pattern of nuclear operatives. This rule is not intended to prevent things like nuclear operatives using a fake ID with names that appear to be nuclear operative names if they decide that they want to do that.

  ## Conventions and Examples
  Names marked with a ❌ cannot be used by any species. Names with a ✅ can be used by any species.

  Humans typically use the Firstname Lastname convention.
  - ✅ Tom Fisher
  - ✅ Spacey Chapman
  - ❌ Dr. Tom Fisher
  - ❌ Walter White
  - ❌ George Washington
  - ❌ Joe Biden
  - ❌ Ben Dover
  - ❌ Mike Hunt

  Dwarfs typically use the human convention in a viking theme.
  - ✅ Ingrid Firebreath
  - ✅ Erik Lightningclaw

  Lizards typically use the Verb-article-Noun convention.
  - ✅ Cleans-the-Airlocks
  - ❌ Bans-the-Admins

  Slimes typically have names that are onomonopia. A last name is optional.
  - ✅ Foolp Suub
  - ✅ Foolp
  - ❌ Slime

  Diona typically have calm, nature themed, Noun of Noun style names.
  - ✅ Petal of Tranquility
  - ✅ Garden of Relaxation
  - ❌ Tree but Alive

  Mothmen typically use latin sounding names, or light themed names.
  - ✅ Socrates Temnora
  - ✅ Sierra Lightseeker
  - ✅ James Nightflitter

  Arachnids typically use latin sounding names.
  - ✅ Argyroneta Reticulatus
  - ✅ Loxosceles Domesticus
  - ❌ Spider-Man

  Usernames, objects, random characters, very "low effort" names, "meta" names, or otherwise implausible names are not permitted.
  - ❌ XxRobustxX
  - ❌ SDpksSodjdfk
  - ❌ Lkdsoisgoieun
  - ❌ F4ith H3arth
  - ❌ Greytide
  - ❌ Passenger
  - ❌ Urist McHands
  - ❌ Admin
  - ❌ Game-Master
  - ❌ Joe Mamma
  - ❌ Middle-Aged Man
  - ❌ Operative Whiskey
</Document>
