<Document>
  # Core Rule 1 - Listen to admins and report issues
  Ahelp (admin help) is a system for admins to communicate with players, report issues, and provide in-game interventions. All ahelps are relayed privately to admins to Discord.

  Players must listen to admins without debating rules. Admins are held to account when intervening in-game, making rule interpretations, and overriding rules to improve overall community experience.

  If you disagree with admin actions, you may submit a staff complaint on the forums at https://forum.spacestation14.com/w/complaint-wizard

  ## What and when should I ahelp?
  Ahelp as soon as you believe there is a bug or rule break. It is better to misreport than to wait or not report at all. (Players often avoid ahelp thinking they save admin time and workload. However, it takes only seconds for admins to check issues, and ahelp delays prolong admin response times.)

  Ahelps must state what the issue is at minimum. Ideal ahelps details events leading up to the issue and who was involved. You will not be punished for misusing ahelp without prior notice.

  During an ahelp session, do not ignore messages or disconnect without notice. Admins may not always respond if they offline or have resolved the issue. Do not discuss ahelps with other players.

  When making requests, antagonists may use ahelp. Living non-antagonists must use IC (In-Character) methods such as prayers, faxes, and phones. Ghost non-antagonists must use the the death channel.

  You are highly encouraged to ahelp if command crew are SSD without cryosleeping or a team antagonist is SSD to free up their respective roles.

  ## Examples
  [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color]
  - Reporting players breaking rules
  - Requesting rule clarification or exemption
  - Requesting TC trade or item spawn as an antagonist through ahelp
  - Notifying admins that you are disconnecting as a nuclear operative commander

  [color=#994444]Prohibited:[/color]
  - Checking for admins by sending unclear messages such as "hello"
  - Acting ignorant, hostile, or dishonest during ahelp
  - Requesting events or roles as a non-antagonist through ahelp
</Document>
