<Document>
  # Core Rule 1 - Listen to admins and report issues
  [color=SlateGray][italic]Revision A, 2025-10-11[/italic][/color]

  Admin help (ahelp) is a system for admins to communicate with players, report issues, and intervene in-game. All ahelps are privately relayed to admin channels in the Wizard's Den Discord.

  Admins have the final say, and players must listen to admins without debates. Admins may intervene in-game, make rule interpretations, and override rules to improve overall community experience.

  If you believe an admin has breached the Wizard's Den admin policy, you may submit a staff complaint on the forums at https://forum.spacestation14.com/w/complaint-wizard

  ## What and when should I ahelp?
  Ahelp as soon as you believe there is a bug or rule break, as it is better to misreport than to wait or not report at all. (Players often avoid ahelp thinking they save admin time and workload. However, it takes only seconds for admins to check issues, and ahelp delays prolong admin response times.)

  Ahelps must state what the issue is at minimum. Ideal ahelps details events leading up to the issue and who was involved. You will not be punished for misusing ahelp without prior notice.

  During an ahelp session, do not ignore messages or disconnect without notice. Admins may not always respond if they are offline or have resolved the issue. Do not discuss ahelps with other players.

  When requesting non-issue in-game interventions, characters and ghosts must use in-character (IC) methods and the death channel respectively to contact admins.

  You are highly encouraged to ahelp to free up slots if command crew are SSD without cryosleeping or a team antagonist is SSD.

  ## Examples
  [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color]
  - Reporting players breaking rules.
  - Requesting rule clarification or exemption.
  - Reporting a bug or requesting assistance due to a bug.
  - Requesting in-game interventions through prayers, faxes, and phones.
  - Notifying admins that you are disconnecting as a nuclear operative commander.

  [color=#994444]Prohibited:[/color]
  - Checking for admins by sending unclear messages such as "hello."
  - Acting ignorant, hostile, or dishonest during ahelp.
  - Requesting in-game interventions over non-issues through ahelp.
</Document>
