<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Medical Doctor/Intern SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#42636d][bold]Medical Doctor[/bold][/color] and [color=#42636d][bold]Medical Intern[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. Though not mandatory, it is recommended that Doctors wear Sterile Masks and Latex/Nitrile gloves when handling patients.
<Box>This Guideline becomes mandatory during Viral Outbreaks [bold]and[/bold] when performing [bold][italic]Surgeries[/italic][/bold].</Box>

2. Medical Interns should focus on helping Medical Doctors and Paramedics in whatever they require, and tending to patients that require light care.
<Box>If necessary, they can stand in for regular Medical Doctor duties.</Box>

3. Paramedics are expected to fulfill the duties of regular Medical Doctors if there are no active Medical Doctors/Interns.

4. Medical Doctors must ensure there is at least one (1) Defibrillator available for use in the Exam Room (or wherever the main treatment area is).

5. Medical Doctors must maintain the entirety of Medbay in an hygienic state. This includes, but is not limited to, cleaning organic residue, fluids and/or corpses.
<Box>Janitorial Services should be requested for big spills.</Box>

6. Medical Doctors must place all corpses inside body bags and/or freezers to preserve their state when unable to be worked on immediately.
<Box>In extreme overload, the morgue may be used for preservation but should be checked for [bold][italic]souls[/italic][/bold] to ensure bodies can be revived.</Box>

7. Medical Doctors must work together with Geneticists and Chemists to make sure that Cloning is stocked with Biomass, Osseous Reagent and Sanguine Reagent.
<Box>In addition, Medical Doctors must make sure that the Morgue does not contain cloneable corpses.</Box>

8. Medical Doctors must certify that all cloned personnel are properly transferred to the new cloned body.
<Box>In addition, Medical Doctors must ensure cloned personnel are fully healed and any damage or missing organs are fixed before being released.</Box>

9. Medical Doctors are not permitted to leave Medbay to perform recreational activities if there are unattended patients requiring treatment.

10. Medical Doctors must stabilize patients before delivering them to Surgery. If the patient presents Internal Bleeding, they are to be taken to Surgery post haste.

11. Medical Doctors are not obliged to treat patients who are actively and intentionally harming themselves. If treated, refer the patient to the on-station Psychologist.

</Document>
