<Document>
# The Body

## The Brain
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanBrain" Caption="Human Brain" />
</Box>

Everything in a patient's body depends on the brain.
[color=#00d3b8][bold]As long as the patient's brain is not dead, the patient is alive.[/bold][/color]
Everything else in their body is responsible for keeping its brain alive.
The more an injury threatens your patient's brain, the more important it is to treat.

[color=#00d3b8][bold]Once a brain dies, it is dead, and the body cannot be rescuitated.[/bold][/color]

A patient's brain requires adequate saturation (oxygenation for most species) in the bloodstream to survive.
[color=#00d3b8][bold]The primary goal in medical care is to ensure the brain has adequate saturation.[/bold][/color]

Symptoms of a patient with severe brain damage include, but are not limited to:

- [color=cyan]Impaired communication[/color]: A patient experiencing severe brain damage can have difficulty speaking (i.e. stuttering).
- [color=cyan]Impaired motor control[/color]: A patient experiencing pain may show sluggishness or an inability to aim precisely.
- [color=cyan]Inability to stand[/color]: A patient experiencing severe brain damage may be unable to stand.
- [color=cyan]Gasping[/color]: A patient experiencing severe brain damage may have trouble breathing, and gasp as a result.
- [color=cyan]Nonresponsiveness[/color]: A patient experiencing severe brain damage may be unable to respond to environmental stimuli.

### Diagnosis

You can gauge your patient's brain activity with your health analyzer, listed as [color=#7af396]Brain Activity[/color].
The left-most icon on your medical HUD also indicates a rough read of brain activity, with the blue cross being replaced by a red-and-white exclamation mark if the patient's brain is at risk of fatal injury.

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Brain Activity[/color] is lowering, ensure their [color=#7af396]Blood Saturation[/color] is at safe levels.

## Bloodstream

Blood saturation is the primary measure for how satiated a patient's brain is.

Blood saturation is affected by:
- [color=cyan]Blood volume[/color]: Blood can be restored with saline for most species, or blood bags.
- [color=cyan]Breathable air[/color]: Ensure the patient can breathe. Dexalin (plus) can be used to artificially oxygenate the bloodstream.
- [color=cyan]Blood flow[/color]: The heart is responsible for circulating blood around your patient's body. CPR can be administered if the patient's heart has stopped, followed by surgical intervention as soon as possible.

### Diagnosis

You can gauge your patient's blood vitals with your health analyzer, listed as [color=#7af396]Blood Saturation[/color], [color=#7af396]Blood Pressure[/color], and [color=#7af396]Blood Flow[/color].

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Blood Saturation[/color] is low, ensure their [color=#7af396]Blood Pressure[/color] is at safe levels, and make sure the patient has access to air.
Medicines such as Dexalin can be used to ensure the bloodstream has access to air, and to speed up the process of respiration after prolonged suffocation.

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Blood Flow[/color] is low, ensure their [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color] and [color=#7af396]Heart Health[/color] are at safe levels.
In the case of a stopped heart, you can give CPR to ensure the blood is moving.

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Blood Pressure[/color] is low, ensure their [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color] and blood volume are at safe levels.
Saline and blood bags can be used to increase the patient's blood volume.

## The Heart

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanHeart" Caption="Human Heart" />
</Box>

The heart is responsible for blood flow.

[color=#00d3b8][bold]If a patient's heart has stopped, they are priority number one.[/bold][/color]

Blood flow increases with heartrate, and decreases with heart damage, coming to near-zero if the heart stops.

The heart will increase its heartrate in response to pain, lack of access to breathable air, and lowered blood volume.

The heart will stop from:
- [color=cyan]Ventricular tachycardia[/color]: Excessively high pulse can cause the patient's heart to stop, usually from pain. Administer painkillers and inaprovaline before restarting the heart.
- [color=cyan]Hypovolemia[/color]: If a patient loses too much blood, their heart will stop. Stop bleeding and restore blood levels before restarting the heart.
- [color=cyan]Accumulated damage[/color]: If a patient's heart accumulates too much damage, it will stop. Surgical intervention will be required before restarting the heart.

The heart can be restarted using a defibrillator.

If the heart cannot be restarted, medical professionals and other crew alike can administer CPR to ensure blood flow.

### Diagnosis

You can gauge your patient's heart vitals with your health analyzer, listed as [color=#7af396]Heart Health[/color] and [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color].

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color] is low, ensure their blood volume is adequate, and use a defibrillator or stimulant medications as necessary.

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color] is high, ensure that the patient's pain is under management, the patient's blood volume is sufficient, and that the patient has adequate access to oxygen.
Medicines such as Inaprovaline can be administered to stabilize the heart rate, at the risk of reducing the patient's overall [color=#7af396]Blood Saturation[/color] if other conditions are not treated.

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Heart Health[/color] is declining, ensure that their [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color] is not excessively high.

If your patient's [color=#7af396]Heart Health[/color] is dangerously low, surgery will be required to repair injuries to the heart.

## Pain

In response to injuries, your patient will experience pain.

Fresh wounds are more painful than older and untended wounds.

The effect of pain can primarily felt through the increase in a patient's heart rate, as well as shock in cases of severe pain.

Symptoms of a patient experiencing pain include, but are not limited to:

- [color=cyan]Impaired communication[/color]: A patient experiencing pain can have difficulty speaking (i.e. stuttering or volume), and may be unable to operate their headset effectively
- [color=cyan]Imapired motor control[/color]: A patient experiencing pain may show sluggishness or an inability to aim precisely.
- [color=cyan]Inability to stand[/color]: A patient experiencing pain may be unable to stand.

### Diagnosis

The patient's pain level can primarily be gauged by asking the patient how they feel, or in cases where they cannot communicate, their [color=#7af396]Heart Rate[/color] or displayed symptoms.
Note that pain is not the only thing that can cause the heart rate to increase.

</Document>
