<Document>
# Paramedic

As the primary first responders within the [color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] department, [color=cyan]Paramedics[/color] are responsible for responding to injury calls, stabilizing patients, and bringing them back to [color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] for [color=cyan]Physicians[/color] to treat. If the [color=cyan]Physicians[/color] need extra hands to keep patients stable, the [color=cyan]Paramedics[/color] provide this as well.

As a [color=cyan]Paramedic[/color], keep the following things in mind:

- [bold]Speed is key[/bold]: A few seconds can be the difference between life and death. Familiarize yourself with the stations you work on, and be prepared to respond to calls promptly.
- [bold]Stay alert[/bold]: Keep an eye on the crew monitors, listen to communications for calls for medical assistance, and anticipate situations where your assistance will be required.
- [bold]Don't die[/bold]: You cannot save lives if you yourself are in need of saving. Avoid dangerous situations in trying to save patients, and do not end up getting dragged to [color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] by your coworkers.

## Saving Lives

### 1. The call to action

At some point, someone will call for help, you will notice abnormal readings on the crew monitor, or you will run across injured personnel as you travel the station.

### 2. Decide who to treat

Triage is an important skill. Your medical HUD provides a head's up display of your patients' brain health, whether or not the brain is getting enough oxygen, and your patients' heart rates. Your health analyzer can provide more specific information.

Consider prioritizing patients with the following symptoms:

- [bold]Brain damage[/bold]: Brain death is to be avoided at all costs. As long as your patient has a glimmer of brain activity, you can still save them.
- [bold]Stopped heart[/bold]: A patient's heart being stopped can quickly escalate into severe brain damage.
- [bold]Arterial bleeding[/bold]: A patient's blood volume going too low can deprive the brain of the blood saturation important for life, and cause the heart to stop.

### 3. Stabilization

- [bold]Keep blood moving[/bold]: If your patient's heart has stopped, CPR is strongly advised. You can enlist nearby personnel to perform CPR whilst you proceed with other measures.
- [bold]Treat external wounds[/bold]: Apply topicals as necessary to bandage and salve exterior wounds to halt patients' bleeding.
- [bold]Give stabilizing medicines[/bold]: Inaprovaline can be used to keep the heart and brain from deterioriating as fast, painkillers to relieve the pain, and dexalin (plus) to improve oxygenation if needed.

### 4. Get them to medical

Get your patient to medical, and keep them stable during the process of doing so.

Once they're in the hands of [color=cyan]Physicians[/color], you should be fine to leave to retrieve other patients, unless the [color=cyan]Physicians[/color] ask for a hand.

## The Body

A good understanding of how patients' bodies works is essential for saving lives and keeping your patient alive until you get them to the [color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] department.

[textlink="Learn more about The Body." link="OffbrandBody"]

## Topicals

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack" Caption="Bruise Pack"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment" Caption="Ointment"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze" Caption="Gauze"/>
</Box>

When responding to injuries, the first thing you should do is apply the best type of topical for the wound that you have on hand.

[textlink="Learn more about Topicals." link="OffbrandTopicals"]

## Medications

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleBicaridine" Caption="Bicaridine" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleDermaline" Caption="Dermaline" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleDexalinPlus" Caption="Dexalin Plus" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleDylovene" Caption="Dylovene" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleInaprovaline" Caption="Inaprovaline" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleTramadol" Caption="Tramadol" />
</Box>

After ensuring wounds have been treated with topicals, medications can be given to aid the body in healing, and to relieve pain.

[textlink="Learn more about Medications." link="OffbrandMedication"]

</Document>
