<Document>
# Physician

As the primary care provider within the [color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] department, Physicians are responsible for monitoring patients, ensuring they have the required medication, and operating on patients as necessary.

## The Body

A good understanding of how patients' bodies works is essential for saving lives and ensuring their visit to [color=#5b97bc]Medical[/color] has good outcomes.

[textlink="Learn more about The Body." link="OffbrandBody"]

## Topicals

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack" Caption="Bruise Pack"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment" Caption="Ointment"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze" Caption="Gauze"/>
</Box>

Topicals are the first step in treating brute or burn injuries; every wound should be bandaged or salved before proceeding with treatment.

Each wound can only be bandaged or salved once; different medicated bandages and salves may be better for specific types of wounds.

[textlink="Learn more about Topicals." link="OffbrandTopicals"]

## Medications

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleBicaridine" Caption="Bicaridine" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleDermaline" Caption="Dermaline" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleDexalinPlus" Caption="Dexalin Plus" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleDylovene" Caption="Dylovene" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleInaprovaline" Caption="Inaprovaline" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemistryBottleTramadol" Caption="Tramadol" />
</Box>

After ensuring wounds have been treated with topicals, medications can be given to aid the body in healing, and to relieve pain.

[textlink="Learn more about Medications." link="OffbrandMedication"]

## Cryostasis

In emergency situations, you may not be able to attend to every patient in a timely manner.

Cryostasis devices allow you to slow down your patients' bodies, buying you more time.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StasisBed" Caption="stasis bed" />
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CryoPod" Caption="cryo pod" />
</Box>

[textlink="Learn more about Cryostasis." link="OffbrandCryostasis"]

## Surgery

Some patients may come in with internal injuries that surface-level administration of topicals or medicine cannot heal, invisible to your eye but reported by the health analyzer.

Ensure patients are stable and wounds have been treated before bringing them to an operating room.

[textlink="Learn more about Surgery." link="OffbrandSurgery"]
</Document>
