<Document>
  # 2. Non-Antagonists Must Use Reasonable Escalation.

This rule ensures conflicts are resolved fairly and realistically.

Conflicts must follow this progression unless justified otherwise:
- Verbal: Attempt resolution through dialogue (e.g., “Return my ID”).
- Non-Violent: Use non-harmful actions (e.g., blocking a door, reporting to Security).
- Non-Lethal: Use non-lethal force (e.g., disarms, stun batons).
- Lethal: Use lethal force only as a last resort (e.g., defending against lethal threats).
- Do Not Resuscitate (DNR): Refusing to revive a defeated opponent (rarely acceptable).

Non-antagonists should always attempt to de-escalate a conflict before escalating. If your attempt to de-escalate does not end the conflict, you can always escalate to the next step in resolving a conflict. Moreover, you can always match the level of conflict the other player has already escalated to. You may not arbitrarily start conflicts or escalate them. All conflicts must have a reasonable basis in-character. 

Characters working in the Security Department can always use Non-Lethal force to arrest anyone who does not cooperate during their arrest. Whereas lethal force is only permitted against immediate threats to your character’s life.

Indirect conflict is still conflict, and follows the same progression for the level of conflict you are in. Theft, property damage, and harming or killing pets will always put you into conflict with another player and they can respond with the appropriate escalation for that level of conflict. 

After a conflict has been resolved, anyone who is injured or dying should be escorted to the Medical Department on the station or the Security Department. This de-escalates the conflict, and any future conflict will have to follow the same progression starting from the first level of conflict.

The final level of conflict is only for repeated lethal encounters with that character during conflict or as a result of capital punishment by space law, and must be approved by the Captain of the station before they can be declared DNR, otherwise they must be revived and put into the Permanent Brig within the Security Department.

Station-Wide threats are always at the DNR level of conflict with all non-Antagonists. Station-Wide threats refer to gameplay scenarios or Antagonist roles that pose an existential danger to the entire crew or station infrastructure.

Prioritize de-escalation. Unnecessary violence disrupts roleplay and fairness.

</Document>
