<Document>
  # 5. Fulfill Role Duties and Respect Team Hierarchy

This rule ensures immersive roleplay by requiring players to perform their character’s assigned duties and respect their team’s hierarchy. Any violations of this rule will have immediate consequences, up to and including removal from the round and/or a role ban.

## Non-Antagonist Teams:
- Central Command manages all stations.
- The Captain manages all departments on a station.
- Department Heads manage the crew members in their department (e.g., the Chief Engineer manages other members of Engineering).
- Crew members manage the interns/assistants in their department (e.g., the Station Engineer manages other Technical Assistants in Engineering).

## Antagonist Teams:
- Team leaders (e.g., Nuclear Operative Commander) direct their team’s actions.
- Solo antagonists (e.g., Thieves) answer to no one.

Never ignore or obstruct lawful orders given to you by another player if your character is subordinate to their character. You may, however, always ignore orders that endanger you or violate space law. Antagonists are exempt from this clause even if they are otherwise crew-members and may always ignore and obstruct lawful orders given to them by non-Antagonists or other Antagonists if they do not have a(n) antagonist team.

Solo Antagonists and Antagonists with a team always have objectives. You are expected by other players and GAs to focus on completing your objectives before the round ends. Antagonists may cause a level of disruption to the station that is proportional to their objectives. However, excessive disruption irrelevant to completing these objectives is prohibited. If you have the “DAGD” or “Die a Glorious Death” objective, you are exempt from this.

Never join a round as a character with a role you do not intend them to perform the duties of. You should never be spending more time outside of your department or the station than in it unless you have a reasonable in-character justification (e.g. Salvage Specialists always have a reasonable justification for this, because their duties are always performed outside of the station).

Your character can always change roles if and when they are authorized to by a member of the command personnel on the station. 

</Document>
