<Document>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RoboticArm" Caption="The factory must grow."/>

On goob many machines and processes can be automated.

The first step is getting science to unlock [bold]Industrial Engineering[/bold] which unlocks everything you need.

If you have played with Factorio or the Create mod you will be familiar with how it works.

## Robotic Arm

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RoboticArm"/>

The main workhorse for automation, it moves items from an input to an output.

Without any configuration, it will work with items on the floor infront of it and behind it.

[bold]Use a multitool[/bold] to link its input and output machine to [bold]automated machines[/bold].
Any signal port that starts with "Item:" is compatible.

It has a [italic]Moved[/italic] signal port which is invoked after an item is moved to the output.

## Automated Machines

A variety of machines can be automated by installing an [bold]Automation Upgrade[/bold] on them.

This can unlock:
- signal ports to control the machine by linking it to buttons, logic gates, etc.
- signal ports that get invoked when the machine does something, like a disposal unit being ready to flush
- item automation ports for the [bold]robotic arm[/bold] to use
- a combination of both

Here is every machine that accepts automation upgrades:

<GuideAutomationSlotsEmbed/>

## Storage Bin

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StorageBin"/>

A large gridinv storage that can be accessed by robotic arms by default.

It has a filter slot to control what items can be inserted, similar to a belt whitelist.

A good use of this is stacking up items and then extracting them in chunks with a stack filter robotic arm.

## Interactor

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Interactor"/>

This simulates left click interactions with its held item on an entity infront of it.
If no item is held it's like pressing E, to open a door/crate, picking up an item, etc.

It stores its tool in an actual hand so you can swap it out with the strip menu by pressing E on it.

A filter slot is used to change what entities it will interact with. Using a proper filter is essential as it will only try to interact with 1 item.
It will search for [bold]any entity[/bold] without a filter, even things like conveyors or puddles! Use filters.

It has 4 signal ports:
- Start, used to try interacting with something
- Auto Start, when enabled it will automatically try to interact after a successful interaction
- Started, invoked if the interaction starts a doafter
- Completed, invoked on interaction success OR when the doafter ends
- Failed, invoked if it could not interact with anything

## Constructor

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Constructor"/>

This will construct new objects like you would in the G menu, click it to select which thing to craft.
It will only complete the first step, [bold]use interactors to finish multi-step constructions[/bold].
Construction ghosts and created items both get placed infront of it.

Input items are taken from the floor nearby as well as its internal storage, which doubles as a storage bin.

It has the same ports as an Interactor.

## Filters

Filters can be inserted into robotic arms and storage bins to restrict what items they can move and store respectively.

Craft them by hand in the [bold]G menu[/bold] and click them into machines to insert them.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterName"/>
The name filter searches an item's name in some way.
For example, if you set it to check that an item [italic]contains[/italic] "sheet", it will match steel sheets, glass sheets, etc.
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterLabel"/>
The label filter requires items to have an exact matching label.
Use a hand labeler on items to have them picked up.
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterStack"/>
The stack filter controls how it interacts with stacks.
The minimum stack size is a simple minimum, if an item doesn't have that much in a stack it won't be used.
Out chunk size limits how many of a stack can be taken. Only a whole multiple of this size will be taken out.
[italic]For example, a chunk size of 5 on stacks of 6, 10, 14 and 15 will take 5, 10, 10 and 15 respectively.[/italic]
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AutomationFilterCombined"/>
The combined filter stores 2 filters inside it and uses a logic gate to control how they function.
By default it will allow any item that passes either filter (an OR gate).
It supports all the same operations that logic gate items do.
These can be nested for arbitrarily complex filters!
</Box>

## Transport

Conveyor belts are an obvious way to transport items around as they allow machines to pick up from them.

For higher speed you can use automated disposal units to flush items around.

For long-range space transport you can use Containment Field + Disposal Unit cannons to fire items precisely.

</Document>
