<Document>
	## Rule 4: Play your role

	Only choose a role you're actually wanting to play a round of.

	[color=#a4885c]CREW STANDARDS & EXPECTATIONS[/color]

	Station personnel are expected to behave as a crew member (See also: Rule 1 - Roleplay Standards).

	Passengers, Clowns, Mimes and other low-responsibility roles are still bound by the same rules as regular crew.

	Stay in your lane. If you pick a doctor, you're expected to do your duty of being a medical doctor, not to do engineering work. Offering help is fine, but do not "steal" another person's job.

	Breaks are encouraged, but you should prioritize your job over most social roleplay scenarios, such as getting a drink at the bar.

	[color=#a4885c]COMMAND AND SECURITY STANDARDS & EXPECTATIONS[/color]

	Command and security are expected to play to a higher standard of roleplay, seriousness and competence. Do not ignore your duties.

	If you need to leave the round early as a Head of Staff, you must inform command and head to a cryosleep pod. If you cannot do this for any reason, send an ahelp prior to your disconnection instead.

	Making mistakes is fine. Things happen, so don't stress too much about the funny space game.

	[color=#a4885c]SPACE LAW & STANDARD OPERATING PROCEDURE (SOP)[/color]

	Space law and the SOP are sets of in-character rules dictating the laws of the station and how it should be managed.

	Regular crew members are not expected to know space law or the SOP like the back of their hand. However, be aware you may be subject to IC disciplinary action if you fail to follow it.

	The captain and members of security, especially the HoS and Warden, are expected to follow and have a good understanding of space law.

	Members of command, especially the Captain and HoP, are expected to follow and have a good understanding of the Standard Operating Procedure (SOP).

	Space law & SOP are NOT server rules. Players may be expected to follow them, but in emergencies, it is allowed to breach them within reason if deemed necessary.

	[color=#a4885c]ANTAGROLLING[/color]

	"Antagrolling" refers to the act of frequently joining rounds only to then leave if you did not receive an antagonist role.

	Antag-rolling is not allowed.

</Document>
