<Document>
	## Rule 1: Roleplaying Standards

	Harmony is a medium role-playing server.

	You're not expected to be 100% immersed in everything that is happening. However, we still expect players to act in character at all times, in a manner befitting Space Station 14. The game has many clashing themes and many unserious tones, but generally try to take things as seriously as you would if you were in your character’s shoes.

	Job knowledge is restricted within reason; for example, an engineer should not know how to make complex medicines. In an extreme crisis or to save your own life, you may stretch this information.

	[textlink="(See also: Rule 4 - Play your role)" link="HarmonyR4"]

	Avoid using netspeak (lol, wtf) unless you're writing on a PDA or piece of paper.

  [color=#a4885c]NAMING CONVENTIONS[/color]

	Your character is an employee of Nanotrasen. Names should be context-appropriate and support appropriate role-play.
  Do not make excessive meme/pop culture references when naming your character (Gregory House, Walter White).
  Stage names (Clown, Mime, Musician) are given more creative freedom, but must still be appropriate. Names with potentially offensive meanings are subject to admin discretion.

  [color=#a4885c]NEW LIFE RULES (NLR)[/color]

	Your character does not remember anything which happened while they are either unconscious or dead.
  When returning to life after being defibrillated, you do not remember the events directly leading up to your death. You may remember vague descriptors of who or what killed you (Eg. Stabbed by someone in a yellow suit). Do not get into the specifics such as species or gender of crew members.

	When borged or cloned, your character does not remember anything which happened since the start of the shift.

  [color=#a4885c]METAGAMING[/color]

	"Metagaming" refers to the use of OOC information acquired via means unavailable to other players, such as:

	- Metacommunications (Out-of-game communication with another player) via Discord or other external means. Streaming is, however, still allowed.
	- Multikeying (Using multiple accounts for yourself during a round).
	- Using either OOC or LOOC to share current round information.

	Metagaming is not allowed.

	Harmony does NOT have a metashield - Knowledge of antagonists is not restricted, within reason.

  [color=#a4885c]POWERGAMING[/color]

	"Powergaming" refers to putting your own mechanical advantages ahead of other people's enjoyment or roleplay scenarios, such as:

	- Seeking out weapons, explosives or poisons "just in case" you need them.
	- Hiding antagonist objectives.
	- Going out of your way to hunt down antagonists unreasonably (See also: Rule 7 - Validhunting).

	Powergaming is not allowed and is subject to admin discretion.
</Document>
