<Document>
  # Harmony Rules

	[color=#ffd700]You must be at least 16 years of age to play on Harmony. Any users suspected of being under 16 years of age will be banned until they are of age.[/color]

	[color=#ff0000]Disconnecting from or ignoring/evading admin communication will result in an appeal only ban.[/color]

	This is the "short" form of the rules, which has all the information any regular player should need. You can find the "long" form of the rules with more examples & clarifications of any ambiguity on our Discord and Wiki.

  Should you need it, some RP-specific documents available on the wiki such as Space Law, the Standard Operating Procedure, and the Alert Procedure. They will be mentioned here and are expected to be followed.

	[color=#D3D3D3]discord.gg/n5ha6gVG[/color]

	[color=#ff0000]Recent Changes[/color]

  - Game rules rewritten to be more clear and reflect differences between Harmony and official servers. Contact Liltenhead on discord with any questions.

  ## Community Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

	[color=#a4885c]Rule 0:[/color] [color=#a4885c]The[/color] [color=#ffd700]Golden[/color] [color=#a4885c]Rule.[/color] Admins may excercise discretion with rules as they see fit. If you rule lawyer or line skirt, you will be removed.

	[color=#ff0000]ZERO TOLERANCE RULES[/color]

	[color=#a4885c]1A:[/color] Absolutely no hate speech, slurs, bigotry, racism, specism (demeaning other characters in-game due to their in-game race), sexism, or anything even remotely similar. (YOU WILL GET PERMABANNED)

	[color=#a4885c]2A:[/color] Absolutely no Erotic Roleplay (ERP) or sexual content, including direct or indirect mentions of sexual behavior or actions. (YOU WILL GET PERMABANNED) (Leeway is given to insults, ex: 'You are a dickhead', do not push it)

	[color=#a4885c]3A:[/color] Don't communicate in-game/in-character information through methods outside of the game (such as talking in Discord with other users actively playing or by talking to your sibling across the room while you are both playing). This is referred to as "Metacomming". Adminstrators cannot police metacommunications, we must assume it is being abused. (ALL INVOLVED WILL GET PERMABANNED)

	[color=#a4885c]4A:[/color] Attempting to evade game bans will result in an automatic appeal-only permanent ban that is only appealable after six months and only with a voucher of good behavior from another SS13/SS14 server. Attempting to evade job bans will result in an appeal-only permanent ban. (YOU WILL GET BANNED MUCH WORSE THAN YOU ALREADY WERE)

	[color=#ff0000]GENERAL ETIQUETTE[/color]

	[color=#a4885c]5A:[/color] These are English servers. Speak only English in IC and OOC.

	[color=#a4885c]6A:[/color] Don't use exploits or external programs to play, gain an advantage, or disrupt/crash the round/server. This includes autoclickers and scripts to automate the game or evade AFK detection. Intentionally attempting to lag/crash the server will result in an immediate appeal-only ban.

	[color=#a4885c]7A:[/color] Don't use multiple SS14 accounts to play (referred to as "multi-keying"). Users knowingly using multiple SS14 accounts will have all of their accounts banned.

	[color=#a4885c]8A:[/color] Do not ignore the admin help relay or abuse it by flooding it with spam messages, checking for admins before stating a problem (ex: "hello?", "any admins?"). Hostility to administators in the relay will likely result in your removal. All admin helps are sent to the Harmony Discord relay.

  ## Game Rules
  These rules only apply during an active round.

  - [textlink="0B: Don't be a dick" link="HarmonyR0"]
  - [textlink="1B: Roleplaying Standards" link="HarmonyR1"]
  - [textlink="2B: SSD Players" link="HarmonyR2"]
  - [textlink="3B: Maintaining a Respectful Environment" link="HarmonyR3"]
  - [textlink="4B: Play your role" link="HarmonyR4"]
  - [textlink="5B: Play Antagonists Responsibly" link="HarmonyR5"]
  - [textlink="6B: Self-Antagging" link="HarmonyR6"]
  - [textlink="7B: Validhunting" link="HarmonyR7"]
  - [textlink="8B: Erotic Content" link="HarmonyR8"]

  ## Silicon Rules
  You are only a silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplaying standards if there is any conflict between the two. Silicon Rules do not override core rules.

  - [textlink="1S: Your silicon laws are rules" link="HarmonyS1"]
  - [textlink="2S: Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="HarmonyS2"]
  - [textlink="3S: Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="HarmonyS3"]
  - [textlink="4S: You cannot request a law change" link="HarmonyS4"]
  - [textlink="5S: You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="HarmonyS5"]
  - [textlink="6S: You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="HarmonyS6"]
  - [textlink="7S:You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="HarmonyS7"]
  - [textlink="8S:Your HUD determines who is crew" link="HarmonyS8"]
  - [textlink="9S:Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="HarmonyS9"]
  - [textlink="10S:You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="HarmonyS10"]
</Document>
