<Document>
	## Rule 5: Play Antagonists Responsibly

	The goal of an Antagonist is to make the round exciting, fun, and dangerous, within limits.

	Antagonists are generally given more leeway, and are not affected by Rule 4, Rule 6 or Rule 7.

	[color=#a4885c]ANTAGONIST STANDARDS & EXPECTATIONS[/color]

	Antagonists should make an effort to add to the round, either through completing objectives or personal gimmicks. If you are not willing to act as an antag, do not turn on antagonist roles. If you accidentally roll an antag and do not wish to play it, please ahelp it.

	Different antagonists are under no obligation to work together, and are free to attack/hinder or help one another.

	Do not suicide or immediately go SSD after being caught. If you wish to disconnect after being detained please ask IC to be taken to cryosleep (there is frequently one inside perma), or ahelp if that cannot be accomplished.

	Do not destroy the evacuation shuttle or dock, and do not EORG, even as an antagonist. Usage of any form of explosive, mass fire bomb, or canister bombs is prohibited on the evacuation shuttle.

	Security (as well as cyborgs and the station AI) shouldn't be taken out pre-emptively. If they are actively tracking you they may be eliminated to help you escape. However, staff may take objection if they believe you are attempting to kill as many for the sake of killing, rather than your objectives.

	[color=#a4885c]SPECIAL CASES[/color]

	Free agents, such as skeletons, are allowed to choose whether they wish to be antagonistic or not.

	A free agent must still follow antagonist rules if they wish to cause trouble.

	Rat Kings are allowed to kill people as they wish. They are bound by other antagonist limits.

	[color=#a4885c]MINOR ANTAGONIST LIMITS[/color]

	Being an antagonist may pit you against the station, but you should not actively work against the enjoyment of other players.

	Minor antagonists (Syndicate Traitors, Thieves, Rat Kings and antagonistic Free Agents) should not:

	- Actively round remove people not listed as targets by you or another syndicate.
	- Indiscriminately kill a large portion of the crew for the sake of murder, also known as "Murderboning". This includes on the evacuation shuttle. Rat Kings are exempt from this and may kill as they wish.
	- Commit grand sabotage, such as releasing the tesla, tampering with atmospherics or other large scale destruction which warrants a shuttle call.
	- Render the evacuation shuttle uninhabitable through usage of bombs or fires.

	If your objectives include Die A Glorious Death (DAGD), you are exempt from these limits. It is rare for a reason.

	Major antagonists (Nuclear Operatives, Lone Operatives, Ninjas and Dragons) are not bound by these limits.

	[color=#a4885c]TEAM ANTAGONIST RULES[/color]

	Team antagonists (Nuclear Operatives, Zombies) must work together to accomplish their common goal. How you accomplish this is up to you, however.

	If you need to leave the round as a high impact team antagonist (Nuclear Operative, Initial infected), you are expected to ahelp. Your death may be required for the round to end.

	When converted by a conversion-based team antagonist, do not immediately suicide or go SSD.

	If you wish to forego your objectives, you must get approval from the entirety of your team, as well as from an administrator.

</Document>
