<Document>
	## Rule 1: Roleplaying Standards

	The following behaviors are prohibited on Harmony:

	Metagaming (using OOC information acquired via means unavailable to other players. Examples include, but are not limited to, third-party software or direct, physical communication). Streaming is allowed.

  Placing current round information into OOC chat (IC in OOC);

  Using LOOC to talk to others to give them current round information. This applies to Ghosts as well. If you want to provide minor instruction to a nearby player, please inform the Server Staff before doing so.

  Using multiple accounts for yourself during a round (Multikeying) is not allowed.

  When it comes to suiciding, do not suicide upon getting caught, or when converted by a conversion Antagonist.

  Harmony is a medium role-playing server. You’re not expected to be 100% immersed in everything that is happening. However, we still expect players to act in character at all times, in a manner befitting Space Station 14. The game has many clashing themes and many unserious tones, but generally try to take things as seriously as you would if you were in your character’s shoes.

  We do not restrict knowledge of any antagonists, but you may pick and choose what your character knows. Job knowledge is restricted within reason; for example, an engineer should not know how to make complex medicines. In an extreme crisis or to save your own life, you may stretch this information.

  Administrators may ask you to change your behavior if it is seen by the Server Staff as damaging the IC atmosphere of the server. Examples include, but are not limited to: references to memes or real life events, reference characters (Gregory House, Walter White), or inappropriate play on words. Excessive meme/pop culture names will also be asked to change.

  New Life Rule is in effect, you remember all events up until you fall unconscious unless you enter a dead state. Being defibrillated will return all your memories except for the events leading up to your death. You may remember vague descriptors of who or what killed you. Examples include: Shot, stabbed, burned. You may also describe crew member, borg, or a mob species like carp. Avoid going into specifics like species or gender of crew members though. Being cloned/borged will make your character forget everything since the shift started.

  Your character is an employee of Nanotrasen. Names should be context-appropriate and support appropriate role-play. Stage names have more creative freedom. This includes roles like the clown, mime, and musician.

  Netspeak should be avoided, (lol, wtf) unless you’re writing on a PDA or piece of paper.

	[color=#a4885c]Power Gaming[/color]

	Powergaming can simply be defined as putting your own mechanical advantages ahead of other people's enjoyment or the development of engaging role-playing scenarios. It should be avoided in favor of strategies that both encourage and promote the enjoyment of all parties involved. Administrators may ask you to tone down your play if it is disruptive, or a pattern of power gaming is noticed.

	[color=#a4885c]Flavour Text[/color]

	Your character's flavor text should only contain information that any other character couldn’t notice at a glance. The flavor text shouldn't contain any information about a feature (like personality, past, and so on) that isn't immediately apparent.
</Document>
