<Document>
	## Rule 6: Self-Antagging

	Some forms of Self-Antagging may be highly subjective. An Administrator may warn you if your general behavior over multiple rounds is becoming a problem. If you need more clarification as to what behavior is a problem, you're highly encouraged to talk to the Server Staff about this.

  Minor criminal activity is allowed as a non-antagonist. However, it will be considered self-antagging if it negatively affects a significant portion of the crew, puts the station at risk, or is done without any reasonable IC justification and/or provocation.

  There will be no end-of-round grief once the "end screen" pops up. Antagonists may no longer pursue their objectives, and everyone is to stay in character until the lobby screen appears. Do not start any conflicts, or take any actions that could lead to conflicts regardless of antag status. This includes things like destroying centcom property.

  Stealing high-value items (such as the hand teleporter or nuke disk) is generally considered self-antagging, as it is fulfilling the syndicate's objectives.

  Breaking people out of the general brig area is an IC issue. Breaking people out of the permanent brig would be considered self antagging.

  Resisting arrest as a non-antagonist is allowed, but you may not escalate to lethal force.

  Actively diverting Security personnel and resources away from an active and direct antagonist threat in order to deal with you and your actions will be considered self-antag as it is putting the station at risk and aiding the antagonist.

	[color=#a4885c]Escalation rules[/color]

	Murder is not acceptable for non-antags. Killing should only be done to protect a life, during an authorized execution, or in any situation security has to employ lethal force.

  Violence capable of inflicting serious damage to someone, especially anything that places them into a critical state, is reserved for Antagonists.

  Self-defense is allowed to the extent of saving your own life or the life of another. All conflicts end once one participant enters a critical state. You are to make sure the critically injured person receives proper medical attention, unless it would be unreasonable for you to do so (you are also very injured, they are an antagonist, it would be unsafe to do so, etc.).

  Minor assault and fistfights are acceptable, assuming that both players have a reasonable justification as to why the fight started. Assault without any provocation is to be considered a random death match (RDM) and is against server rules.

  The clown and mime are meant to entertain. Minor pranks are permitted, as long as you aren’t directly harming another crew member from doing their job. You are meant to entertain, not be a public annoyance all the time.

  Actions like kidnapping, stabbing someone with a screwdriver, or slipping people who are fighting active threats should be avoided. Deliberately hampering the crew during a red alert or higher, gives them justification to respond with equal force.
</Document>
