<Document>
	## Rule 4: Play your role

	Only choose a role you’re actually wanting to play a round of.

  Choosing to play as a Head of Staff (such as Chief Medical Officer) means you will be expected to play to a higher standard of roleplay, seriousness and competence. You may be banned from Command if you fail to meet these standards, or if you ignore your duties.

  If you need to leave the round early as a Head of Staff, you must inform Command and place yourself in cryo. If you cannot do this for any reason, then instead Ahelp prior to leaving so that an administrator can remove you after logging out. Things happen, so don’t stress too much if something in real life is more important than logging out of the funny space game.

  Stay in your lane. If you pick a doctor, you’re expected to do your duty of being a medical doctor. Breaks are encouraged; not everyone needs to be constantly on edge waiting to do their job. Interacting with other departments is heavily encouraged, as is spending time at the bar, etc. However, in cases of emergencies, your job should take priority over most social roleplay scenarios, like getting a drink at the bar.

  The captain and members of security are expected to follow and have a good understanding of space law. This server doesn’t have a standard operating procedure; in general, you should be following the alert procedure and keeping the station running as intended.

  Following, or failing to follow standard operating procedure is an IC issue, and should be dealt with in character. If someone is being very negligent or extremely incompetent, feel free to ahelp.

  The order of the Laws determine their priority for cyborgs, with higher priority laws being displayed first. If one contradicts another, you are to follow the highest on the list. Common sense is to be used with all default Lawsets as they have been installed by NT for the protection of the station and their interests.

  Cyborgs are expected to follow the same guidelines as organic crewmembers charged with those tasks, unless their laws state otherwise (eg, Engineering Cyborgs should follow the same guidelines as organic Engineers).

  Frequently joining a round, only to then leave or commit suicide if you did not get an antag role is not permitted.
</Document>
