<Document>
	## Rule 5: Play Antagonists Responsibly

	Remember the goal of an Antagonist is to make the round exciting, fun, and dangerous, within limits. You should make an effort to add to the round, either through completing objectives, or personal gimmicks.

  The role of the antagonist may pit you against the station. However, this does not mean killing the entire station to steal a jetpack. You are free to follow your assigned objectives or create your own, but avoid preventing revival of crew not listed as objective targets. You are also permitted to freely defend yourself with lethal force and need not escalate as a normal crewmember would.

  The Die a Glorious Death objective essentially permits whatever you want. It is rare for a reason.

  If you are not willing to act as an antag, do not check on antagonist roles. If you accidentally roll an antag and do not wish to play it, please ahelp it.

  Team-based antagonists (such as Nuclear Operatives) are expected to ahelp if they need to leave the round, or communicate with their team that they need to leave. Their deaths are required for the round to end if they are to fail.

  Team commanders should always ask the rest of their team first if they are okay with trying a gimmick and disregarding their assigned objectives. The entire team must agree on this before asking the admins for approval. If the team does not agree unanimously then the gimmick should not be attempted and the team should follow standard objective procedures.

  Nuclear operatives are required to work towards the goal of nuking the station. How you go about this can range from stealth ops to war ops, but overall you must be working towards the disk and ultimately the destruction of the station.

  Lone Antagonists (Traitors, Ninjas, Lone Operative) are under no obligation to work together, and are free to attack/hinder/mess with one another. Team antagonists must work together.

  Antagonists are permitted to assist other antagonists with their objectives.

  Releasing the singularity or the tesla, tampering with atmospherics, large scale destruction, or any other action that directly warrants a shuttle call, should be limited to late in the round, and restricted to those with the "die a glorious death" objective. Regular syndicate agents may still use things like syndicate bombs if they will help your objectives. Game ending antagonists such as the space dragon, or nuclear operatives may destroy whatever they see fit. You can always ahelp before doing so for further clarification.

  Antagonists are free to pursue their objectives even on the evacuation shuttle.

  Arrivals, and the immediate area surrounding it is off limits to any form of antagonist behavior. Let people join the round.

  Evac shuttle is off limits from major destruction. This means no placing of syndicate bombs, no tossing half a dozen grenades just for fun. If you wish to grenade a target, that is fine. Don't blow up the entire shuttle in hopes to get a last second kill.

  Major antagonists such as nuclear operatives may ignore this entirely, as hijacking the evac to centcom is a win condition. Dragons may also destroy the evac shuttle, but shouldn't prioritize that. Syndicate agents with "die a glorious death" may do any level of destruction to evac they see fit.
</Document>
