<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Chain of Command
This is the ideal list for passing down the Captain role in command. There are several factors to take into respect here, but this boils down to a simple list.

[bullet/][color=#1b67a5]Blueshield Officer[/color] (BSO) and [color=#1b67a5]Nanotrasen Representative[/color] (NTR) should never hold a position of command on this station.

[bullet/]This list can be deviated from for special circumstances, with the vote resting on Command to do so.

[bullet/][color=#1b67a5]Nanotrasen Representative[/color], if one is present, should assist in this process and guide the new Captain.

[bullet/]When choosing the succeeding Captain, they should be marked on their ID as [color=#1b67a5]Acting Captain[/color] (following the same promotion procedures).

<Box>~</Box>
<Box>[bold][color=#1b67a5][head=1]Command Succession[/head][/color][/bold]</Box>
<Box>Captain</Box>
<Box>Head of Personnel (HoP)</Box>
<Box>Head of Security (HoS)</Box>
<Box>Warden</Box>
<Box>Research Director (RD)</Box>
<Box>Chief Medical Officer (CMO)</Box>
<Box>Chief Engineer (CE)</Box>
<Box>Quartermaster (QM)</Box>
<Box>Security Officer</Box>
<Box>~</Box>

## Succession Decision Process
The new Acting Captain should follow the same responsibilities and uphold the same duties as a normal Captain would. These can be found in the Captain SOP.
The succession list is shown from [bold]top to bottom[/bold] and should be followed as such.

If it is deemed necessary, or by wish of the Head of Staff that is being chosen, the next person in the succession may be skipped.

[bullet/]For choices where the Head of Staff is deemed necessary to skip by others, it should be put to a vote by successors (barring Security Officers).

[bullet/]For choices where the Head of Staff chooses to not accept the title, they should have a valid reason for doing so and justify it if necessary.

## Choosing Security Officers
When choosing Security Officers for Command Succession, it should be put to a vote by all those included if there is no [color=#1b67a5]Nanotrasen Representative[/color].

When voting, it should be held as fast as possible. If a tie happens while voting, seniority should prevail.

## Procedure for Acquiring Access
If at all possible, damage to station and Captain Quarter's should be minimized while acquiring accesses to ID during Command Succession procedures.

AI should follow these procedures and assist in this process. If AI is not available, engineers should be utilized in opening the doors and ensuring they are properly secured when finished.

</Document>
