<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Dismissal/Demotion Policies
These are the policies/procedures that should be followed when dismissing or demoting personnel from a position.

1. In the event of a full dismissal from a position, the personnel should have their ID marked as "Terminated" and set to an Assistant in terms of accesses (only Maintenance).
<Box>[bullet/]Extra access should not be permitted except for special cases with approval from Captain or a relevant Head of Staff (when giving access to a Department).</Box>
<Box>[bullet/]If dismissed by Central Command orders, authorization for extra access should be given by Central Command.</Box>

2. In the event of a demotion, the relevant Head of Staff must choose whether to demote them to a lower rank in the Department or have them transferred to a Service position (with HoP approval).
<Box>[bullet/]It is recommended that the personnel, when demoted out of a Department, be granted access to a Service job of their choice, or demoted to an Assistant (and marked as such).</Box>

3. Dismissals and Demotions should not be performed without authorization from the relevant Head of Staff or Captain; unless specified by orders from Central Command or immense violations of Space Law.
<Box>[bullet/]In such cases of immense violations of Space Law, the perpetrator must have committed serious crimes and/or actively be punished with Perma Brig.</Box>

4. Personnel that are dismissed or demoted by a Head of Staff or Authoritative Personnel must report to Head of Personnel for dismissal/demotion. Failure to do so will result in legal authority to detain with force.

5. Personnel that are dismissed or demoted are considered trespassing in areas they would no longer have access. Any materials kept from areas are considered contraband (if listed as such) and should be turned in.
<Box>[bullet/]Personnel are allowed to keep items not listed as contraband, but should not inhibit the Department.</Box>

## Causes for Dismissal or Demotion
1. Any [bold]major[/bold] breach of Standard Operating Procedure without propable cause.

2. Any [bold]major[/bold] breach of Space Law (and detained for such crimes).

3. Unreasonable/Major Incompetence in current position.

4. Refusal to follow legal/relevant orders from respective Head of Staff or Captain.
<Box>[bullet/]Legality and relevance of the order must be decided by Captain or Head of Personnel</Box>

5. Creation of an abusive, dangerous, and/or unsafe work environment. Written approval for dangerous creations must be approved by respective Head of Staff or Captain.
<Box>[bullet/]Abusive environments include berating, insulting, belittling, or otherwise treating coworkers like dirt.</Box>

## Vote of No Confidence
A [italic]Vote of No Confidence[/italic] is a method for crew members to arrange for the removal of a Command Personnel (barring Central Command personnel). It must be justified with reasoning found below.

1. Voting must be verified by a third party who can tally the votes and verify the validity (this should usually be Central Command personnel, such as NTR).
<Box>[bullet/]The third party must be on-station. The third party should be the Captain if they are not the target in question.</Box>

2. If the third party dismisses the vote, for any reason, the individual must be treated as if it had not happened. They maintain their authority.
<Box>[bullet/]In cases of a tie or understaffed environments, the third party may participate in the vote.</Box>

3. Votes by Departmental crew against the Head of Staff must pass with majority in the Department (2/3rd majority in favor).

4. Votes by Heads of Staff against Captain must be in majority favor.

5. If a Command member is dismissed or demoted by a vote, Central Command must be informed (included any Central Command on station) with voting details included (personnel, reasoning, vote tally).

6. Valid reasons include, but are not limited to: 'Causes for Dismissal or Demotion', Absent/SSD (for extended periods), Critical Lack of Communication, Abuse of Authority, Incompetence, et cetera.

7. Invalid reasons include, but are not limited to: Personal Gripes, Reasonable Dismissal/Demotion of Personnel, Denial of Permission, et cetera.

</Document>
