<Document>
  # Processing Prisoners
  This section of Space Law is to offer a more in-depth explanation on proper procedures for the HoS, Warden, Security Officer, or if there's no one around, the Captain to give to the arrested individual.

  ## Brigging
  The Warden, Head of Security, and Captain all share authority over the brig. Brigging procedures are primarily the job of the warden, but can be done by the HoS or arresting officer should the warden be unavailable.

  Standard Operational Procedures for brigging are as follows:

  1. Take the prisoner to a brig cell, set the time and activate the timer. Inform the warden if additional time will need to be added.

  2. Enter the cell with the prisoner in tow, open the cell locker, and hold the prisoner over it.

  3. Empty their pockets and remove their gloves, backpacks, tool belt, gas masks, and any flash resistant equipment such as Sunglasses, Welding Masks/Goggles, Space Helmets, etc.

  4. Buckle the prisoner to the bed.

  5. Search the items removed and confiscate any contraband, stolen items, or tools that could be used to commit future crimes.

  6. Close the locker and lock it.

  7. Stun the prisoner, remove their cuffs, stun them again, pick up the cuffs then leave the cell. Change the prisoner’s security record to DETAINED if this has not been done already.

  8. Modify their brig sentence for additional offences or good behavior, if applicable.

  9. Once they have served their sentence, set their status to DISCHARGED or PAROLED.

  Do [bold]NOT[/bold] fully strip the prisoner unless they have earned a permanent sentence.

  ## Permabrigging

  1. Prisoners must be cuffed, and their ID must be terminated.

  2. Prisoners must be stripped of all belongings. Said belongings must be placed in one of the prisoner gear lockers, and the prisoner equipped with standard prisoner uniform and headset.

  3. Prisoners must be clothed in a prisoner uniform and shoes and given a Prisoner ID.

  4. Prisoners must be brought to the Permabrig area by the warden or HoS and the doors closed properly behind them.

  5. Authorization must be given by the Captain. If a Captain is not assigned, dead, missing, or otherwise rendered incapable of providing authorization, the Acting Captain may authorize an execution in their stead. Should the Captain and Acting Captain be unable to provide authorization, it must come from Central Command. Without authorization, executions are murder.
  
  6. Though not obligatory, it is recommended that all executed prisoners be considered for borgification post-execution.

  7. Update the security and medical records of the executed prisoner.
</Document>
