<Document>
  # Space Law
  On Space Station 14, stations operate under abbreviated space law. All crew, passengers, and visitors aboard the station are expected to follow these laws.

  Foreign invaders, such as nuclear operatives, ninjas, and pirates, are not protected under space law. Traitors are not foreign invaders so are usually protected by space law.

  Skeletons, lost shuttle refugees (including syndicate refugees), and non hostile foreign ships like the chef ship are all protected under space law. They must, however, seek proper identification (a passenger ID would suffice for IDless persons). Otherwise, they may be detained under failure to comply.

  ## Treatment Of Prisoners
  Prisoners still have certain rights that must be upheld by law enforcement:
  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to basic communications equipment (Radios) so long as they are not abused. If the radio is tampered with a replacement must be given before sentencing or the tampering should be reversed.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter and safety. If the brig is no longer safe, confinement must be established in another location.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel during an interrogation if requested and available for sentences of a high enough severity that legal counsel could reasonably shorten the inmates stay, or in cases where evidence is inconclusive.
  - Prisoners must be given their shift mandated PDA after confinement has finished, unless there is solid proof of PDA tampering. In case of tampering, the PDA is to be secured and replaced with a new unit at release.
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement, and should not be restrained with handcuffs or other devices after incarceration unless there is an undue risk to life and limb. Similarly, any prisoners held for permanent confinement should be held in the communal brig, and should not be confined to a solitary cell unless they pose a risk to life and limb.

  ## Revival
  - If lethal force was required to incapacitate a capital offender (any code 5 crime) or an attempted escape from permanent confinement, they are no longer eligible to be revived; that is to say, they should not be revived under any circumstance as they have demonstrated too great a threat or intent to reoffend.
  - The CMO, Captain, or HoS may also declare a patient or prisoner to not be revived within reason. Examples are a patient immediately killing themselves after getting revived, wasting resources. A prisoner/patient was executed legally due to a combination of other stacking crimes.

  ## Search and Seizure
  A personnel search is a seizure of the objects in a person's backpack, hands, coat, belt, and pockets. If any contraband is found during a search, the officer may choose to further the search into a detainment or simply confiscate the restricted items. After the search is conducted, all legal items are to be returned to the person. A crewmate may legally decline any search conducted without probable cause or a warrant while the alert level is green. It should be noted that if the alert level is blue or above, all personnel searches are legal.

  A departmental search is the sweep of an entire area or department for contraband. It is recommended that the officers be extremely thorough, checking all lockers, crates, and doors. These can only be done with permission or, ideally, a warrant signed by the department head or highest-ranking command staff, which is the captain in most cases. Departmental searches should involve multiple officers and the station detective if available and should be observed by the appropriate departmental head.

  ## Warrants
  - A warrant is a form that specifies "who" is to be searched and "why". It must be stamped by the proper authority according to it's creation.
  - Security officers can create a warrant at any time but can not approve it by themselves. The warden or HOS must approve officers search warrants.
  - The warden can create a warrant but it must be approved by HOS or the departmental head of the to-be searched.
  - Warrants written by the Head of Security must be looked over by the Warden, Captain, or relevant departmental head.
  - In the event of a skeleton crew where no applicable head is available the captain can serve as a substitute for approval of warrants or departmental searches.

  ## Implantation
  Any prisoner in custody can be subjected to implantation or implant extraction procedures, so long as it's within reason. The process of adding or extracting an implant should not prolong the detainees sentence, meaning you can not hold them longer to perform the procedure, unless stated otherwise. A former inmate can be requested to undergo implantation/extraction at a later point in time; if they fit the circumstances during their confinement, they must comply. The following have been listed out with special circumstances, anything not in this list can still be applied, given proper legal context. A prisoner can still receive implantation/extraction procedures without meeting the circumstances if they give their clear permission.
  Usage of contraband implanters is a detainable offense, but it's not reasonable to detain someone solely for having an unidentified implant inside them.
  
  [color=#a4885c]Tracking Implants:[/color] Trackers can be applied to any suspect that has been convicted of a violent crime (the red linked crimes).

  [color=#a4885c]Mind Shields:[/color] Mind Shields can be administered to any prisoner who has been charged with unlawful control, has clearly been mind-controlled themselves, or has otherwise lost control of themselves. It is always reasonable to hold a prisoner until you finish implanting them with a Mind Shield, even if their sentence has concluded, so long as it's done in a timely fashion. If a suspect refuses to cooperate, or the implant fails to function, they can be charged with Refusal of Mental Shielding.

  ## Implant Removal
  Any detainee can be subjected to an attempt at implant extraction, so long as it is within reason. It is unreasonable to attempt an extraction on any or all prisoners by reason of "best practice" or general policy. It is unreasonable to attempt an extraction without having reasonable suspicion that that implant is inside the detainee. Reasonable causes of suspicion include, but are not limited to: a security officer or member of command witnessing an action by a suspect before, during or after their arrest that has no other reasonable explanation; an implanter being found on the person or in the belongings of the suspect; an implanter being forensically-linked to the suspect; absolutely no other plausible situation being possible. It is unreasonable to permit implant extraction to be attempted by someone outside the station's security team or command structure unless no alternative is possible without risking fatal injury. It is unreasonable to force a sapient creature (including detainees, crew members at liberty, visitors, ancestor species, interns or otherwise) to perform an extraction procedure on themselves or others.

  ## Arresting Procedure
  Arresting procedure refers to an ideal way of carrying out an arrest. Not all arrests can or will be performed this way, but they should generally follow these procedures in order to make the arrest go as smoothly as possible. 
  1. Inform the criminal that they are wanted, and why they are wanted. This is void if they are visibly armed, or in in the process of committing a crime, including trespassing in a high security area.

  2. If compliant you need not stun the criminal or suspect before applying cuffs. Additionally if the offense is minor the suspect may be allowed to walk freely to security or a similar outpost accompanied by an officer until such liberty is abused You may utilize departmental security outposts to search compliant suspects or prisoners.

  3. If resistant to arrest, use your nonlethal weaponry until such a situation may prompt use of lethal force. If successful, transport the prisoner immediately to the brig and begin brigging procedure.

  4. If lethal force was used, the suspect must be provided medical aid until they are in a stable enough condition to serve their sentence, unless lethal force was used in the prevention of a class five offense under which revival is no longer required.

  ## Sentencing
  The captain, HOS, and warden are responsible, within reason, for ensuring security officers place appropriate sentences that follow space law. If they are aware of an inappropriate sentence, including excessively long sentences, and if there is not an urgent threat or danger that they must prioritize, then they must work to correct that sentence. Unreasonable failures, as determined by game admins, of the captain, HOS, or warden to ensure space law is followed will be considered a rule issue, not an in-character issue.

  Use common sense and humanity when issuing punishments. You should not always seek out the highest punishment you can, you don't have to always give the maximum time or always look to demote someone. Prisoners cooperating and on good behavior should have their sentences reduced. Always take in account the severity and only charge for what is needed for someone to learn their lesson.

  [color=#a4885c]Stackable Crimes:[/color] Crimes are to be considered 'stackable' in the sense that if you charge someone with two or more different crimes, you should combine the times you would give them for each crime. Linked crimes, shown in matching colors and suffixes on the Quick Crime Guide, can not be stacked and instead override each other, you should pick the highest crime that matches the case.

  [color=#a4885c]Repeat Offenders:[/color] Repeated crimes are when someone is released for a crime and then goes to commit the same crime, or a similar severity crime within the same shift. Criminals that reoffend should be charged with a one tier higher maximum sentence, this can stack all the way up to a capital offense which is required for permanent confinement.

  [color=#a4885c]Accessory, Attempting, And Intention:[/color] If someone intentionally, knowingly and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime they can be charged with the relevant crimes, such as an engineer giving someone tools, who says they are going to break into an area. Same goes for a clear and solid attempt at a crime, or a person who shows clear intent to act out a crime, such as a syndicate nuclear operative arming a nuke but getting arrested before it goes off, they can still be charged with terrorism. Does not apply to crimes that have an attempted listing already, like attempted murder.

  ## Brigging Procedure
  Brigging procedures refers to the recommended way to handle brigging a prisoner. Not all situations can or will go down this smooth; this serves as a guideline of an ideal brigging situation. 

  1. Take the prisoner to the brig and inform the Warden of their crimes so their Security Record may be updated.

  2. Take the prisoner to a brig cell, set the time and activate the timer.

  3. Enter the cell with the prisoner in tow, open the cell locker and hold the prisoner over it.

  4. Empty their pockets and remove their gloves, backpacks, tool belt, gas masks, and any flash resistant equipment such as Sunglasses, Welding Masks/Goggles (Vox Excluded), Space Helmets, etc.

  5. Buckle the prisoner to the bed.

  6. Search the items removed and be sure to check the internals box in their backpack.

  7. Confiscate any contraband and/or stolen items, as well as any tools that may be used for future crimes. These are to be placed in evidence, not left on the brig floor or your personal use, until they can be returned to their rightful owners.

  8. Close the locker and lock it.

  9. Remove their cuffs, pick up the cuffs then leave the cell.

  10. If the suspect attempts an escape, stun them before exiting the cell.

  11. Modify their brig sentence for sparking a hunt, or good behavior, if applicable.

  12. Upon release, ensure that they are marked as "Discharged" in the Criminal Records Computer, in the event they end up in the brig again.

  The Warden or Head of Security is responsible for placing/ordering prisoners be placed in permanent confinement.

  1. Permanent Prisoners are to be completely stripped of their belongings, which are to be held in either evidence or a prison locker.

  2. The prisoner is to be dressed in an Orange Prison Jumpsuit and Shoes, which are found in the prison lockers.

  ## Normal Punishments
  - [color=#a4885c]Warning:[/color] For minor crimes, fix the issue, then warn the person not to attempt the crime again. If they still proceed to do it at a later date, a brig time may be better.
  - [color=#a4885c]Confinement:[/color] The typical punishment, being confined in a cell for a temporary amount of time according to the crimes.
  - [color=#a4885c]Demotion:[/color] Entails removing all departmental gear they have on their person and revoking the involved department access off their ID. This requires the captain's or involved department head's approval. Demotions should only be issued if the person pose a threat to their own department or are in a position where they have/can abuse their job's gear to commit further crimes.

  ## Major Punishments
  [color=#a4885c]Permanent Confinement:[/color] Being held in the permanent brig for the entire duration of the shift. A person is eligible for permanent confinement if they have committed a capital crime, or sentenced with a repeated extreme crime. Any persons subject to this punishment are required to be transported in cuffs to CentComm at the end of the shift. A permanent prisoner can not be deprived of anything covered by the section "Treatment Of Prisoners".

  [color=#a4885c]Execution:[/color] A humane way of dealing with extremely unruly crewmates. Within reason, a prisoner who has been given the death sentence may pick how they wish to be killed, common methods are firing line, lethal injection, exile, and high voltage electrocution. Another alternate method of "execution" is the process of placing a staff's mind into a borg, this is allowed so long as the suspect consents to be borged. Execution can only be issued with the captain's or acting captain's approval; if the HoS is acting captain or there is no acting captain, all heads of staff are to hold a vote on the matter.

  ## Restricted Items and Areas
  - [textlink="Restricted Items and Areas" link="SpaceLawRestrictedList"]

  ## Crime Listing
  - [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]
</Document>
