<Document>
  # CLASSIFIED

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatCentcomcap" Caption="FOR YOUR EYES ONLY"/>
  </Box>
  
  # DESTROY AFTER READING.
  
  Hailing from an ice-covered ocean moon, Decapoids are one of the most mysterious species NT Science Division has encountered. Only a scant few close encounters have been confirmed, and have generally resulted in the loss of a vessel with all hands, and the stations stripped of all valuables.

  ## Physical Features
  
  Decapoids possess [color=#1e90ff]heavy, armored chitin[/color] rendering them extremely durable in a firefight. This chitin appears to be airtight, as they have shown no negative response to being spaced. They also possess a [color=red]large and extremely powerful claw,[/color] capable of applying up to 4,000psi of pressure, severing limbs, and tearing through metal like paper.
  
  ## Anatomy

  The species appears to be aquatic, although their exact method of respiration is unknown. Every Decapoid encountered thus far has been equipped with [color=#1e90ff]some sort of toroidal device[/color] of unknown purpose attached to the neck, and what appears to be a gas tank strapped to their lower back. 

  ## Communication
  
  Black-box records show that verbal communication has been attempted every time Decapoids have been encountered, but they seem either unwilling or unable to respond to our attempts. This may be related to the afforementioned toroidal device, but it is unclear whether or not this is the case.
  
  ## Threat Level
  
  Unknown.
  
  ## Decapoid Naming Conventions
  Decapoids seem to have names which take the form of short, unpronounceable strings of consonants.
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] 'Rk T'th
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] k'Pgh Qn
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Ml Drgtth
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] G'rk Pj'bm
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Crab Legs
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Keith Hardshell
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry
</Document>
