<Document>
  # Thaven

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobThaven" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! This species has a severely limiting game mechanic and is not recommended for new players.[/color]
  [color=#ffa500]This mechanic makes it very difficult to form a consistent character or personality, as it can severely affect the way a Thaven speaks and interacts with others.[/color]

## Moods
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganThavenBrain" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The Thaven have a unique brain structure, similar to a positronic brain, and thus have "Moods" which affect them similarly to a borg's Laws.

  [color=#ffa500]These Moods must be followed to the best of your ability![/color] [color=red]A Thaven's Moods as-written are non-diegetic gameplay features. They should be treated as things your character believes to be facts - and should not be referenced by name or wording.[/color] [color=#ffa500]A Mood being violated by yourself or others is uncomfortable or disquieting. The specifics of that are up to you, but if a Mood is violated, you must seek to correct the mistake immediately.[/color]

  [color=red]Following your moods affords you a limited license to do certain things which would otherwise be against the rules, if approached with proper escalation. If you have a question about this, don't hesitate to ask using the Ahelp feature (F1).[/color]

## Mood Swings
  Thaven brains are susceptible to fluctuations in electromagnetic fields. As a result, their ability to synchronize and regulate their Moods tends to degrade with extended exposure to the cosmic rays and ion storms that permeate NT stations. [color=#ffa500]It also renders them vulnerable to EM fields generated by the syndicate Cryptographic Sequencer, or EMAG,[/color] which can give them additional, often severely debilitating moods.

## Thaven Nerve Pinch
  Thaven hand-to-hand martial arts have a focus on inflicting non-permanent damage. As a result, [color=#ffa500]their unarmed attacks are slow, and deal no damage,[/color] but [color=#1e90ff]cause a fair amount of stun buildup.[/color]

## Breathing
   Due to sharing a common ancestor with space carp, Thaven lungs are strange, resilient organs that generate energy from the motion of respiration alone. As such, [color=#1e90ff]Thaven are immune to asphyxiation,[/color] so long as there is something to breathe.

## Damage
  Due to their relatively fragile bone structure and unique nervous system, they take [color=#ffa500]10% more damage from blunt, slash, pierce, and genetic, and 20% more damage from radiation,[/color] but their unique ancestry allows them to take [color=#1e90ff]10% less damage from heat, cold, and poison.[/color]

 ## Thaven Naming Conventions

  Thaven typically name themselves after a single virtue they hold dear. Sometimes these names can be long and unwieldy.

  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Honesty
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Have Mercy
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Give Thanks To Thy Ancestors
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Obedience
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Search The Scriptures
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] John Smith
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Fuck The Police
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Live Long And Prosper
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry

</Document>
