<Document>
  # Server Rules

This server is intended to be a Medium Roleplay (MRP) server, good communication along with other associated skills are necessary!

Character has to be maintained at all times and actions are to be realistic (or at least the closest to reality). Low-Roleplay (LRP) (i.e. using memes ICly, “netspeak”, powergaming, unrealistic actions, disregarding the setting of the game) is severily discouraged and may be punishable, especially during HRP gamemodes.

English is the language of the server and players must be able to speak it and understand it. You are allowed to speak other languages with other players as long as you do not spam the server and comply with admin's instructions.

As stated earlier, you must speak (in IC) with the proper lingo/vocabulary of the current epoch and setting you're playing. (Do not use “netspeak” like “LOL”, “OMG”, “brb”, “g2g”, etc.).

It is against the rules to speak about Out-Of-Character (OOC) topics Inside-Character (IC) and vice-versa on purpose. Failing to do so will be considered metagaming and may be punishable.

Once a round ends, griefing and random killing is tolerated. This is called “End of Round Grief” (EORG) and it's allowed ONLY when the round has ended.

You must not be toxic or too agitated in any OOC communication channels (Dead-chat and mentor/adminhelp included).

Losing is part of the game: do not get mad about losing your character.
Ban evading is strictly prohibited.

Every user must have common sense to identify and apply the rules to their behavior correctly so as to avoid breaking the rules and to discern wrong-doers from players who follow the rules.

Sharing and/or using exploits/bugs of any kind as well as sharing any kind of information that could lead to griefing is prohibited. This includes also abusing incomplete game mechanics, using unintended features to gain an unfair advantage for yourself or your team. You will be warned first and, if you persist, a permanent ban from the server will be applied.

If you find an exploit please inform staff privately in a timely manner.
</Document>
