<Document>
  # Server Rules
  This is a Wizard's Den server, one of the official Space Station 14 servers. If you are banned on this server, you will be banned on all official servers.

  This is a roleplay server, meaning that roleplay rules apply. This is NOT a medium roleplay (MRP) server, meaning that MRP Amendments do NOT apply.

  Space Station 14 is not like most games. Many rules are designed to require roleplay, and not all rules are intuitive. Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play so that you aren't surprised. Some of our rules are zero tolerance rules, meaning that a violation will result in an indefinite ban without any warning. Game admins will treat you as if you have read the rules, even if you have not.

  ## Core Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  - [textlink="1. Admins have final say" link="RuleC1"]
  - [textlink="2. Don't be a dick" link="RuleC2"]
  - [textlink="3. No Hate Speech or Discriminatory Language" link="RuleC3"]
  - [textlink="4. No sexual content/themes, including erotic roleplay (ERP) and no shock content" link="RuleC4"]
  - [textlink="5. Do not use out of game methods to communicate with other players" link="RuleC5"]
  - [textlink="6. Do not attempt to evade bans" link="RuleC6"]
  - [textlink="7. Only use English" link="RuleC7"]
  - [textlink="8. Do not exploit the game, use cheats, or macros" link="RuleC8"]
  - [textlink="9. Do not use multiple accounts, or alt accounts, and do not share accounts" link="RuleC9"]
  - [textlink="10. Do not abuse or ignore admin messages" link="RuleC10"]
  - [textlink="11. Do not threaten to ahelp other players or argue with them about rules" link="RuleC11"]
  - [textlink="12. Players must be and act at least 16 years old" link="RuleC12"]
  - [textlink="13. Use realistic character names, and do not use names of famous people" link="RuleC13"]
  - [textlink="14. Do not use LOOC or OOC to share current round information" link="RuleC14"]

  ## Roleplay Rules
  These rules only apply during a round. A round ends only when the round summary has appeared. All of these rules apply fully until the moment that the round summary appears, even while the arrivals shuttle is in transit.

  The deathmatch and sandbox game modes are exempt from these rules. Players who choose to not follow these rules are entirely responsible for knowing if an exempt game mode is active.

  Roleplay rules do not apply to ghosts/spectators/observers while they are ghosts/spectators/observers. Dead chat is considered to be an in-game out of character chat channel.

  See the list of [textlink="role types" link="RoleTypes"] for more information about the different types of roles.

  - [textlink="1. Silicones must follow Silicon Rules" link="RuleR1"]
  - [textlink="2. Familiars must obey their master" link="RuleR2"]
  - [textlink="3. Roleplay a normal person" link="RuleR3"]
  - [textlink="4. Do not metagame, obey the Metashield" link="RuleR4"]
  - [textlink="5. Don't interfere with arrivals" link="RuleR5"]
  - [textlink="6. Don't act like an antagonist unless the game tells you that you are one" link="RuleR6"]
  - [textlink="7. Do not stall the round" link="RuleR7"]
  - [textlink="8. As an antagonist, only be friendly to your team and don't work against your team" link="RuleR8"]
  - [textlink="9. As an antagonist, do not cause excessive death, damage, or destruction beyond your objectives" link="RuleR9"]
  - [textlink="10. Listen to your team leader" link="RuleR10"]
  - [textlink="11. Follow reasonable escalation" link="RuleR11"]
  - [textlink="12. Do not abandon your role" link="RuleR12"]
  - [textlink="13. Stick to your role" link="RuleR13"]
  - [textlink="14. Set an example if playing command or security" link="RuleR14"]
  - [textlink="15. Command and Security must follow Space Law" link="RuleR15"]

  ## Silicon Rules
  You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules.

  - [textlink="1. Your silicon laws are rules" link="RuleS1"]
  - [textlink="2. Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="RuleS2"]
  - [textlink="3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="RuleS3"]
  - [textlink="4. You cannot request or allow a law change" link="RuleS4"]
  - [textlink="5. You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="RuleS5"]
  - [textlink="6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="RuleS6"]
  - [textlink="7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="RuleS7"]
  - [textlink="8. Your HUD determines who is crew" link="RuleS8"]
  - [textlink="9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="RuleS9"]
  - [textlink="10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="RuleS10"]
</Document>
