<Document>
  # Server Rules

  Server has no job time requirements, however you are required to have at least some idea of what the job requires and what you're doing.

  Space Station 14 was designed to be a roleplay game, roleplay correctly as this is an MRP server.

  ## Core Rules
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds. These rules are pulled and nitpicked from ParadiseStation 13.

  ## Rule 0: Don't be a dick
  Practice common sense while consulting these rules. The general idea counts, not the exact wording. The rules are guidelines for the server and should be interpreted to suit the situation at hand, not manipulated to suit your needs. Attempting to Rules-Lawyer an Administrator is never a good idea, and likely to result in harsher punishment

  The Server Staff retains the right to issue Permanent Bans to players that they consider to be a consistent net negative to the community and server, without the need for any specific Rule to be broken.

  ##Rule 1: Listen to the Admins
  The Staff Members have final say on the server. If you are banned or job banned from the server, you are to write an appeal instead of continuing the conversation via Adminhelp or Discord messages.

  The Adminhelp system is not to be spammed. If you do not get a response, the Administrators are either busy with other matters or not available.

  ##Rule 2: Roleplaying Standards
  The following behaviors are prohibited on PlanetoidStation 14:

  Metagaming (using OOC information acquired via means unavailable to other players. Examples include, but are not limited to, third-party software or direct, physical communication). This includes streaming; get permission from the Server Staff via ahelp before each round you stream.

  Placing current round information into OOC chat (IC in OOC);

  Using LOOC to talk to others to give them current round information. This applies to Ghosts as well. If you want to provide minor instruction to a nearby player, please inform the Server Staff before doing so;

  ###Regarding Roleplaying

  PlanetoidStation 14 is a Medium Roleplaying Server. This means that we do not expect players to completely and absolutely immerse themselves in the universe of the game. However, we still expect players to act in-character at all times, in a manner befitting the overall scenario: that of working aboard a high-tech research space station owned by a Galactic MegaCorp with dubious moral standards.

  We do not restrict knowledge on any Antagonists, but you may pick and choose what your character knows. Similarly, we do not enforce Clone Memory Disorder (amnesia after cloning/borging), but you may freely play it straight in your character. We also do not restrict knowledge based on your job.

  Administrators may ask you to change your behavior if it is seen by the Server Staff as damaging the IC atmosphere of the server. Examples include, but are not limited to: references to memes or real life events, full reference characters (such as a Diona named Groot who says nothing but "I am Groot"), or an excessive amount of unserious, out-of-universe behavior in an IC context (with the obvious exception of the Clown and Mime)

  ###Regarding "Powergaming"
  The Server Staff retain the right to ask you to tone down what is perceived as being excessive powergaming that causes noticeable disruption to the rest of the playerbase. Powergaming is readily defined as the prioritization of amassing mechanical advantages for yourself, to the detriment of the enjoyment of others or the creation of interesting RP situations, and is to be avoided in favor of methods that both encourage and promote the fun of all parties involved in interactions where such moderation is possible.

  ##Rule 3: SSD Players
  SSD Players are players that have disconnected from the game. They can be identified by the green "ZZZ" next to their head.

  You may not touch or interact with people under the influence of 'Sudden Sleep Disorder' except to pull them to Cryodorms and place them in a Cryosleeper, to provide medical care to SSD players, such as medication or surgery, or to remove them from an immediate life threatening situation, such as a plasma fire;

  Even if the person in question who goes SSD is wanted, you may not arrest them without Adminhelping for permission. Likewise, you may not kill them if they are your assassination target. In this last case, place them in Cryodorms, and after they are removed from the round, you will automatically be given a new target;

  If the person goes SSD immediately after an arrest, you are free to continue processing and brigging them as if they were still awake. Likewise, if your assassination target goes SSD immediately after you begin attacking them, you are free to continue your assault;

  If you believe an SSD person needs to be interacted with (such as an SSD Captain needing to have their equipment removed), ask the Administrators first.

  ##Rule 4: Maintaining a Respectful Environment
  Under no circumstances is OOC harassment of another player allowed, regardless of who the victim is. Repeated IC harassment with little to no reason can be considered metagrudging;

  Racial, Ethnic, Religious, etc, slurs are not allowed ICly or OOCly. Interspecies racism is allowed (so long as no other Rules are broken), as it is considered IC;

  Do not use the server to advertise other servers or for other commercial interests. An exception may be made if you seek Administrator approval (e,g, if you require help to test a server feature on a local testing server).

  Do not put down, invalidate, berate and/or otherwise insult any player, community or server. While anger, frustration, and abuse may be quite suitable ICly, you may be asked to stop by an Administrator if it is seen as over the top, spamming, or without good cause. You can easily enjoy your time on a specific server without having to share your disinterest or plain criticism of other ones.

  ##Rule 5: Play the Role you've chosen
  Choose the role based on what you want to spend the round doing;

  Choosing to play as a Head of Staff (such as Chief Medical Officer), or the station AI means you will be expected to play to a higher standard of roleplay, seriousness and competence. You may be Jobbaned from Command if you fail to meet these standards, or if you ignore your duties;

  If you choose to join as an important non-Command role, such as a Doctor or Engineer, you are expected to be able to fulfill said role's duties to a reasonable extent when work is actually needed to be done. Using the job just for the equipment, or consistently ignoring any emergencies that may require your attention may lead to a Jobban;

  The Captain and members of Security are expected to follow and have a good understanding of Space Law and SOP (Standard Operating Procedure). Consistent abuse of these positions will lead to a Jobban; however, you may request to play a corrupt member of Security via Adminhelp, with valid justification;

  Following, or failing to follow SOP is an IC issue, and should be handled and enforced in-character, not via Adminhelp, unless the player in question runs afoul of other Server Rules or the behavior persists excessively over multiple rounds.

  Synthetics may not ask for law changes, attempt to force the crew to change laws, or prevent Command from lawfully changing their laws unless they are an Antagonist, subverted, or their laws require it. If you suspect a law to be grief, Adminhelp before acting upon it;

  Cyborgs are expected to follow the same guidelines as organic crewmembers charged with those tasks, unless their laws state otherwise (eg, Engineering Cyborgs should follow the same guidelines as organic Engineers). Cyborgs are to follow an AI's commands without hesitation, unless unlinked or Laws dictate otherwise;

  Frequently joining a round, only to then leave or commit suicide if you did not get an Antagonist Role (Antag Fishing), is not permitted;

  ##Rule 6: Play Antagonists Responsibly
  Remember the goal of an Antagonist is to make the round exciting, fun, and dangerous, within limits. You should make an effort to add to the round, as opposed to simply completing your objectives and carrying on normally.

  The role of the Antagonist may pit you against the station. However, this is not grounds for murderboning the entire crew if your objective is to steal a jetpack, as you must work towards your objectives, not general mayhem. You may, however, antagonize/murder specific people who will help you complete your objective or who are hindering you from completing said objective. You are also permitted to freely defend yourself with lethal force if another player attempts to capture/hinder you;

  The Die a Glorious Death objective does not mean "Kill until killed", nor is it an excuse to take a large segment of the station down with you;

  If you are not willing to act as an Antagonist, or if you have to leave the round midway, Adminhelp so someone else can fill your role;

  Team-based Antagonists (such as Nuclear Operatives, Blobs, RevHeads, etc) are expected to Adminhelp if they need to leave the round so that Admins may replace them with minimal disruption to the round and tasks of the Antagonists;

  The Hijack the Shuttle objective means you are able to unleash whatever chaos is required on the station to accomplish your objectives. Certain rules, such as the ones concerning Metagaming and ERP, still apply. If in doubt, Adminhelp it;

  Antagonists are permitted to assist other antagonists with their objectives. They must tell you what their objectives are, before you can help them. They cannot simply request 'help'. They have to be specific about what the objective is, e.g: "The Syndicate asked me to kill X. Will you help?". This does not entitle you to mass-murder, or take other hijack-only actions, unless the person you are helping clearly tells you that they have hijack. If they do tell you that they have hijack, and you plan to help them by doing hijack-only actions, please ahelp this to let us know;

  Releasing the Singularity or the Tesla, tampering with Atmospherics, large scale destruction, or any other action that directly warrants a Shuttle Call, is reserved for those who have the "Hijack the Shuttle" Antagonist objective, or are a round-ending Antagonist by default (such as a Malfunctioning AI, Nuclear Operative or Wizard). The exception is if you have been given permission by the Server Staff;

  Antagonists are permitted to pursue their objectives even on the Escape Shuttle;

  Antagonists may not spawn camp the Arrivals Shuttle, or the immediate area, for late arrival victims

  ##Rule 7: Self-Antagging
  Some forms of Self-Antagging may be highly subjective. If an Administrator tells you to stop certain actions, you are to stop. An Administrator may also warn you if your general behavior over multiple rounds is becoming a problem, in which case you are to stop. If you need more clarification as to what behavior is a problem, you're highly encouraged to talk to the Server Staff about this.

  ###General Rules
  Minor criminal activity is allowed as a Non-Antagonist. However, it will be considered Self-Antagging if it negatively affects a significant portion of the crew, or is done without any reasonable IC justification and/or provocation;

  The use of bombs as a Non-Antagonist is only acceptable in the bomb range, lavaland, and other Z-level variants. If you wish to use bombs on the station z-level for any reason such as a Blob, Alien infestation, Nuclear Operatives, etc., contact the Server Staff and get their approval before doing anything;

  While the Escape Shuttle is in transit, Shuttle Grief is not allowed. Attacking people on the shuttle for any reason other than self-defense may lead to a Ban for Shuttle Griefing, with the exception of Antagonists completing their objectives. Violence is allowed once the shuttle has docked and end round statistics are displayed;

  Breaking people out of the Security Brig area is allowed as a Non-Antagonist to the extent of minor damage to the station. Releasing anyone from the Permabrig as a Non-Antagonist requires Administrator permission;

  Resisting arrest as a Non-Antagonist is allowed, but not to a lethal degree;

  Actively diverting Security personnel and resources away from an active and direct Antagonist threat in order to deal with you and your actions will be considered Self-Antagging;

  Claiming your character is a psychopath, has mental disorders, or any other related justification, does not change any of these rules, and is unacceptable as an excuse

  ###Assault and Self-Defense
  Murder is not acceptable for non-antags. Killing should only be done in extreme self-defense, during an authorized execution, or in any situation Security can employ lethal force. If you wish to murder, or at least seriously injure, someone, Administrator permission is required;

  Violence capable of inflicting serious damage to someone, especially anything that places them into a critical state, is reserved for Antagonists. Outside Self-Defense, this kind of violence is not permitted;

  Self-defense is allowed to the extent of saving your own life. Putting someone into Critical Condition is considered self-defense only if they attempted to severely hurt/kill you. Preemptively disabling someone, responding with disproportionate force, or hitting someone while they are already down, is not self-defense;

  Minor assault and fistfights are acceptable, assuming that both players have a reasonable justification as to why the fight started. Assault without any provocation or warning is strictly disallowed under a majority of circumstances.

  ###Clown and Mime
  Being the Clown or Mime does not give you a license to break any Server Rules, much less any Rules regarding violence. You are here to entertain the crew, and can do so via light pranking, puns, jokes or artistic miming;

  While defining "humour" is, in fact, very difficult, actions like kidnapping, stabbing someone with a screwdriver or slipping people who are fighting Nuclear Operatives, should be avoided. Deliberately hampering the crew during a Code Red, or higher, crisis, will give them ample justification to retaliate accordingly.

  ##Rule 8: Validhunting
  It is only the job of Security to stop Antagonists. If you are not a member of Security, then hunting Antagonists is not something you should be doing. You may not drop your job, or go out of your way, to hunt Antagonists. You may, however, defend yourself or others from Antagonist attack if you happen to witness it;

  Xenobiology/Sentient Animals: any form of non-antagonist Sentient Animals must both AHELP and Acquire Permission from the Head of Security and Captain before assisting with Security matters. You are allowed to defend yourself if either your master or yourself are attacked, but all validhunting Rules still apply unless you have been given express permission by both IC Command and online Admins.

  Antagonists that seek to destroy the station itself (Nuclear Operatives, or Malfunctioning AI), or exterminate the whole crew (Xenomorphs or Wizards) are exempt from this Rule. However, players in jobs such as Medical, or Cargo, are expected to do those jobs if they are better suited to help the station;

  ##Rule 9: Erotic Content
  As a general rule, anything more sexualized than kissing and hugging is considered ERP. We obviously cannot list all the fetishes that exist here, so please use common sense. Administrators may ask you to stop anything they feel is borderline, in which case you are to stop at once;

  Sexual innuendos, jokes, remarks, and comments are allowed to only a certain extent. They should not be used excessively and not overdone with details. Examples such as "Go blow one", "Eat a dick", or "Go twiddle the Captain" are fine;

  Linking any type of NSFW content anywhere on the server is strictly prohibited

</Document>
