<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Chief-Engineer <119664036+Chief-Engineer@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 NeKognitoHazard <168395829+NeKognitoHazard@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 TheNeonViking <julian.sean.ison@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Rouge2t7 <81053047+Sarahon@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Space Law
  Shiba Sector operates under abbreviated space law. All crew, passengers, and visitors aboard the station are expected to know and follow these laws.

  - [color=red][bold]Head of Security[/bold][/color] and especially [color=red][bold]Warden[/bold][/color] should be very familiar with space law.
  - Security players should strive to fully comprehend Space Law.
  - [bold]Ignoring or misuse of Space Law may be subject to punishment under incompetence. Do not play security if you do not plan to follow the rules[/bold]

  ## Treatment Of Prisoners

  Prisoners still have rights that must be upheld by law enforcement:

  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care. They should also be provided psychiatric and spiritual counselling if requested.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to communications equipment (Radios) so long as they are not abused.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter and safety. If the brig is no longer safe, confinement must be established in another location.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel during an interrogation if requested and available.
  - Prisoners must be given their shift mandated PDA during confinement. Unless there is solid proof of PDA tampering, in which case the PDA is to be secured and replaced with a fresh one
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement, and should not be restrained with handcuffs or other devices after incarceration unless there is an undue risk to life and limb. Similarly, any prisoners held for extended or permanent confinement should be held in the communal brig, and should not be confined to a solitary cell unless they pose a risk to life and limb.

  ## Searches

  - A personnel search is a seizure of the objects in a person's backpack, hands, coat, belt, pockets, and hat. If any contraband is found during a search the officer may choose to further the search into a detainment or simply confiscate the restricted items. After the search is conducted all legal items are to be returned to the person.

  - A crewmate may legally decline any search conducted without a warrant while the alert level is green. Should be noted that if the alert level is blue or above all personnel searches are legal and no longer require a warrant.

  ## Implantation
  - Any prisoner in custody can be subjected to implantation or implant extraction procedures, so long as it's within reason. The process of adding or extracting an implant should not prolong the detainees sentence, meaning you can not hold them longer to perform the procedure, unless stated otherwise. A former inmate can be requested to undergo implantation/extraction at a later point in time; if they fit the circumstances during their confinement, they must comply. The following have been listed out with special circumstances, anything not in this list can still be applied, given proper legal context. A prisoner can still receive implantation/extraction procedures without meeting the circumstances if they give their clear permission.

  - [bold]Mind Shields[/bold]: Shields can be administered to any inmate who has been clearly mind controlled, lost control of themselves, or a suspect charged with unlawful control. Unlike standard implantation you may hold a prisoner until you finish issuing Mind Shields, so long as it's done in a timely fashion. If a suspect refuses cooperate or the implant fails to function they can be charged with Refusal of Mental Shielding.

  ## Removal
  - A suspect can be forced to receive implant removal if there is strong reasonable proof that they have been implanted, such as an officer seeing them use one or their prints being on a discarded injector. Unlike implantation procedure a prisoner can have their sentence entirely delayed or extended until they comply with the procedure, as long as security are actively making attempts to preform it. Akin to implanting, if an inmate gives their clear permission, implant removal can proceed without proof.

  ## Blood testing
  - Blood testing is a procedure that can be used to determine if a person is a [textlink="Changeling" link="Changelings"]. Blood testing may only be forced when there has been confirmation of changelings existence on the station.

  ## Sentencing
  - All sentencing is to be handled by the Warden, if no Warden is available the HoS is to take over that duty, if there's no HoS it falls onto the highest ranking command member.

  - Use common sense and humanity when issuing punishments. You should not always seek out the highest punishment you can, you don't have to always give the maximum time or always look to demote someone. Always take in account the severity and only charge for what is needed for someone to learn their lesson.

  - [bold]Accessory, Attempting, And Intention:[/bold] If someone intentionally, knowingly and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime they can be charged with the relevant crimes, such as an engineer giving someone tools, who says they are going to break into an area. Same goes for a clear and solid attempt at a crime, or a person who shows clear intent to act out a crime, such as a syndicate nuclear operative arming a nuke but getting arrested before it goes off, they can still be charged with terrorism. Does not apply to crimes that have an attempted listing already, like attempted murder.

  - [bold]Stackable Crimes:[/bold] Crimes are to be considered 'stackable' in the sense that if you charge someone with two or more different crimes, you should combine the times you would give them for each crime.

  # YOU MAY NOT EXCEED 10 MINUTES AS A BRIG TIME

  Perma may be given to exceptionally problematic crewmembers within reason, even if the maximum crime does not allow for perma.


  # Execution
  - [bold]All executions are to be confirmed and overseen by the Captain. Exceptions to this rule exist. A prisoner may request a specific execution method, if reasonable. Otherwise the most humane method is prefered. Refer to Standard Operating Procedure to further understand any guidelines applied to execution.[/bold]

  # Exceptions
  - [bold]If a changeling is discovered they are kill on sight.[/bold]
  - [bold]Any unauthorised magic use should be treated seriously and may be kill on sight[/bold]
  - [bold]Any cases of weapons of mass destruction,extreme terrorism or clear intention to destroy the station are kill on sight[/bold]

  ## SOP guidelines
  - [textlink="Legal" link="Legal SOP"] refer to, for more in-depth guidelines.

  ## Crime Listing
  - [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]
</Document>
