<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Rouge2t7 <81053047+Sarahon@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Solstice <solsticeofthewinter@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Blueshield Officer (BSO) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Blueshield Officer[/bold][/color] of this station.

<ColorBox>
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" Margin="10">
    The [color=#1b67a5][bold]Blueshield Officer[/bold][/color] should never be Captain nor Head of Staff.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

The [bold][color=#fcd12a]most important[/color][/bold] rule of the Blueshield Officer is to protect and maintain the lives of Command personnel on the station.
<Box>Command personnel are personnel hired by Nanotrasen (confirmed personnel in command) and any Central Command officials (including NTR).</Box>

1. The Blueshield Officer is hired and entrusted with the sole responsibility of protecting command. They should only take action in matters related to command or upon request from command members, unless directed otherwise by Central Command.
  <Box>The Blueshield Officer should remain neutral on all conflicts between command staff.</Box>

2. The Blueshield Officer is to put the lives of Command over the lives of all others, including the Blueshield Officer. Their well-being is top priority.
<Box>This includes first aid, revival, and ensuring they are safe and secure during emergencies.</Box>

3. The Blueshield Officer is to protect the lives of Command, not follow their orders to a fault.

4. The Blueshield Officer is not permitted to interfere with legal demotions or arrests. To do so would be a violation of their Central Command orders and Space Law.
<Box>This primarily pertains to Command and Security work.</Box>

5. The Blueshield Officer may use lethal force when actively protecting a member of Command from a clear and present danger. When the situation permits, they should warn transgressors that lethal force will be used if they continue their actions.

6. If multiple command members are threatened at once, the Blueshield Officer should follow the Chain-Of-Command to know who to prioritize.
<Box>Central Command officials are to be prioritized over Command staff.  </Box>

</Document>
