<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Rouge2t7 <81053047+Sarahon@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Captain SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Captain[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. The Captain should [bold]NOT[/bold] act as a Security Officer. Their Job is to manage and help the station. Any deviation without reasonable reason may be grounds for demotion.

2. If a Department lacks a Head of Staff, the Captain should make an effort to appoint an Acting Head of Staff, if there are available personnel to fill the position.
<Box>Said Acting Head of Staff must be a member of the Department they are to lead.</Box>
<Box>The Acting Head of Staff must have the prefix 'Acting' in front of their title, and be relieved of duty when a new one is hired by Nanotrasen. Refer to [bold]Hiring/Transfer Policies[/bold]</Box>

3. The Captain is to ensure that Space Law is being correctly applied. This should be done in cooperation with the Head of Security and Warden.

4. Captain is [bold]heavily encourage[/bold] to give the provided pinpointer(s) to the Head of Security.
<Box>If the Head of Security is not available, then the Warden.</Box>
<Box>If neither are available on the current station, refer to the [bold]Chain of Command[/bold].</Box>

5. Captain may keep Captain spare IDs in their room or give it to the appropriate members in the [bold]Chain of Command[/bold].
<Box>The [color=#1b67a5][bold]Nanotrasen Representative[/bold][/color] and [color=#1b67a5][bold]Blueshield Officer[/bold][/color] are not permitted to carry these IDs.</Box>

6. The Captain is not to leave the Station unless given specific permission by Central Command or running with a "skeleton crew" (5 or less crew).

7. The Captain must keep the Nuclear Authentication Disk on their person at all times.

8. The Captain is to attempt to resolve every issue that arises in Command locally before contacting Central Command.

9. The Captain, despite being in charge of the Station, is not independent from NanoTrasen. Any attempts to disregard general company policy are to be considered an instant condition for contract termination.

10. Firing a Head of Staff [bold]must[/bold] be done with reasonable justification. Refer to [bold]Dismissal/Demotion Policies[/bold].
<Box>Firing Central Command VIPs ([color=#1b67a5][bold]Nanotrasen Representative[/bold][/color] and [color=#1b67a5][bold]Blueshield Officer[/bold][/color]) [bold]must[/bold] be done with authorization from Central Command.</Box>

11. The Captain may not promote anyone to Central Command VIP Positions ([color=#1b67a5][bold]Nanotrasen Representative[/bold][/color] and [color=#1b67a5][bold]Blueshield Officer[/bold][/color]) without authorization from Central Command.

12. The Captain may carry their weaponry on them at all times.

</Document>
