<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 BombasterDS2 <shvalovdenis.workmail@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Chief Medical Officer (CMO) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. The Chief Medical Officer is permitted to carry a regular Defibrillator or a Compact Defibrillator on their person at all times.

2. The Chief Medical Officer is permitted to carry a telescopic baton, flash, and syringe gun at all times.
<Box>The syringe gun should not contain harmful chemicals at any point except during emergencies, such as Nuclear Operatives, Blob, and/or Delta Alert.</Box>

3. The Chief Medical Officer is not permitted to allow the creation of poisonous or explosive mixtures in Chemistry without express consent from the Captain or, failing that, the presence of a clear and urgent danger to the integrity of the station, except of course in situations where Chemical Implants are required.

4. The Chief Medical Officer is not permitted to allow the release of any virus without a full list of its symptoms, and they must have a vaccine of the virus on hand to be given out on request.
<Box>The virus may not have any harmful symptoms whatsoever, though neutral/harmless symptoms are permitted.</Box>

5. The Chief Medical Officer must make sure that any cloneable corpses are cloned; except in cases where the individual has had a successful brain transplant.

6. The Chief Medical Officer is responsible for setting up the Cloning Devices in a location where Medical Personnel can access it.

7. The Chief Medical Officer is expected to assist Chemists and Medical Doctors when necessary.

8. The Chief Medical Officer is expected to work on Command Personnel over regular Medical Personnel when possible.

</Document>
