<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Head of Security (HOS) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Head of Security[/bold][/color] of this station.

<ColorBox>
  <Box>
    For the purposes of Alert Escalation: Treat higher alerts as if they are still on the previous alert level. (Yellow Alert is Blue Alert if it was Blue Alert prior.) Furthermore, treat Delta, Gamma, Epsilon, and Violet Alert as Red Alert.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

The [color=#1b67a5][bold]Head of Security[/bold][/color] is permitted to carry their shift-start equipment, but should follow escalation procedures and refrain from using lethals.

## Green Alert
1. The Head of Security is permitted to carry out arrests under the same conditions as their Security Officers.

2. The Head of Security is permitted to carry a standard disabler, a flash, a telescopic baton, a flashbang, and a standard energy gun.
<Box>While permitted to carry their unique Energy Gun, they should keep it on Stun/Disable.</Box>

3. The Head of Security is permitted to carry their standard equipment provided in their locker, including their submachine gun, but should refrain from using it.

4. The Head of Security is not obligated to provide a trial, but is encouraged to allow legal representation should the suspect request it. This only applies to Capital Crimes.

5. The Head of Security may not overrule a Captain/Nanotrasen Representative, unless their decisions are blatantly breaking Standard Operating Procedure and/or Space Law. In which case Central Command is to be contacted as well.

6. The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as the Warden for Armory equipment, portable flashers and deployable barriers.

7. The Head of Security is not permitted to collect equipment from the Armory to carry on their person.

8. The Head of Security is permitted to either use their regular coat, or armored trenchcoat.

9. The Head of Security is permitted to wear their unique gas mask.

10. The Head of Security may not overrule established sentences, unless further evidence is brought to light or the prisoner in question attempts to escape.

11. The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as Security Officers for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for Security Officers.

## Blue Alert
1. All Guidelines carry over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color].
<Box>The exception being that the energy gun may now be used in energy or ion mode if needed.</Box>

2. The Head of Security is permitted to use the submachine gun lethally for self-defense purposes. They must follow the same escalation laws for hostiles.

## Red Alert
1. All Guidelines carry over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color] and [color=#1b67a5]Blue Alert[/color].

2. The Head of Security is required to make a Station Announcement regarding the nature of the confirmed threat that caused [color=#ba292c]Red Alert[/color].
<Box>The Captain may perform this duty in the place of the Head of Security.</Box>

3. The Head of Security may also wear their hardsuit if necessary.

</Document>
