<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Head of Personnel (HOP) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Head of Personnel[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. The Head of Personnel should not assign personnel to any department without authorization from the relevant Head of Staff.
<Box>[bullet/]If no Head of Staff is available, they may make the judgement themselves; the exception being [color=#ba292c][bold]Security[/bold][/color], where only the Captain, HoS, and Warden (in the event of no HoS), may authorize a transfer.</Box>

2. The Head of Personnel should not give any personnel increased access without the relevant Head of Staff's authorization. The Head of Personnel should also not give anyone Captain access unless they are the [bold][color=#1b67a5]Acting Captain[/color][/bold].
<Box>[bullet/]Any Captain-level access should be removed when a Nanotrasen-assigned Captain joins the station.</Box>

3. The Head of Personnel may not increase any job openings unless the relevant Head of Staff approves.

4. The Head of Personnel may not dismiss/demote any personnel without authorization from the relevant Head of Staff (exceptions apply: see Space Law and General SOP).

5. The Head of Personnel may not promote anyone above Command. This includes positions such as Nanotrasen Representative, Blueshield Officer, and any other Central Command figure.

6. The Head of Personnel may utilize paperwork for proceedings, but should expedite requests during major station emergencies. Emergency Access takes precedence over paper.

7. The Head of Personnel should never leave their office unattended with personnel in-line unless required by an emergency.

8. The Head of Personnel is not permitted to perform Security duties; furthermore, the Head of Personnel is permitted to carry a non-lethal energy gun for self-defense.

9. The Head of Personnel is permitted to carry a telescopic baton, flash, and non-lethal energy gun on their person at all times.

10. The Head of Personnel must follow [bold]Hiring/Transfer Policies[/bold] and [bold]Dismissal/Demotion Policies[/bold] when performing such Standard Procedures.

11. The Head of Personnel must reference Chain of Command and [bold]Chain of Command[/bold] when necessary.

</Document>
