<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Nanotrasen Representative (NTR) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Nanotrasen Representative[/bold][/color] of this station.

<ColorBox><Box HorizontalAlignment="Center" Margin="10">The [color=#1b67a5][bold]Nanotrasen Representative[/bold][/color] should never be Captain nor Head of Staff.</Box></ColorBox>

The [bold][color=#fcd12a]most important[/color][/bold] rule of the Nanotrasen Representative is to assist Command Personnel and ensure they are following SOP.
<Box>Command personnel are personnel hired by Nanotrasen (confirmed personnel in command) and any Central Command officials (including NTR).</Box>
<Box>The Nanotrasen Representative is basically an OSHA Worker. Act like one and ensure departments are following the SOP and being Safe.</Box>

## Resources
1. The Nanotrasen Representative posesses a FAX machine to directly fax to Central Command (with notification to Central Command Officials).

2. In the event of an emergency, the station is equipped with a minimum of one Red Phone which directly notifies Central Command.

3. In the event of an emergency, the Nanotrasen Representative possesses a Central Command Encryption Key in their headset for direct communications with Central Command.

## Rulings
1. The Nanotrasen Representative is to ensure that every Department is following Standard Operating Procedure, including Command personnel.
<Box>If a Department does not have a corresponding Head of Staff, NTR must ensure the Captain appoints an Acting Head of Staff and assist in such endeavors to guide them.</Box>

2. The Nanotrasen Representative must attempt to resolve any [bold]major[/bold] breach of SOP before contacting Central Command. This is an imperative.
<Box>Standard Operating Procedure must generally be followed with reasonable justifications when it is ignored.</Box>

3. The Nanotrasen Representative is to ensure, along with Captain, Head of Security, and Warden, that Space Law is followed and being applied correctly.
<Box>This does not permit NTR to override brig timers, punishments, or any other Security endeavor unless Central Command orders as such.</Box>

4. The Nanotrasen Representative is not to use their direct connection to Central Command for leverage over other crew members.
<Box>In addition, they may not threaten to fire anyone (nor contact Central Command to do so) unless a justification for demotion exists.</Box>

</Document>
