<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Quartermaster (QM) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Quartermaster[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. The Quartermaster must ensure that every approved order is delivered within 15 minutes of having been placed and approved.

2. In the event of a major crisis, such as Nuclear Operatives, Blob, and/or Delta Alert, expediency is to be favored over paperwork, as excessive bureaucracy may be detrimental to the well-being of the station.

3. The Quartermaster is permitted to hack the Autolathe, or to have a Cargo Technician do so, assuming they do not produce illegal materials.

4. The Quartermaster is not permitted to authorize the ordering of Security equipment and/or gear without express permission from the Head of Security and/or Captain.
<Box>An exception is made during extreme emergencies, such as Nuclear Operatives, Blob, and/or Delta Alert, where said equipment is to be delivered to Security, post haste.</Box>

5. The Quartermaster is permitted to authorize non-departmental orders (such as a Medical Doctor asking for Insulated Gloves) without express permission from the respective Head of Staff (in this example, the Chief Engineer), utilizing their best judgement, although they may still request a stamped form.
<Box>However, any breach of Standard Operating Procedure and/or Space Law that results from said order will also implicate the Quartermaster.</Box>

6. The Quartermaster is not permitted to authorize a Supermatter Crate without express permission from the Chief Engineer.

7. The Quartermaster is required to follow the guidelines put in place for Cargo Technicians.

8. The Quartermaster must carry a handheld radio to keep in contact with Salvage in case of emergencies or general communication when they are on an expedition or too far from the station.

9. The Quartermaster is permitted to carry a telescopic baton and flash during all alert levels.

</Document>
