<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Research Director (RD) SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Research Director[/bold][/color] of this station.

<ColorBox>
  <Box>
    For the purposes of Alert Escalation: Treat higher alerts as if they are still on the previous alert level. (Yellow Alert is Blue Alert if it was Blue Alert prior.) Furthermore, treat Delta, Gamma, Epsilon, and Violet Alert as Red Alert.
  </Box>
</ColorBox>

## Green Alert
1. The Research Director must make sure Research is being done, and monitor Anomalies and Artifacts progress, including Robotics as well.

2. The Research Director is permitted to carry a telescopic baton and flash.

3. The Research Director is not permitted to bring harmful chemicals outside of Science.

4. The Research Director is permitted to carry/wear their Experimental Hardsuit on them, but should keep it inactive unless necessary, for personal safety.

5. The Research Director is permitted to change the AI Unit's lawset, provided they receive general approval from the Captain and another Head of Staff.
<Box>If there are no other Heads of Staff available, Captain approval will suffice.</Box>

6. The Research Director must ensure the cyborg computer is kept safe and used appropriately, avoiding any unnecessary damage to crew or NanoTrasen property.

## Blue Alert
1. All guidelines from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color] carry over to [color=#1b67a5]Blue Alert[/color]. No special guidelines added.

## Red Alert
1. Guidelines 1, 4, 5, and 6 carry over from [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color].

2. In addition to the telescopic baton and flash, the Research Director is permitted to carry a single weapon created in the Protolathe, with permission from Captain, Head of Security, and/or Warden.
<Box>Exceptions apply for extreme emergencies, permitting the use without approval, for cases such as Blobs, Nuclear Operatives, and/or Delta Alert.</Box>

3. The Research Director is permitted to bring harmful chemicals outside of Security so long as it is for Security personnel.
<Box>Said chemicals must be for security-oriented purposes, such as thermite, controlled explosives, crowd control, biohazard containment, et cetera.</Box>

4. The Research Director should ensure that AI and Cyborgs are to remain under control of crew personnel (not corrupted) to the best of their ability.

</Document>
