<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Station Alert - Blue

  <Box>
    [italic]Called by: Anyone with Command-Level Access at a working Communications Console.[/italic]
  </Box>

  [bold]Conditions:[/bold]

  There is a suspected threat on-board the station, or at a nearby location in space. This includes any signs of hostile activity that have not caused any damage to station or crew, but nonetheless seem present.

  [italics]Minor threats such as thieves, bar fights, and non-violent protests are not credible enough threats to elevate alert level to blue.

  [bold]OR[/bold]

  Confirmed Code Red threats have been properly handled or subsided on their own. It is recommended that, after 10+ minutes on Code Red without any hostile activity, Code Blue be called.

  [bold]Security:[/bold]

  Weapons do not need to be holstered. However, it is recommended that Security personnel follow Security SOP in order to prevent accidents and to be fully aware of armament procedure;

  Random searches are fully permitted. Security personnel may detain any personnel refusing a random search in order to conduct said search;

  [bold]Secure Areas:[/bold]

  EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator, Engineering Secure Storage, AI Upload, Vault, Gateway, anywhere else requiring command level access that does not get regularly used.

  It is recommended that all Secure Areas be bolted down unless their use is necessary;

  Excursions into the Gateway are not recommended, unless they are rescue parties.

  [bold]General Crew:[/bold]

  All personnel are highly recommended to maximize their Suit Sensors;

  Personnel are to report any suspicious activity to the nearest member of Security, or use their PDA or headsets if required;

  Personnel are highly encouraged to exercise caution, even if the threat is only suspected. Following simple safety procedures (such as not going through Maintenance alone) can prevent needless accidents;

  Visitors to the station (anyone with Civilian-level access) are recommended to stay in public areas, for their safety.

</Document>
