<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
    # Station Alert - Green

    <Box>
        [italic]Called by: Anyone with Command-Level Access at a working Communications Console.[/italic]
    </Box>

    [bold]Conditions:[/bold]

    Default Alert Code at the start of the shift. Do not change unless a threat is suspected/confirmed;

    [bold]OR[/bold]

    All confirmed/suspected threats to the station and/or crew have been handled, or simply vanished on their own. It is recommended that, after 15+ minutes on Code Blue without any hostile activity, Code Green be called;

    [bold]Security:[/bold]

    All weapons must be holstered or kept in pockets/suit storage slots unless absolutely required;

    Random searches are not permitted without express permission by either the Head of Security or Captain. However, searches are still permitted if there is reasonable suspicion of a crime.

    [bold]Secure Areas:[/bold]

    EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator, Engineering Secure Storage, AI Upload, Vault, Gateway, anywhere else requiring command level access that does not get regularly used.

    Secure areas such as EVA are to be left unbolted and ready to be used for their intended purposes.

    Exceptions are below;

    The Vault is not to be opened unless repairs are required, gold is required for Research and Development (in case Mining fails to deliver) or a critical item needs to be hidden in the safe.

    Searches of a person or department need to have a signed and stamped warrant by the Captain or HoP.

    [bold]General Crew:[/bold]

    While not required, it is recommended that the crew activate and maximize their Suit Sensors, due to the potential for workplace accidents;

    Free transit through the station is permitted for the crew, excluding Secure Areas.

</Document>
