<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Station Alert - Red

  <Box>
    [italic]Called by: Anyone with Command-Level Access at a working Communications Console.[/italic]
  </Box>

  [bold]Conditions:[/bold]

  There is a confirmed, hostile threat on-board the station or nearby in space. This threat should pose recognizable danger to the station and/or crew at large.

  [bold]Security:[/bold]

  Security personnel should read Security SOP for armament, armory and safety procedures;

  Random searches are fully permitted and recommended. Security personnel may detain any personnel refusing a random search in order to conduct said search;

  Security personnel are to cooperate fully with any Central Command Staff (such as Emergency Response Teams) in order to eliminate the threat to the station.

  [bold]Secure Areas:[/bold]

  EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator, Engineering Secure Storage, AI Upload, Vault, anywhere else requiring command level access that does not get regularly used.

  There are no restrictions on bolting Secure Areas. Secure Areas may be left bolted or unbolted at the discretion of Command personnel;

  [bold]General Crew:[/bold]

  All personnel are required to maximize their Suit Sensors;

  Unless their job demands it, personnel are forbidden from entering maintenance tunnels. Personnel in violation of this order may be charged with trespassing;

  Visitors to the station (anyone with Civilian-level access) are to remain inside the Bar, Library or Dormitories for the duration of Code Red;

  Personnel are to follow the instructions of Security staff, so long as they are within the bounds of Space Law and are not acting against the general well-being of the station and its crew. Failure to do so may lead to their arrest for Creating a Workplace Hazard.

  Crewmembers in maintenance without proper reason or authorization may be detained for trespassing.

</Document>
