<Document>
# Alert Procedure
Alert levels exist on the station to advise the crew at-large of the state of the station's overall security or well-being. Setting an alert level via the communications computer is an immediate action, so it is often done after sending a message to the crew.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerComms" Caption="This sets the alert level."/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyLight" Caption="This displays the alert level."/>
</Box>
There are some restrictions on when certain alert levels can be used. They are elaborated on as follows:

## Code Green
[color=#7cfc00]Regular operating conditions, absent or manageable station threat(s) present.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Standard armor/weaponry loadout advised for all Security personnel. Open carry of additional lethal arms disallowed.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Report to supervisor for general orders.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with minimal force; prioritize de-escalation whenever possible.

## Code Blue
[color=#0000FF]Elevated alert status. There is a confirmed threat to the station or its crew.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Head of Security ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying lethal weaponry permitted for all security personnel. Standard ballistic armor highly recommended for security personnel.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Report to supervisor for general orders. Random searches may be performed at the discretion of security personnel, without a warrant.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Binary suit sensors recommended; full sensors encouraged. EVA suits recommended for emergency responders, functioning internals heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color]: EVA suits recommended for engineers. Make emergency internals easily accessible.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with minimal force; non-lethal weapons may be used freely based on threat and compliance. [bold]Intruders on the station are not considered crew and are not subject to standard Rules of Engagement. It is always acceptable to meet an intruder with lethal force.[/bold]

## Code Red
[color=#ff0000]Emergency alert status. There is an immediate security emergency affecting the station.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Head of Security ◃ Security Personnel ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying weaponry permitted for all security personnel. Standard ballistic armor mandatory, hardsuits heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Report to supervisor for general orders. Searches and departmental raids may be performed at the discretion of security personnel, without a warrant. Open carry permitted at the discretion of Command.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Full suit sensors mandatory for observation and safety. EVA suits and functioning internals heavily advised for emergency responders.
- [color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color]: EVA suits heavily advised for engineers. Distribute emergency internals to crew.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with necessary force; lethal force is permitted in self-defense, or in the defense of a crewmember; non-lethal methods must be attempted first. [bold]Intruders on the station are not considered crew and are not subject to standard Rules of Engagement. It is always acceptable to meet an intruder with lethal force.[/bold]

## Code Pink
[color=pink]Emergency alert status. The station is currently beseiged by strike, mutiny, or other union activity.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Head of Security ◃ Security Personnel ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying weaponry permitted for all security personnel. Standard ballistic armor mandatory.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Martial law is in effect. Searches and departmental raids may be performed at the discretion of security personnel and without a warrant. All arrests permitted at discretion of security personnel. Threats that have been incapacitated by lethal force may be withheld medical treatment until Code Pink has been rescinded. Security is fully authorized to take whatever actions deemed necessary to neutralize union threats.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Full suit sensors mandatory for observation and safety.
- [color=#a4885c]Cargo[/color]: Purchase mindshield and tracking implants for the use of Security.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with necessary force; lethal force is permitted in self-defense, or to effect an arrest.

## Code Violet
[color=#7f00ff]Elevated alert status. There is a serious viral outbreak or other significant medical emergency.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Chief Medical Officer ◃ Medical Personnel ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying of lethal weapons disallowed. Standard ballistic armor recommended for all security personnel. Basic PPE mandatory for all personnel, level 3 biohazard gear heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Report to supervisor for orders. Non-medical personnel should ensure they do not interfere with medical staff, may assist where applicable, and obey all applicable orders from medical personnel. Security should seek to aid medical staff in enforcement of quarantine procedures or medical treatment as necessary.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Report to supervisor for orders. Full suit sensors heavily advised. EVA suits recommended for emergency responders, functioning internals and PPE heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color]: Standard practice.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with minimal force; prioritize de-escalation whenever possible.

## Code Yellow
[color=#ffff00]Elevated alert status. There is a major structural or atmospheric damage to the station.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Chief Engineer ◃ Engineering Personnel ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying of lethal weapons disallowed. Standard ballistic armor recommended for all security personnel. EVA suits heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Report to supervisor for orders. Non-engineering personnel advised to evacuate affected areas and obey any relevant instructions from engineering personnel. Security should seek to aid engineering staff where possible.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Full suit sensors heavily advised. EVA suits and functioning internals recommended for emergency responders.
- [color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color]: EVA suits heavily advised for engineers. Distribute emergency internals to crew. Propose evacuation if damage is irreparable or sufficiently hazardous.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with minimal force; prioritize de-escalation whenever possible.

## Code Gamma
[color=#db7093]Emergency alert status. The Station is on its last legs, almost everyone is dead, or there is another existential crisis affecting the station.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Head of Security ◃ Security Personnel ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying weaponry permitted for all security personnel. Standard ballistic armor mandatory, EVA suits heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Report to supervisor for general orders. Martial law is in effect. Open carry disallowed for non-security personnel. Searches and departmental raids may be performed at the discretion of security personnel and without a warrant. All arrests permitted at discretion of security personnel. Threats that have been incapacitated by lethal force may be withheld medical treatment until Code Gamma has been rescinded. Security is fully authorized to take whatever actions deemed necessary to neutralize or repel station threats. Propose evacuation or scuttling if station cannot be retaken.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Full suit sensors mandatory for observation and safety. EVA suits and functioning internals heavily advised for emergency responders.
- [color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color]: EVA suits heavily advised for engineers. Distribute emergency internals to crew.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with necessary force; lethal force is permitted in self-defense, or to effect an arrest.

## Code Delta
[color=#8b0000]Emergency alert status. The station is currently under threat of imminent destruction. Should reversal of impending destruction prove impossible, evacuate.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Head of Security ◃ Security Personnel ◃ Department Heads
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying weaponry permitted for all security personnel. Standard ballistic armor mandatory, EVA suits heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Martial law is in effect. Searches and departmental raids may be performed at the discretion of security personnel and without a warrant. Arrests of officers permitted at discretion of security personnel. Threats that have been incapacitated by lethal force may be kept in Preservative Stasis until Code Delta has been rescinded. Security is fully authorized to take whatever actions deemed necessary to neutralize or repel station threats.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Full suit sensors heavily advised. EVA suits and functioning internals heavily advised for emergency responders.
- [color=#a4885c]Engineering[/color]: EVA suits heavily advised for engineers. Distribute emergency internals to crew.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with necessary force; lethal force is permitted in self-defense, or to effect an arrest.

## Code Octarine
[color=#4cabb3]Emergency alert status. The station is facing imminent bluespace destruction.[/color]
- [color=#a4885c]Chain of Command[/color]: Captain ◃ Head of Security ◃ Security Personnel ◃ Department Heads ◃ Chaplain
- [color=#a4885c]Armory Policy[/color]: Open carrying weaponry permitted for all security personnel. Standard ballistic armor mandatory, EVA suits heavily advised.
- [color=#a4885c]Discipline[/color]: Martial law is in effect. Searches and departmental raids may be performed at the discretion of security personnel and without a warrant. Arrests of officers permitted at discretion of security personnel. Threats that have been incapacitated by lethal force may be withheld medical treatment until Code Octarine has been rescinded. Security is fully authorized to take whatever actions deemed necessary to neutralize or repel station threats.
- [color=#a4885c]Medical[/color]: Full suit sensors mandatory for observation and safety.
- [color=#a4885c]Cargo[/color]: Purchase mindshield and tracking implants for the use of Security.
- [color=#a4885c]Rules of Engagement[/color]: Engage with necessary force; lethal force is permitted in self-defense, or to effect an arrest.

</Document>
