<Document>
# Important Character Creation Tips
This is a guide for the parts of character creation that effect gameplay.

[textlink="For a guide on making cosmetic changes, click here." link="YourFirstCharacter"]

## Spawn Priority
This affects where you spawn in upon joining the game after the round has already started.

Choosing "Arrivals" will spawn you on a separate station where you wait for a shuttle to arrive to ship you to the main station.

Choosing "Cryosleep" will have you wake up in a cryosleep chamber already on the station.

Choosing "None" will either pick for you or choose the only spawn option available for the current station.

This is a mostly arbitrary choice. You can safely leave this on "None" and you won't suffer any real inconveniences.

## Jobs
You can set your job preferences in the lobby. While these don't [color=#a4885c]guarantee[/color] your position, someone who wants the job will be [color=#a4885c]randomly[/color] selected at the start of the round.
You are given a chance at being chosen for your high priority job first, then your medium priorities, then your low priorities.
You also given an option to automatically be a passenger or to be sent back to the lobby if you don't get chosen for any of your preferred jobs.

Some jobs are locked until you've played long enough as other entry level jobs.

[textlink="For more infomation about jobs, click here." link="Jobs"]

## Job Loadouts
You may also choose [color=#a4885c]loadouts[/color] for each job. Loadouts are the clothing items and trinkets that you spawn with upon joining the game. Some loadout items are locked behind playtime restrictions.
This may have various effects on gameplay, as some clothing items have [color=#a4885c]armor protection[/color] or [color=#a4885c]slow down your movement speed[/color]. This applies especially to Command and Security.

You may also choose what bag you spawn in with.
[color=#a4885c]Backpacks[/color] are medium sized but can carry large items easier. [color=#a4885c]Satchels[/color] have more total space than backpacks but have trouble carrying large items. [color=#a4885c]Duffel bags[/color] are large but incur a movement penalty.

## Antags
Turning on an [color=#a4885c]antagonist[/color] toggle will put you on the list of potentional antags at the start of the round. They do not guarantee your antagonist role, don't use this as an excuse to self-antag!
Instead, like job priorities, a handful of players are chosen randomly from eligible players. If you are a command member or security officer, you cannot be chosen for an antag role.

[textlink="For more information about antagonists, click here." link="Antagonists"]

Joining multiple games or ghosting/disconnecting/commiting suicide upon not being chosen for an antag role is referred to as "antag-rolling" and it is against the rules.
Plenty of people patiently wait for their turn to be antagonists, so [color=#a4885c]we kindly ask you to refrain from opting-in to an antagonist role if you aren't ready[/color].

## Traits
Speech traits alter your speech, sometimes to an extreme degree.

They include:
- Accentless (disables the accent of your selected species)
- Cowboy accent (word replacement, partner)
- Frontal lisp ("s" is replaced with "th")
- Italian accent (Mamma-mia, word replacement)
- Pathological liar (word replacement, changes words like "yes" to "no")
- Pirate accent (Arrgh, word replacement)
- Social anxiety (s-s-stutter)
- Southern Drawl (replaces "-ing" with "-in'" and similar changes)

You should be comfortable with talking normally or with a minor accent such as Social anxiety or Southern drawl before taking heavy accents like Italian or Cowboy.

There are also disabilty traits. Familiarize yourself with the game and the game's flow before taking one of these, as some may become difficult for beginners to deal with.

They include:
- Blindness (severely limits your vision)
- Lightweight drunk (you get drunk faster and you suffer more from the ill-effects of alcohol)
- Muted (you cannot talk or whisper, but you can still communicate via emotes and pen and paper)
- Narcolepsy (you randomly fall asleep at unpredictable and often inconvenient times)
- Pacifist (you cannot hit, shoot, or throw sharp objects at people)
- Paracusia (you sometimes hear noises that aren't real)
- Short-sighted (somewhat limits your vision without prescription glasses)
- Snoring (you make loud snoring sounds when asleep)
- Unrevivable (you cannot be resuscitated when you meet your untimely demise)
</Document>
