<Document>
  # Important Character Creation Tips
  This is a guide for the parts of character creation that effect [color=cyan]gameplay[/color].

  [italic]A guide for customizing your character's appearance can be found [textlink="here" link="YourFirstCharacter"].[/italic]
  
  ## Spawn Priority
  This affects where you spawn in upon joining the game after the round has already started. You can choose between:
  - [bold]Arrivals[/bold], which will have you wait for a shuttle to take you to the main station.
  - [bold]Cryosleep[/bold], which spawns you on the station in a cryosleep chamber.
  - [bold]None[/bold], which lets the game choose for you.

  ## Jobs
  You can set your job preferences in the lobby. While [color=cyan]these don't guarantee[/color] your position, someone who wants the job will be randomly selected at the start of the round.

  Some jobs are locked until you've played long enough as other entry level jobs.

  [italic]More detailed guides about jobs can be found [textlink="here" link="Jobs"].[/italic]

  ## Job Loadouts
  You can decide on [color=cyan]loadouts[/color] for each job. This may have various effects on gameplay, especially for Command and Security.

  You may also choose what bag you spawn in with.
  - [bold]Backpacks[/bold] are medium sized.
  - [bold]Satchels[/bold] have slightly more space but have trouble fitting large items.
  - [bold]Duffel bags[/bold] are large but incur a movement penalty.

  ## Antags
  Turning on an [color=cyan]antagonist[/color] gives you a chance to be that antag for the next round, like a job priority. If you are a command member or security officer, you cannot be chosen for an antag role.

  [italic]Information on antagonists can be found [textlink="here" link="Antagonists"].[/italic]

  Plenty of people patiently wait for their turn to be antagonists, so we kindly ask you to refrain from opting-in to an antagonist role if you aren't ready.

  ## Traits
  Accent traits alter your speech, sometimes to an extreme degree.

  There are also disabilty traits. Familiarize yourself with the game and the game's flow before taking one of these, as some may become difficult for beginners to deal with.
</Document>
