<Document>
# Welcome!

Welcome to the alpha build of Space Station 14!
You have just started your shift aboard a Nanotrasen space station. You and your crewmates should cooperate, perform your jobs the best you can and have fun.

We hope you enjoy the game, and this entry will serve to guide you on how to learn to play.

There's quite a bit to read, but SS14 is in itself a very large and in-depth game, and hopefully these guides help you enjoy it to its fullest.

This entry and its subentries contain simple and broad information new players need to play the game on most servers.

Some information given here may be repeated or further touched upon in the Station and Shifts entry, [textlink="which can be found here." link="SS14"]

## How to use this guidebook
This guidebook contains [color=#a4885c]step-by-step instructions[/color] on how to perform tasks, [color=#a4885c]tables of components[/color] one might require,
or simply [color=#a4885c]tips, tricks and guidelines[/color] on how to perform your job.

You can refresh yourself on your job before starting your shift or reference certain pages as needed, [textlink="such as recipes for cocktails" link="Drinks"].

## Wait, what's Space Station 14?
Space Station 14 is a free (forever) open source remake of the infamous Space Station 13, hoping to provide an improved experience for both newcomers and old players alike. Space Station 14 is designed as a fully moddable experience that you can modify to your liking with custom servers, adding entire swaths of new content for people to explore.

Please make sure you understand the server rules (F1) and if you have any questions, consult this guide, your colleagues on shift in person or over radio or via discord. You can also ask admins for help (ahelp) by hitting the escape key > admin help and typing a message to any online admins. Especially do this if you witness someone breaking rules.

[color=#a4885c]To reiterate, you are all a crew of people who work together[/color] and you should not be harming each other unless you have an extremely good reason (such as self-defence) and even then, you should call security over radio.

</Document>
