<Document>
# Welcome to Trieste Port-14!

You've just begun your first day aboard Trieste Port, the oceanside platform city!
You and your fellow citizens are tasked with working together, surviving, and having fun!

[bold]Make sure to follow all server rules.[/bold] You can ask questions or report rule breaks to the [color=#EB2D3A][bold]admin team[/bold][/color] by using the [bold]admin help menu[/bold]. ([italic]accessible by pressing [/italic][color=yellow][bold][keybind="OpenAHelp"/][/bold][/color])

More detailed guides about [italic]specific jobs[/italic] and [italic]mechanics[/italic] can be found [textlink="here." link="SS14"/]

This guide can be reopened at any time using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="OpenGuidebook"][/bold][/color].

## Basic Controls
The following are the controls you'll need for regular gameplay:

- Run using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="MoveUp"][keybind="MoveLeft"][keybind="MoveDown"][keybind="MoveRight"][/bold][/color]. Hold down [color=yellow][bold][keybind="Walk"][/bold][/color] to walk

- Examine the world around you with [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ExamineEntity"][/bold][/color]

- Interact with the world using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="Use"][/bold][/color]

- Hovering over an entity and pressing [color=yellow][bold][keybind="UseSecondary"][/bold][/color] shows the [italic]context menu[/italic], which contains additional interactions

- Swap hands using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="SwapHands"][/bold][/color] and activate the currently held item with [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ActivateItemInHand"][/bold][/color]

- Drop held items with [color=yellow][bold][keybind="Drop"][/bold][/color] or throw them using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ThrowItemInHand"][/bold][/color]

- Pull and release things with [color=yellow][bold][keybind="TryPullObject"][/bold][/color] and [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ReleasePulledObject"][/bold][/color]

A more comprehensive list can be found on the [textlink="controls" link="Controls"] page.

## What is Trieste Port?

Trieste Port is a fork of base space station 14, where instead of a station players play on an ocean world.

  To the far west of the Platoform map, a diving bell will arrive periodically to bring players between the ocean floor and the platform.

  The platform contains the Cargo department, the Bridge, the Kitchen, the Reporter's office, Security and Medical.
  Sweetwater, the ocean floor, contains: Science, Engineering, Salvage, the Janitor, the Bar, the Library and the Head of Personnel.

  Outside of Sweetwater, there is a simulated ocean with floodable water. The water and it's residents are extremely dangerous, so be careful near airlocks.

</Document>
