<Document>
# Editing your Character
This is a guide for editing your character's appearance. Make sure you read Character Creation first, for information about how to create your character.
Upon creating your character, you may be intimidated by your vast range of options.
  
It's okay to make your first character [color=#a4885c]randomized[/color] and roll with it, even experienced players do it. However, please keep in mind,
on our server, the character is very important and needs to be connected to a background and lore, making sense and being explainable in the SS14 universe.
This means, that once your character is created, the [color=#a4885c]changes you can make[/color] to it are limited. While for example, you [color=#11ff11]
can change[/color] your haircut or hair color and even your facial hair, you [color=#ff1111]cannot change[/color] your background or your skin color.
  
We recommend, that you think well about characters, its appearanceand its background and that you be [color=#a4885c]methodical[/color] in its creation. This
will make creating a character a complex albeit relatively easy task to do, if you do it one step at a time. Just keep in mind that [color=#a4885c]any changes
[/color] you make to your character later on, need to be [color=#ff1111]realistically possible and explainable in RP[/color]. Any changes to your characters
physical aspects, such as skin color or size, need [color=#11ff11] admin approval[/color].

Things you [color=#11ff11]CAN[/color] change include:

- Haircut
- Facial Hair
- Weight
- Markings and Scarfs
- Clothing
- Languages you speak (with RP explanation, i.e. doing a language course, etc.)
- Pronouns used (the change might need RP explanation or clarification)
- Languages and Accents (you need to RP it out and explain it)

Things you [color=#ff1111]CANNOT[/color] change include:

- Race
- Size
- Skin Color
- Background (some exceptions are possible with admin approval, if it is related to RP or makes sense (game updates, new features, etc.)
- Allergies and Medical Conditions (unless it is possible to cure them in game and canon)
- Professional Job (i.e. Engineering, Science, etc.) unless the character has received training and studied for it and obtains HoP and department head approval.
- Civlian NT Jobs (Janitor, Chef, etc.) unless they receive HoP approval and (if required) have the necessary skill or someone to train them.

Contractors once implemented, are [color=#a4885c]excluded[/color] from job change restrictions. They can offer whatever service they want and charge for it, but
they are bound to comply with their contracts, if they want to avoid lawsuits and fines. Some services however might [color=#11ff11]require a permit or license[/color].

[italic]If you are in doubt about whether a change is legit or not, feel free to ask the admin staff.[/italic]

## Choosing a Species
Most species have minor differences. If you want to find out more about each species, you can do so by checking out the
[color=#a4885c]Species[/color] entry in this guidebook. Please keep in mind, that your species [color=#a4885c]must exist[/color]
in the SS14 universe. Creating a new species, requires [color=#ff1111]admin approval[/color]. We recommend, your first species to
be human, for the ease of use. Especially if you have little roleplay experience and are new to SS14.

If you play a non-human species, like dwarfs or a moth, make sure you are familiar with all their related canon information, such as
their eating habits, the abilities and limitations, etc. Some races are pretty difficult to play and RP. For example, there are races,
that breath nitrogen instead of oxygen, requiring them to [bold]ALWAYS[/bold] have an N2 Tank and internals on them.

Once you are ready for a more complex character, you may find that it's a good idea, to start with a moth, dwarf or reptilian. You will need to learn the differences
and habits as well as this race's history and background lore, but in game, they play very similar to a human character, and thus are not too difficult to get into.

The fact that it might involve significantly more work and effort and may result in a much more difficult gameplay, shouldn't discourage you from getting creative with your character, or from creating a character using one of the more advanced races. Especially for experienced role players, these advanced characters, while challenging, are
usually a lot of fun to play, if they are fleshed out well and if the player knows how to RP them.

This guide will assume you are creating a human, but the process for creating and editing your character is similar across all species. The biggest difference will be,
that some options might be different or missing, while new ones are added.

## Minor Characteristics
These include:
- Age (18-29 for young, 30-59 for middle-aged, 60+ for old)
- Sex (your sprite, as seen by toggling "Show clothing")
- Pronouns (what the game will refer to you as)
- Skin color (may be a slider or RGB depending on species)
- Eye color (RGB)
- Hair color (RGB)

These are minor changes and have little effect on gameplay. This is what players will read when they [color=#a4885c]examine you[/color]. ("young man")

## Hair and Facial Hair
Again, you may be intimidated by the vast range of options. That's okay. Just take your time, try the different options out and play around. This can be
changed at any time, without admin approval, even during a running shift, using a mirror.

[color=#a4885c]Take your time with it.[/color] Character creation is fundamental and the most important step on our server. Your character will be your
personality. It will be what others know you buy and what you will be spending many hourse playing. To get a basic idea, you can skim or click through each
of the options and find which one you like. Sometimes it might be easier to set your desired hair color before looking at the options.

If you really can't decide, some popular haircut options include Floorlength Bedhead, Modern, Business, CIA or simply bald.
Alternatively, [color=#a4885c]randomize[/color] a separate character and see what kind of haircuts they're rocking with. Suprise yourself.

[bold]Remember, your character is yours. You don't have to go by something, everybody else does, or be shy of doing something, nobody else has tried.[/bold] As
long as it is an available option for your character and makes sense in game or can be realistically explained, it's fine. Think about it! Most human males are
about 6" (180 cm) tall. Still, there are some humans, albeit rare, that get fairly close to the 7" (200 cm+) mark.
  
## Markings
Markings range from [color=#a4885c]scars and snouts[/color] to [color=#a4885c]tattoos and tails[/color].
Think of them like [color=#a4885c]accessories[/color] that are a part of your body, for giving your character some extra flair and uniqueness.
They cannot be changed during the round without admin intervention and to change them. Additionally medical intervention during a round is required. After a round,
markings can be changed or removed freely, but [color=#ffff11]require proper RP and explanation[/color] during the next round. After all people will notice the
difference.

Keep in mind, that some species have more marking options than others. Humans are more limited in terms of markings than moths or reptilians.

You can have a set number of markings in each '[color=#a4885c]category[/color]', as seen at the top. For example, reptilians can have one chest marking but two markings on the top of their heads. Markings are [color=#a4885c]cosmetic[/color] in their nature and have no effect on gameplay. There exist purely for customization and style purposes.

## How to stand out
Memorable characters are usually remembered for their personality, their deeds and their [color=#a4885c]robustness[/color], but that doesn't mean you have to be some sort of hotshot. Remember, that [color=#ffff11]memories, experiences and events[/color] are carried over between shifts and will be remembered by others. This allows you, to make
youeself known by whom you are, but also means, that any damge done to relations might take a significant time to repair.

Don't sweat having a big, flashy and memorable character. Make your own story that you'll be remembered for. The most important part is, that you are having fun and can nail it
with great RP.
</Document>
