<Document>
# The Captains and the Clowns
Upon creating your character, you may be intimidated by your vast range of options. It's okay to be scared. Everyone else is secretly equally as terrified.
  
It's okay to make your first character randomized and roll with it, even experienced players do it.
Making your first character doesn't have to be precise, either. You can wing it and see what happens.
  
If you'd like to be methodical, though, creating a character is easy to do one step at a time.

## Choosing a Species
Most species have minor differences, which you can read about under the Species entry.
However, you may find that it's easier to make your first character as a human, moth, dwarf or reptilian.

This shouldn't discourage you from getting creative with your character, though! If you have a character in mind that you truly want to show the world, go for it.

This guide will assume you are creating a human, but the process is similar across all species.

## Minor Characteristics
These include:
- Age (18-29 for young, 30-59 for middle-aged, 60+ for old)
- Sex (your sprite, as seen by toggling "Show clothing")
- Pronouns (what the game will refer to you as)
- Skin color (may be a slider or RGB depending on species)
- Eye color (RGB)
- Hair color (RGB)

These are minor changes and have little effect on gameplay. This is what players will read when they examine you. ("young man")

## Hair and Facial Hair
Again, you may be intimidated by the vast range of options. That's okay.

Take your time with it. You can skim or click through each of the options and find which one you like.
Sometimes it's easier to set your desired hair color before looking at the options.

If you really can't decide, some popular haircut options include Floorlength Bedhead, Modern, Buisness, CIA or just bald! No shame in being bald.
Alternatively, randomize a character and see what kind of cuts they're rocking with. Suprise yourself.
Don't feel obligated to use any of these, though.
  
## Markings
Markings range from scars and snouts to tattoos and tails. Think of them like accessories that are a part of your body, as they cannot be removed during the round.
This is usually to give your character some extra flair that clothing can't accomplish.
Some species have more marking options than others. Humans are more limited in terms of markings than moths or reptilians.

You can have a set number of markings in each 'category', as seen at the top. For example, reptilians can have one chest marking but two markings on the top of their heads.
These are cosmetic and have no effect on gameplay.

## How to stand out
You don't really need to stand out, but memorable characters are usually remembered for their personality, their deeds and their robustness. Don't sweat having a big, flashy and memorable character.
Become the character and forge a story of your own.
</Document>
