<Document>
# The Captains and the Clowns
This is a guide for editing your character's appearance. Make sure you read Character Creation first.
Upon creating your character, you may be intimidated by your vast range of options.
  
It's okay to make your first character [color=#a4885c]randomized[/color] and roll with it, even experienced players do it.
Making your first character doesn't have to be precise, either. You can [color=#a4885c]wing it[/color] and see what happens.
  
If you'd like to be [color=#a4885c]methodical[/color], though, creating a character is easy to do one step at a time.

## Choosing a Species
Most species have minor differences, which you can read about under the [color=#a4885c]Species[/color] entry.
However, you may find that it's easier to make your first character as a human, moth, dwarf or reptilian.

This shouldn't discourage you from getting creative with your character, though.

This guide will assume you are creating a human, but the process is similar across all species.

## Minor Characteristics
These include:
- Age (18-29 for young, 30-59 for middle-aged, 60+ for old)
- Sex (your sprite, as seen by toggling "Show clothing")
- Pronouns (what the game will refer to you as)
- Skin color (may be a slider or RGB depending on species)
- Eye color (RGB)
- Hair color (RGB)

These are minor changes and have little effect on gameplay. This is what players will read when they [color=#a4885c]examine you[/color]. ("young man")

## Hair and Facial Hair
Again, you may be intimidated by the vast range of options. That's okay.

[color=#a4885c]Take your time with it.[/color] You can skim or click through each of the options and find which one you like.
Sometimes it's easier to set your desired hair color before looking at the options.

If you really can't decide, some popular haircut options include Floorlength Bedhead, Modern, Buisness, CIA or simply bald.
Alternatively, [color=#a4885c]randomize[/color] a separate character and see what kind of haircuts they're rocking with. Suprise yourself.

Don't feel obligated to use any of these, though.
  
## Markings
Markings range from [color=#a4885c]scars and snouts[/color] to [color=#a4885c]tattoos and tails[/color].
Think of them like [color=#a4885c]accessories[/color] that are a part of your body, for giving your character some extra flair and uniqueness. They cannot be changed during the round.

Some species have more marking options than others. Humans are more limited in terms of markings than moths or reptilians.

You can have a set number of markings in each '[color=#a4885c]category[/color]', as seen at the top. For example, reptilians can have one chest marking but two markings on the top of their heads.
These are [color=#a4885c]cosmetic[/color] and have no effect on gameplay.

## How to stand out
Memorable characters are usually remembered for their personality, their deeds and their [color=#a4885c]robustness[/color], but that doesn't mean you have to be some sort of hotshot.

Don't sweat having a big, flashy and memorable character. Make your own story that you'll be remembered for.
</Document>
