<Document>
  # Sentencing

  All sentencing is to be handled by the Warden, if no Warden is available the HoS is to take over that duty, if there's no HoS it falls onto the highest ranking command member.

  Use common sense and humanity when issuing punishments. You should not always seek out the highest punishment you can, you don't have to always give the maximum time or always look to demote someone. Always take in account the severity and only charge for what is needed for someone to learn their lesson.

  [color=#a4885c]Stackable Crimes:[/color] When working with confinement and extended confinement punishments, crimes are to be considered 'stackable' in the sense that if you charge someone with two or more different crimes, you should combine the times you would give them for each crime. Linked crimes, shown in matching colors on the Quick Crime Guide, can not be stacked and instead override each other, you should pick the highest crime that matches the case. Crimes are separate in the sense that you can charge for two or more counts of a crime if it is done to different departments/people, which would then allow you to stack the brig time for each count.

  [color=#a4885c]Repeaters:[/color] Repeated crimes are when someone is released for a crime and then goes to commit the same crime within the same shift. Repeated crimes can be charged with tacked-on time; first repeat: 3:00, second repeat: 6:00, third repeat: 9:00, fourth repeat: permanent confinement. The tacked-on time can extend over the normal confinement maximum time of 20 minutes without it being considered extended confinement. It should also be noted each tacked-on time is directly linked to one type of crime, so for say, if someone does their first repeat of trespass and petty theft, you can charge them with an extra 6 minutes.

  [color=#a4885c]Accessory, Attempting, And Intention:[/color] If someone intentionally, knowingly and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime they can be charged with the relevant crimes, such as an engineer giving someone tools, who says they are going to break into an area. Same goes for a clear and solid attempt at a crime, or a person who shows clear intent to act out a crime, such as a syndicate nuclear operative arming a nuke but getting arrested before it goes off, they can still be charged with terrorism. Does not apply to crimes that have an attempted listing already, like attempted murder.

  [color=#a4885c]Court:[/color] All major punishments can be fought against by the accused in a court case. While court isn't necessary to follow through with the punishment, every prisoner being subject to a major punishment MUST be told their right to a trial. The prisoner may request their case be heard in court at any point during their sentence and it must be fulfilled (as long as there is an able lawyer present on the crew). If the trial does not end in their favor, security may proceed with their punishment and the prisoner can not request a second court hearing. A court case additionally can be delayed and handled at CentCom if the evacuation shuttle is on route, this will not allow you to follow through with things like execution without a hearing.

  ## Normal Punishments

    - [color=#a4885c]Warning:[/color] For minor crimes, fix the issue then warn the person to not attempt the crime again, if they still proceed to do it at a later date, a brig time may be better.

    - [color=#a4885c]Confinement:[/color] The typical punishment, being confined in a cell for a temporary amount of time according to the crimes, not exceeding 20 minutes, unless dealing with repeated crimes.

    - [color=#a4885c]Demotion:[/color] Entails removing all departmental gear they have on their person and revoking the involved department access off their ID. This requires the captain's or involved department head's approval. Demotions should only be issued if the person pose a threat to their own department or are in a position where they have/can abuse their job's gear to commit further crimes.

  ## Major Punishments

    - [color=#a4885c]Extended Confinement:[/color] Being confined in the permanent brig for a temporary amount of time according to the crimes, exceeding 20 minutes. Max sentence is 45 minutes.

    - [color=#a4885c]Permanent Confinement:[/color] Being held in the permanent brig for the entire duration of the shift. Any persons subject to this punishment are required to be transported in cuffs to CentCom at the end of the shift. A permanent prisoner can not be deprived of anything covered by the section "Treatment Of Prisoners".

    - [color=#a4885c]Execution:[/color] A humane way of dealing with extremely unruly crewmates. A prisoner who has been given the death sentence may pick how they wish to be killed, common methods are firing line, lethal injection, exile, and high voltage electrocution. Another alternate method of "execution" is the process of placing a staff's mind into a borg, this is allowed so long as it is lawful. The remains are to be properly stored and transported to CentCom at the end of the shift. Execution can only be issued with the captain/acting captain's approval, if the HoS is acting captain or there is no acting captain, all heads of staff are to hold a vote on the matter.

</Document>
