<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 12 - Do not abandon your role
  Do not join the round as a role that you don't intend to play. Do not enable antagonist roles that you don't intend to play. Abandoning a role includes not completing tasks that the role is expected to do, in addition to things like leaving the game. Members of command should almost all stay on the station until the emergency shuttle arrives. Enforcement of this rule is more strict for command and antagonist roles, and less strict for less important roles like passengers.

  Violations of this rule typically result in temporary or indefinite role bans. We understand that you may need to leave round early or unexpectedly. If you are in an important role (which is relayed to you in chat upon receiving your role), you should notify command members or an admin via ahelp so that they know you are leaving. Space Station 14 is a game. Do not endanger the safety of yourself or others, and do not neglect important things to avoid leaving a round early, even if you have to leave immediately without notifying anyone. Role bans for disconnecting are typically only applied if there is a pattern, and are almost always temporary.

  "Antag rolling" refers to a player abandoning their role if they do not get an antagonist role.

  ## Examples
  Acceptable:
  - As an engineer, building a bar in maintenance while there is nothing important for engineering to do.
  - As the captain, having the chef teach you how to cook while there is nothing important needing your attention.
  - As a passenger, building a shuttle with materials given to you by cargo and engineering.
  - Taking a short break from your job at the bar.
  - Getting an antagonist role and doing the bare minimum needed to complete your objectives.
  - Getting an antagonist role and making a genuine effort to complete your objectives, but failing to complete any.
  - Getting an antagonist role and intentionally not doing any of your objectives, but creating a similar level of disruption that completing your objectives would create.

  Prohibited:
  - As an engineer, building a bar in maintenance while the station has no power.
  - As the captain, leaving the station to go on an expedition with the salvage team.
  - As an atmospherics technician, building a shuttle round start and never coming back to the station.
  - Spending your entire shift at the bar, even when there is work that needs to be done by your role.
  - Ghosting, suiciding, or leaving at the start of a round because you don't like the map or the players in your department.
  - Getting an antagonist role and not doing any antagonist activities.
  - Ghosting, suiciding, or leaving at the start of a round because you did not get an antagonist role.
  - Ghosting, suiciding, or getting yourself killed because nuclear operatives declared war, and you want to try to get an antagonist ghost role.
</Document>
