<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 9 - As an antagonist, do not cause excessive death, damage, or destruction beyond your objectives
  This rule is not intended to disallow reasonable steps taken to complete your objectives. As an antagonist, you can always kill in bona fide self defense. Taking steps to permanently round remove many people who are no longer an immediate threat to you is almost always excessive, even if it is done to prevent yourself from being discovered.

  This rule is not intended to disallow all antagonist activity unrelated to objectives. Antagonists may cause a level of disruption to the station that is proportional to their objectives, even if it is unrelated to their objectives. As an antagonist, killing a single person in a round is not on its own be a violation of this rule.

  ## Exemptions
  The "die a glorious death" objective allows antagonists to ignore this rule entirely.

  ## Examples
  Acceptable:
  - Permanently round removing people who you have the objective to kill.
  - Causing massive station damage and chaos as an antagonist with the "die a glorious death" objective.
  - Killing anyone you see as a nuclear operative.
  - Permanently round removing a single person so that you can impersonate them to make it easier for you to complete a steal objective.
  - Sabotaging station power 10 minutes into the round to try to get the shuttle called because you've completed all of your other objectives and have one to escape on the shuttle alive.
  - Sabotaging a department's power 10 minutes into the round to make a steal objective easier to accomplish.
  - Permanently round removing many people who have demonstrated a persistence and a capability to either kill you or interfere with the completion of your objectives.

  Prohibited:
  - As a traitor with 3 kill objectives, taking steps to permanently round remove many non-objective people who are no longer an immediate threat to you, even if it is done to prevent yourself from being discovered.
  - Setting up an electrified grille in maintenance and using it to kill anyone who walks into it with the hope that one of your objectives will be one of them.
  - Sabotaging power station-wide 10 minutes into the round to make a steal objective easier to accomplish.
</Document>
