<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Kira Gbedan <161087999+Verbalase@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 18 - Don't rush for or prepare equipment unrelated to your job. (Powergaming)
  Powergaming is readily defined as the prioritization of amassing mechanical advantages for yourself, to the detriment of the enjoyment of others or the creation of interesting RP situations, and is to be avoided in favor of methods that both encourage and promote the fun of all parties involved in interactions where such moderation is possible.

  Requesting job changes is not prohibited by this rule. This rule is loosened if the station is understaffed or if there is a significant threat to you.

  Antagonists are exempt from this rule entirely.

  If you start with the item, it is fine for you to keep. For example, the Janitor starting with galoshes bypasses this rule as it is actually needed for their job.
  
  Basic tools are explicitly not powergaming, but don't go hoarding them, and if you know there's already a couple of sets in your department you don't need more.

  The Server Staff retain the right to ask you to tone down what is perceived as being excessive powergaming that causes noticeable disruption to the rest of the playerbase.

  ## Examples
  Acceptable:
  - Grabbing a gun from the armory because there is a threat or the station is on red alert.
  - Grabbing cuffs for your disabler.
  - Collecting items from maintenance for your role, to build a rage cage, or to give to the clown as a peace offering.
  - Asking atmos for an air canister for a shuttle or so that it can be used for self-service jetpack/tank refills.
  - Making weapons to defend against a known significant threat.
  - Security asking the janitor for galoshes because they’ve been slipped a lot during the round.

  Prohibited:
  - Grabbing insulative gloves as a Medical Doctor for no real reason.
  - Grabbing a gun from the armory despite there being no current threat or reason.
  - Manufacturing weapons, bombs, or death poisons before you know of any reason you would need them.
  - Pre-emptively hide antagonist objectives or pre-emptively secure them with higher security then normally required.
  - Manufacturing or prepare things for the "end of the round" when the shuttle docks with Central Command.
  - As the Captain, giving the HoS your extra ID roundstart "For safekeeping" or "just in case"
  - Grabbing galoshes or magboots roundstart.
</Document>
