<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 11 - Follow reasonable escalation
  Antagonists are fully exempt from escalation rules. Non-antagonists who are in a conflict with antagonists are not exempt. Escalation should typically follow steps or a pattern of conflict types similar to:
  - Verbal
  - Non-harmful
  - Non-lethal
  - Lethal
  - Permanently lethal

  All new conflicts should start at the first step. A player should not escalate a conflict across steps without some escalation from the other party involved in the conflict. Players can skip steps to match the level of escalation that the other person is at, but should almost always not skip steps other than that. Players who attempt to deescalate conflicts will be given more leniency in escalating if the other party continues to escalate despite the attempt at de-escalation. You do not have to try to deescalate conflicts, but someone who watches you over the entire round, or over multiple rounds, should not feel that your goal is generally to escalate conflicts.

  Conflicts or escalation can be indirect. When someone steals someone else's ID, the theft is a direct part of the conflict, but if the victim becomes trapped as a result of not having their ID to open a door, that is also considered part of the conflict and escalation. Do not randomly steal IDs from people.

  Escalation does not have to be directed at a specific player to enter them into a conflict. Nuclear operatives who are trying to destroy the station are considered to be at the permanently lethal level of conflict with all crew on the station. Someone who kills a station pet has started some degree of conflict with all crewmembers. Someone who kills a mouse that a chef was caring for has started some degree of conflict with that chef.

  You will be considered to be violating this rule if you escalate a conflict based on a poor or unreasonable assumption.

  Conflicts should almost never reach the "permanently lethal" stage. Conflicts should only reach this stage if the other party brought it to the stage, or if the same conflict escalated to the lethal stage multiple times in the round.

  If a party in the conflict goes into crit or dies, the party responsible should take them to get treatment or to security. For the conflict, this should be considered saving someone from dying and should deescalate the conflict. If the conflict is deescalated in this way, both parties need to re-escalate to lethal for the conflict to return to that stage. If the conflict is not deescalated in this way, then only the party who defeated the other would need to re-escalate for the conflict to return to the lethal stage.

  Security can immediately escalate to non-lethal force if it is necessary to arrest someone.

  People using or brandishing Syndicate items can typically be presumed to have lethal intent. Someone with lethal intent can typically be immediately escalated against at a lethal level, a notable exception is if you have the tools to safely detain them.

  ## Escalation Involving Animals
  See [textlink="Escalation Involving Animals" link="RuleR11-1"].

  ## Exemptions
  Escalation rules aren't enforced against non-players, but players will be held responsible for rule violations even if they don't realize that a character or animal was controlled by another player. Characters who have purple text saying that they are catatonic are considered non-players. Characters who are disconnected are still considered players.

  ## MRP Amendment
  Escalation rules are enforced even against non-players.

  ## Examples of Conflict Types
  See [textlink="Examples of Conflict Types" link="RuleR11-2"].

  ## Example Scenarios
  These examples assume that you are not an antagonist.

  Acceptable:
  - A player starts punching you, so you start punching back until they stop. If they go into crit, you stop attacking them and take them to security or to get medical attention.
  - You make fun of a clown, who then throws a pie at you and steals your shoes. You slip the clown and steal their mask.
  - You are a security officer and tell someone to stop, so you can question them. They run away, so you use your disabler to stun and cuff them.
  - You are a security officer and see someone wearing a syndicate hardsuit, so you shoot them to crit, cuff them, then take them to security.
  - You are a crewmember and see a nuclear operative, so you kill them.
  - An unauthorized person enters a high risk area of the station, like the armory or atmospherics, so you attack them until they leave.
  - Minorly inconveniencing someone for your own benefit.
  - As an antagonist, killing someone who got in your way.
  - As an antagonist, killing someone who didn't give you what you want.
  - A chef and bartender reach the lethal level of conflict through appropriate escalation. The chef crits the bartender and does not take them to medbay or security. The bartender immediately tries to crit the chef next time they run into each other.
  - A chef and bartender reach the lethal level of conflict through appropriate escalation. The chef crits the bartender and does not take them to medbay or security. The chef insults the bartender next time they see them.

  Prohibited:
  - A player starts punching you, so you gib them.
  - A clown throws a pie at you and steals your shoes, so you stab them to crit with a screwdriver.
  - You are a security officer and tell someone to stop, so you can question them. They run away so you use a truncheon to beat them to crit.
  - An authorized person who you unreasonably or carelessly think is unauthorized enters a high risk area of the station, like the armory or atmospherics, so you attack them until they leave.
  - An unauthorized person enters a low risk area of the station, like cargo, and you start attacking them with no other escalation.
  - Slipping security all round because they are security.
  - Blocking the head of personnel in their office using walls because they didn't give you what you asked for.
  - Hiding someone's body because they punched you earlier in the round.
  - Harassing the bar or bartender by frequently coming in to break their glasses or furniture.
  - Randomly picking fights with people.
  - A chef and bartender reach the lethal level of conflict through appropriate escalation. The chef crits the bartender and does not take them to medbay or security. The chef immediately tries to crit the bartender next time they run into each other.
  - A chef and bartender reach the lethal level of conflict through appropriate escalation. The chef crits the bartender and takes them to the medbay or security. The bartender immediately tries to crit the chef next time they run into each other.
</Document>
