<Document>
# Roleplay Rule 4-2 - Metashield regarding antagonists

  ## Implanted Implants

  Implanted implants are shielded.

  Implanters themselves and un-implanted implants are not shielded. This prohibits implant checking.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - discovering a non-NT implanter, used or unused
  - discovering a non-NT implant box
  - discovering use of a non-NT implant by anyone
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Chameleon Items

  Chameleon items are shielded.

  Being suspicious of an item being fake or stolen is not shielded, but testing items or calling them chameleon is covered by this shield.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - seeing someone else cause any chameleon item to change
  - finding holographic nanomachine fibers
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Stealth Items

  The fact that an item can be something other than what its visual appearance and examine description indicate is shielded.

  This shield protects stealth items, including protecting them from being tested.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - seeing the item behave differently than the expected behavior for the item
  - seeing the item used for its hidden purpose
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Traitor

  The existence of Syndicate operatives who infiltrate and sabotage the station is not shielded.

  ## Thief

  The existence of kleptomaniacs who steal anything that is not bolted down is not shielded.

  ## Ninja

  The existence of Ninjas and the Spider Clan beyond being a pop culture mainstay is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - the Ninja is witnessed cloaking, uncloaking or teleporting. A currently cloaked Ninja does not count.

  ## Changeling

  The existence of cannibal shapeshifters being real is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - you are the Research Director or Chief Medical Officer
  - you witness the Changeling eat or shapeshift
  - the Changeling assaults you using its abilities and you survive

  The unique quality of Changeling blood to react violently in a centrifuge is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Research Director or Chief Medical Officer

  The ability to prevent the revival of a Changeling by cremating them is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Research Director or Chief Medical Officer
  - you have witnessed the successful cremation of a Changeling

  ## Revolutionaries

  The existence of union organizers and prospective mutineers is not shielded. The concept of a Syndicate-backed mutiny is also not shielded.

  The ability to use a flash to "convert" someone to the revolution is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you witness a conversion
  - the revolution reveals itself

  ## Nuclear Operatives

  The existence of Nuclear Operatives beyond a myth that no one would act on is shielded.

  The fact that the nuke disk must be protected and could be used by a bad actor to try to destroy the station is not shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - discovering a blood red hardsuit
  - discovering a nuclear operative's shuttle
  - a War Ops announcement
  - being a nuclear operative
</Document>
