<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 basic pack <159909786+packmore@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 19 - Do not avoid your job or ignore roleplay to PvP (Validhunting)
  This rule is intended to fill holes and alleviate confusion when it comes to rulings of escalation and ignoring ones job to persue PvP (player vs player) engagements. 

  Crew members should generally avoid 'validhunting' - 'witch hunts' intended to kill or incapacitate antagonists - unless they are members of the security team.

  A normal individual on a space station would not immediately abandon their duties, pick up a toolbox, and attempt to kill someone reported to have dangerous Syndicate weaponry.

  A normal individual would not immediately attempt to murder someone for having non-lethal contraband equipment. 

  Individuals actively attempting to pick lethal engagements with crew as a non-antag are generally unaccepted. Non-lethal fights, social fights, and duels agreed upon by both parties after significant roleplay are acceptable.

  Crew members engaging in powergaming (intentionally acquiring weaponry in a scenario where doing so is irrelevant to your department or the current station's situation) will be judged unfavorably when dealing with reports of validhunting.

  Threats that actively endanger the station as a whole, and threats that immediately endanger you or an individual you are aware of and are within immediate reach, are exempt from this. 

  This rule does not impede reasonable escalation from the security team attempting to enforce Space Law.

  ## Examples
  Acceptable: 
  - Getting into a boxing match in an arena specifically designed for it.
  - Getting into a boxing match or fist fight with an individual who you have had in-character issues or frustrations with over the course of the round.
  - Calling security on a suspicious or clearly dangerous individual within your department, and then proceeding to defend yourself when they attack you.
  - Hitting somebody with "warning attacks" when they are doing something illegal to prevent them from completing the illegal action.
  - Non-lethally attacking an individual who is actively attempting to force their way into a secure location.
  - Attacking an individual that you see is attempting to gib a crew member.

  Prohibited:
  - Actively harassing crew members, such as the security team, in the hopes that they will attack first, without a roleplay reason.
  - As a security officer, intentionally harassing or forcing individuals into comitting crimes with the intention of fighting or arresting them after.
  - Randomly attacking individuals in the hopes that they will reciprocate and attack you back.
  - Attempting to get into in-character or 'social' fights that actively impede an individual and their ability to defend themselves during high-stress situations, such as in the case of nuclear operatives.
  - Attempting to attack or incapacitate individuals with contraband that pose no immediate threat to you, as a non security officer.
  - Acquiring weaponry throughout the round, and immediately leaving your department or job to attempt to use such equipment on antagonists reported over the radio who do are not immediate threats to the station.
</Document>
