<Document>
  # Head of Personnel
  Well, well, well. If it isn't the one, the only, Head of Paperwork. Get your gloves on, rookie. The request forms won't write themselves.

  The Head of Personnel is the head of the Service department as well as the manager of all the IDs on the station.
  Your duties include overseeing your chefs, bartenders and botanists as well as coordinating between the other departments and having them get along.

  But most importantly-- [color=cyan]you change IDs[/color].

  ## Changing IDs
  To get started, you need your own ID, someone else's ID and an [color=cyan]ID card computer[/color].
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HoPIDCard" Caption="your ID card"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PassengerIDCard" Caption="someone else's ID card"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerId"/>
  </Box>

  Now, follow these steps.
  - Insert the [bold]Privileged ID[/bold]. This is the card that has the ability to modify other cards.
  - Then insert the [bold]Target ID[/bold]. This is the card you're modifying.
  - Choose a [bold]preset[/bold]. This will change the person's [bold]job icon[/bold] that will show up on secHUDs and the crew manifest.
  - If necessary, add or take away additional accesses.
  - Take out the IDs and make sure you don't accidentally hand someone else your own ID!

  ## Allowing Access
  You [italic]could[/italic] give away acceesses willy-nilly, but your fellow department heads may not appreciate fresh faces walking into their departments without their permission.

  Before assigning a job, at the bare minimum [color=cyan]notify[/color] the department head so that everyone is on the same page.
  Ideally, you should ask them over [bold]radio[/bold] if they approve or send them a letter for them to [bold]stamp[/bold].

  How stringent your policy is up to you, but remember that some accesses could be [color=cyan]detrimental[/color] to the station should they fall into the wrong hands! This is why HoPs will often make job request forms for record-keeping.

  [italic]Tips for formatting your document can be found [textlink="here" link="Writing"].[/italic]

  Also check the wiki for additional tips and [color=cyan]templates[/color] that you can use.

  ## Replacing Lost Equipment
  Some poor shmuck came to your office without a PDA or a headset. Would hate to be that guy!

  Thankfully, you can replace his lost devices using the [color=cyan]PTech[/color] in your office.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VendingMachineCart"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PassengerIDCard" Caption="ID card"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetGrey" Caption="headset"/>
  </Box>

  If you're replacing their radio, you may need to give them spare encryption keys. These are also found in your PTech.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyMedical" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyEngineering" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeySecurity" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [italic]An explanation on the radio and encryption keys can be found [textlink="here" link="Radio"].[/italic]
 
  ## Access Types
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockCommand" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HighSecDoor" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Command[/bold] gives access to the bridge and the vault, but not department head rooms.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockSecurity" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Brig[/bold] gives access to security's lobby. [bold]Security[/bold] gives access to security's equipment, excluding the [bold]Armory[/bold].
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockServiceLocked" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Service[/bold] allows access into general service areas, but not specific service rooms as they have their own accesses, like the [bold]Bar[/bold].
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockScience" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Research[/bold] allows into science and robotics. The R&D server is usually locked behind a [bold]Research Director[/bold] airlock.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockMedical" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Medical[/bold] does not allow access into [bold]Cryogenics[/bold] or [bold]Chemistry[/bold], as they have their own accesses.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockEngineering" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockAtmospherics" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Engineering[/bold] does not allow access into [bold]Atmospherics[/bold] or outside the station, as they have their own accesses.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockCargo" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Cargo[/bold] does not allow access into Salvage, as it has its own access.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockMaint" Caption=""/>
    [bold]Maintenance[/bold] allows access into the maintenance shafts but not the substation rooms.
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirlockExternal" Caption=""/>
    [bold]External[/bold] access allows people to leave the station, either for a spacewalk or a one-way trip.
  </Box>
</Document>
