<Document>
  # General Info
  General info every security member should know and understand.

  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BannerSecurity" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageSecurityOfficer" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageHeadOfSecurity" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageSecurityOfficer" Caption=""/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BannerSecurity" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
## General info
  1. Confiscated items must be placed in [bold][color=#fcdf03]evidence[/color][/bold], not left on the brig floor or your personal use, until they can be returned to their rightful owners.
  
  2. [bold][color=#a83232]Security[/color][/bold] is prohibited from using [bold][color=#fcdf03]most[/color][/bold] Syndicate contraband. [color=#a4885c]See Security Policies section for further info.[/color]
  
  3. Intent is important in determining the level of some crimes. If intent can’t be determined, the lesser charge should be given.
  
  4. Criminals who commit multiple crimes may have charges stacked. The sentences for multiple crimes should run consecutively, not concurrently.
  
  - Charges in the same row should not be stacked for the same count; instead, charge the crew member with the highest applicable offense per count.
  
  5. If a crew member is de-converted from revolutionary or cult groups, all charges related to their time in the organization should be dropped, and they should be given a mindshield (if possible).
  
  6. The warden is responsible for ensuring that all prisoners are safe and that the brig is secure. Failure to do this can result in demotion.
  
  7. A crew member cannot be held for more than 10 minutes without being processed. If 10 minutes elapses and no evidence is provided, the crew member should be set free.

## Arresting a Head of Staff
  
  1. Warrants for heads of staff must be approved by the Head of Security, Captain, or CentCom.
  
  2. Warrants for the Captain must be approved by CentCom.
  
  3. Demotion of a command member and promotion of acting command must be approved by the Captain.
  
  It can safely be assumed that a head of staff is threatening to arrest. Bring backup.

</Document>
