<Document>
  # Security Policies and Practices
  This section of Space Law is to help guide members of Security on the proper procedures when on active duty. This includes the usage of lethal force, legal representation and trials, and additional information regarding contraband.

## Legal Representation and Trials
  Prisoners are permitted to seek legal representation; however, you are under no obligation to provide or allow this. Lawyers, and by extension the Head of Personnel, exist to serve as a guiding hand and the voice of reason within the judicial process, but they have zero authority over the brig, security personnel, prisoners, or sentencing. 
  
  The lawyer's security headset is a privilege not a right. Security personnel are under no requirement to listen to them, and security channel abuse is to result in that privilege being revoked. If the lawyer continuously acts as a disruptive influence, Security personnel are fully permitted to confiscate their access, remove them from the brig and bar their future access to it.
  
  In instances where a conflict of opinion arises over the sentence of a prisoner the chain of command must be followed. This goes, from top to bottom: Captain > Head of Security > Warden > Sec Officer.
  
  Trials are not to be performed for timed sentences. This is mainly for the benefit of the accused as trials will often run many times the length of the actual sentence.

  Trials may be performed for capital crimes and permanent detention; however, there is no requirement to hold them. Forensic evidence, witness testimony, or confessions are all that is required for the Head of Security, Warden, or Captain to authorize their sentence.
  
  In cases where the death penalty is desired but the Captain (or Acting Captain) is unable or unwilling to authorize the execution, a trial is required to authorize the death penalty.
  
## Use of Deadly Force
  As a member of the station's Security force, you are trained for and equipped with the latest in non-lethal weaponry and techniques. However, while you are expected to use those techniques whenever possible, a few cases will usually force you to use lethal weaponry. Usually obtained from the Armory with authorization of the Warden or Head of Security.
  
  It is for this reason that the situations that warrant the use of Deadly Force are few and far between. In most circumstances you will be expected to use your stun weapons to diffuse a situation.
  
  There are a few circumstances where deadly force is permissible:

 [color=#ff0000][bold]Dangerous Enemies of the Corporation :[/bold][/color]
  - [bold]Terminators, Nuclear Operatives[/bold] and [bold]Ninjas[/bold] fall under this category. Even if unarmed they are always considered able and willing to use lethal force. It's more than justified to kill them on sight as attempting to subdue and arrest would pose a severe risk. Note that confirmation of their status is critical, killing someone over suspicion of them being a Head Revolutionary will get you in trouble quickly.

 [color=#ff0000][bold]Code Red Situation[/bold][/color]

  - Situations which would warrant a code red, such as: full blown mutinies, hostile boarding parties, and imminent destruction of the station automatically authorize lethal force. Note: The alert status is not required to be elevated to code red as in most of these scenarios the chain of command will be too damaged or otherwise occupied to raise the alert level.
  
 [color=#ff0000][bold]Non-Lethal Weapons Ineffective[/bold][/color]
  - Certain targets are impervious to non-lethal weapons, such as mechs, borgs and terminators. Lethal force may be used against these targets if they prove hostile until they are incapacitated. Victims should either be revived or the execution should be posthumously approved by the captain.

 [color=#ff0000][bold]Severe Personal Risk[/bold][/color]
  - Sometimes getting close enough to a target to slap the cuffs on will create significant personal risk to the officer. Deadly force from range is recommended to subdue hostile terminators and ninjas.

 [color=#ff0000][bold]Armed and Dangerous[/bold][/color]
  - If the criminal is in possession of dangerous melee weapons, stun weaponry or lethal weaponry and you suspect they are going to use them against you lethal force is permitted. Hostile Traitors and Nuclear Operatives fall under this category. Stun weaponry in the hands of someone whose intention is hostile is considered lethal. [color=#ff0000]Unauthorized personnel in the armory are considered to be armed and dangerous by default. Maximum force is permitted to subdue such targets.[/color]
  
 [color=#ff0000][bold]Multiple Hostiles[/bold][/color]
  - It can be extremely dangerous and difficult to arrest multiple hostiles such as Revolutionaries. If you are being mobbed and stun weaponry isn't helping then you are allowed to use your weaponry in a harmful manner to thin the crowd. This should be done if you are alone dealing with this issue but backup or outright retreating is always preferable. [color=#a4885c]Prison Breaks fit in this category as well, especially if the prisoners possess Security gear for a reason or another.[/color]

In general, if it is possible to capture personnel non-lethally you should. If you do not, expect to have to justify yourself to Internal Affairs to not get fired and to CentCom to not be banned from your job position.

## Contraband Containment and Usage Guidelines
  As a member of the station's security force, you are expected to refrain from using contraband or risk job termination.
  
  Only exception to this is as a security officer, with direct permission from the Head of Security and [bold]only[/bold] the Head of Security, they have the clearance to allow usage of such contraband if deemed appropriate. However, if said officer misuses the contraband. Any and all crimes will be attached not only to the officer, but to the Head of Security as well.
  
  Contraband List
  
  - [color=#ff0000]Unauthorized Higher Clearance items[/color]
  
  Note: With Science making RCDs or Cargo purchasing weapons or Engineers looting board rooms. They might be able to get this equipment with their access, so it is not Theft, but they aren't authorized to own it especially without a good reason.
  - [color=#ff0000]Syndicate Tech[/color]
  ex: cryptographic sequencer, syndicate encryption key, agent ID, hypopen
  - [color=#ff0000]Modified or Illegal weaponry[/color]
  ex: Silencers, Armor-Piercement, Full-Auto Weaponry, Explosives
  - [color=#ff0000]Illicit and Hallucinogenic Drugs[/color]
  ex: Stimulants, Space Drugs, Desoxyephedrine, Nocturine
  - [color=#ff0000]Makeshift Weapons[/color]
  ex: stun prods, stun gloves, cable restraints
</Document>
