<Document>   
# Space Law 

This is just a guideline and you aren't forced to follow it to the letter, but if you don't you should expect certain boys-in-red to come at you with cuffs and a stun-baton (hopefully) on.

Within [bold][color=#313dc4]NanoTrasen[/color][/bold], stations operate under [bold][color=#a83232]Space Law[/color][/bold]. [color=#fcdf03]All persons aboard the station are beholden to this law and expected to follow it.[/color]

<Box> 
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookSpaceLaw" Caption="Book of Space Law"/> 
</Box> 
## Accessory and Enemy of the NanoTrasen

[color=#fcdf03]Accessory:[/color]
- Accessory charges can be given to anyone who assists a criminal in committing a crime or escaping from security. The sentence for accessory charges can be the same as the original criminal up to and including execution, though the HoS and Warden are allowed to give a lesser charge. Intent or knowledge of the original crime is not needed.

[color=#a83232]Enemy of the NanoTrasen:[/color]
- Current enemies of Nanotrasen currently include: The Syndicate, Susnet, the Spider Clan, and Revolutionaries. Deconversion should always be the top priority whenever possible. Execution of revolutionaries is only authorized when deconversion is not possible or poses too significant of a risk. For enemies of the corporation who pose too great a threat to detain, immediate execution is authorized.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageNukie" State="nukie" Caption="Syndicate"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageTerminator" State="terminator" Caption="Terminator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageSpaceNinja" State="spaceninja" Caption="Space Ninja"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookImageRevolutionary" State="revolutionary" Caption="Revolutionary"/>
</Box>

## Crimes and Sentencing
[bold][color=#6cac4c]Infraction - 1XX 
(3 min Brig/150 spesos)[/color][/bold]

[color=#b8d4ac]XX1 - Physical harassment:[/color]
- Repeatedly making unwanted, non-harmful physical contact with another person (e.g. shoving, pulling, grabbing).

[color=#b8d4ac]XX3 - Possession, drugs:[/color]
- Drug possession is the crime of having one or more illegal drugs in one's possession for personal use.

[color=#b8d4ac]XX4 - Vandalism:[/color]
- Vandalism is the action involving deliberate destruction of or damage to the station or private property. The term includes property damage, such as graffiti and defacement directed towards any property without permission of the owner.

[color=#b8d4ac]XX6 - Workplace hazard:[/color]
- To endanger the crew or station through negligent or irresponsible, but not deliberately malicious, actions.

[color=#b8d4ac]XX7 - Trespass:[/color]
- Being in an area which one does not have access to.

[color=#b8d4ac]XX9 - Obstruction of justice:[/color]
- An act that corruptly or by threats or force, or by any threatening letter or communication, influences, obstructs, or impedes, or endeavors to influence, obstruct, or impede, the due administration of justice.

[color=#b8d4ac]X10 - Insubordination[/color]
- The act of willfully disobeying an order of one's superior, security, or others in authority during station emergencies. Refusing to perform an action that is unethical or illegal is not insubordination, nor is refusing to perform an action that is not within the scope of authority of the person issuing the order.

[color=#b8d4ac]X11 - Hooliganism:[/color]
- To intentionally and maliciously engage in disruptive conduct, where one refuses to cease.

[color=#b8d4ac]X13 - Accessory[/color]

[bold][color=#407cdc]Misdemeanor - 2XX (5 min Brig/250 spesos)[/color][/bold]

[color=#a8c4f4]XX1 - Assault:[/color]
- The act of inflicting physical harm upon a person or a threat or attempt to commit such an action. (This charge cannot be stacked with Assault, Officer for the same incident)

[color=#a8c4f4]XX3 - Distribution, drugs:[/color]
- Selling, transporting, or illegally importing unlawful controlled substances. (This charge cannot be stacked with Possession, Drugs)

[color=#a8c4f4]XX4 - Property Destruction:[/color]
- Intentionally destroying station property or non-essential equipment without the severity required for sabotage charges.

[color=#a8c4f4]XX5 - Petty theft:[/color]
- The crime of stealing something that does not have a high value. Each count after the original should be given an additional 1.5 minutes.

[color=#a8c4f4]XX6 - Gross negligence:[/color]
- Recklessly acting without reasonable caution and putting another person at risk of injury or death. (or failing to do something with the same consequences)

[color=#a8c4f4]XX7 - Restricted trespass:[/color]
- Trespassing into a restricted area without using force.

[color=#a8c4f4]XX8 - Breaking and entering:[/color]
- The act of entering a location without legitimate access or authorization through the slightest amount of force (even crowbarring open a non-powered door).

[color=#a8c4f4]XX9 - Resisting arrest, non-violent:[/color]
- Resisting arrest occurs when a person interferes with law enforcement’s attempt to perform a lawful arrest by non violent means.

[color=#a8c4f4]X10 - Dereliction:[/color]
- Abandoning essential job duties as a non-command crew member.

[color=#a8c4f4]X13 - Accessory[/color]

[bold][color=#e8943c]Felony-Misdemeanor - 3XX (7 min Brig/350 spesos)[/color][/bold]

[color=#ffcc9c]XX1 - Assault, deadly weapon:[/color]
- The act of attacking a non-command or security crew member with an item in a way that could result in death. Stamina damage should not be considered for this. 

[color=#ffcc9c]XX2 - Assault, Officer:[/color]
- The act of inflicting physical harm upon a security officer or command member. Note: This charge cannot be stacked with assault for the same incident.

[color=#ffcc9c]XX3 - Possession, weapons:[/color]
- The unlawful possession of a weapon by an individual. This includes explosives.

[color=#ffcc9c]XX4 - Animal Cruelty:[/color]
- To inflict unnecessary suffering on a pet or sapient animal with malicious intent.

[color=#ffcc9c]XX5 - Theft:[/color]
- The trespassory taking and carrying away of goods from the possession of another person or department with intent to steal.

[color=#ffcc9c]XX6 - Manslaughter:[/color]
- An unlawful killing that doesn't involve malice aforethought—intent to seriously harm or kill, or extreme, reckless disregard for life.

[color=#ffcc9c]XX8 - Breaking and entering restricted:[/color]
- The act of entering a role or job restricted location or other enclosed property through the slightest amount of force (even crowbarring open a non-powered door), without authorization. This would include, but is not limited to: Bridge, Head’s Office, Armory, Secure Tech Storage, EVA, AI Sat/upload.

[color=#ffcc9c]X11 - Illegal ID modification:[/color]
- Modifying an ID card or access permissions without sufficient reason, authority, or access.

[color=#ffcc9c]X13 - Accessory[/color]

[bold][color=#d00404]Felony - 4XX (Perma)[/color][/bold]

[color=#e86464]XX1 - Attempted Murder:[/color]
- The incomplete or unsuccessful act of killing someone.

[color=#e86464]XX2 - Assault of an officer with a weapon:[/color]
- Assaulting a member of security or command with an item in a way that could result in death (but doesn't). Stamina damage should not be considered for this.

[color=#e86464]XX3 - Possession, Syndicate Contraband:[/color]
- Having any Syndicate equipment (both weapons and other items) in one's posession.

[color=#e86464]XX4 - Sabotage:[/color]
- Significantly destroying, damaging, or defectively producing property with the specific intent to impede the station's ability to operate. 

[color=#e86464]XX5 - Kidnapping:[/color]
- The unlawful transportation, asportation and confinement of a person against their will.

[color=#e86464]XX9 - Rioting:[/color]
- Rioting is a violent offense against public order involving multiple people. A riot involves a gathering of persons for an illegal purpose

[color=#e86464]X10 - Dereliction of command:[/color]
- An individual in a command role failing to fulfil the duties laid out in their role description. This includes leaving the station without authorization from Central Command.

[color=#e86464]X11 - Illegal AI Modification:[/color]
- Modifying the laws of the station's silicons without reason, authority or access. The uploader of the law is held accountable for any crimes the AI commits while under the law set. If the laws are potentially harmful, replace this sentence with grand sabotage.

[color=#907cc4]X12 - Confirmed enemy of the corp[/color]

[color=#e86464]X13 - Accessory[/color]

[bold][color=#686464]Capital - 5XX (Execution, Force borg, Exile, Perma)[/color][/bold]

[color=#b8b4b4]XX1 - Murder:[/color]
- The act of killing someone.

[color=#b8b4b4]XX2 - Terrorism:[/color]
- To commit an act with the intent to cause injury or death, or to take hostages, in order to provoke a state of terror in, intimidate, or compel a group of crew members to do or to abstain from doing any act.

[color=#b8b4b4]XX4 - Grand Sabotage:[/color]
- Any act that results in extremely dangerous station damage or loss of life. Releasing damaging/lethal viruses, hotwiring the engine, disabling the gravity generator, disabling power for a department or equivalently large portion of the station, giving the AI dangerous laws, destroying the AI, opening several holes in the station hull, setting fire to large areas, detonating multiple cyborgs, and activating high-yield explosives all count as Grand Sabotage.

[color=#b8b4b4]XX5 - Grand theft:[/color]
- To unlawfully take highly restricted, dangerous, valuable, or highly sensitive property or items without consent.

[color=#b8b4b4]XX9 - Inciting a Riot:[/color]
- Inciting a Riot is when a person urges others to engage in tumultuous and violent conduct of a kind likely to create public alarm. A riot involves a gathering of persons for an illegal purpose.

[color=#907cc4]X12 - Confirmed enemy of the corp[/color]

[color=#b8b4b4]X13 - Accessory[/color]

</Document> 
