<Document>
  # Arachnids

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobArachnid" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  ## Extra Arms
  Arachnids can use their vestigial back-limbs to carry more items at one time than other species. [color=#1e90ff]This means they have two extra "Pocket" slots.[/color]
  
  ## Dietary Restrictions
  Their species has developed strong stomach enzymes capable of breaking down uncooked proteins more efficiently, [color=#1e90ff]enabling them to eat raw meat without experiencing any ill effects.[/color] However, this adaptation has rendered their stomachs more sensitive to certain alkaline chemicals, [color=#ffa500]causing foods which contain theobromine (like chocolate and onions) to be poisonous to them.[/color]
  
  ## Damage
  Like most invertebrates, Arachnids breathe through many spiracles, or small holes, distributed across the surface of their body. As a result, [color=#ffa500]they suffocate 50% faster than other species.[/color]
  
  Similar in composition to the haemolymph used by Earth's arthropods, Arachnid blood uses a copper-based respiratory protein. This means [color=#ffa500]they cannot metabolize more blood from iron, and must instead use copper.[/color]
  
  Arachnids' stiff exoskeleton makes punching difficult, so [color=#1e90ff]their unarmed attacks are instead bites, which do piercing damage.[/color]

  ## Sericulture

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialWebSilk" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingUniformJumpskirtWeb" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WebShield" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallWeb" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Arachnids can utilize their spinnerettes to [color=#1e90ff]create Websilk at the cost of hunger.[/color] Using their auxilliary limbs, they can shape this websilk into various commodities, including clothes, armor, and even entire structures.

  ## Arachnid Naming Conventions

  Arachnids typically use names derived from the Latin scientific names of real-world invertebrate species.
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Argyroneta Reticulatus
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Loxosceles Domesticus
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Trombicula Doremi
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Pieza Deresistans
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Spider-Man
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry
</Document>
