<Document>
  # Diona

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiona" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Diona are a remarkable species, one of only a handful of sentient creatures known to have evolved from plants. Their woody roots allow them to [color=#1e90ff]ignore difficult terrain such as Kudzu,[/color] but [color=#ffa500]cannot fit into shoes made for other humanoids.[/color]

  ## Damage
  Rather than having a normal humanoid circulatory system, Diona use capillary action to pump nutrient-carrying sap throughout their bodies, [color=#ffa500]which cannot be metabolized from iron.[/color]
  As their metabolism is very similar to that of Earth plants, chemicals designed to affect the growth and function of other plants have similar effects on Diona. For example, [color=#ffa500]Weed Killer is poisonous to them,[/color] but [color=#1e90ff]Robust Harvest can be used to accelerate their healing [color=#ffa500](At risk of overdose, as explained in the section below.)[/color]

  Due to their stiff, woody exterior, they take [color=#1e90ff]30% less Blunt damage and 20% less Slash damage[/color] but [color=#ffa500]50% more Heat damage, 20% more Shock damage, and they can easily catch on fire when receiving enough Heat damage from *any* source.[/color]

  ## Overdose
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloraTree06" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Being exposed to large quantities of Robust Harvest may [color=#ffa500]cause a Diona to grow out of control,[/color] rooting them in place in a sessile, tree-like form. [color=#1e90ff]This change can be reversed by severing the trunk from its root system.[/color]

  ## Diona Nymphs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A Diona's internal organs are sometimes capable of independence after the death of the main body. [color=#1e90ff]These organs, if voluntarily expelled, will metamorphose into Nymphs, or larval Diona.[/color] Nymphs are capable of speech, but not much else.

  After around ten minutes, a Nymph may undergo a second metamorphosis, [color=#1e90ff]reforming into an adult Diona.[/color] This new Diona will be [color=#ffa500]a new individual, with their own appearance, name, and personality,[/color] but may [color=#1e90ff]retain memories of who they were previously.[/color]

  ## Mycorrhizal Gestalt

  The minds of all Diona (and Nymphs) are subtly connected through a Mycorrhizal Gestalt. They can [color=#1e90ff]silently broadcast information to other Diona[/color] at any time, although they [color=#ffa500]cannot distinguish identity over the connection.[/color] This ability may prove useful when traditional communication methods fail.
  The default radio key for the Gestalt is +m.

  ## Diona Naming Conventions

  Diona typically have qualia names: abstract phrases describing subjective experiences.
  Diona names tend to evoke nature, but this is not required.
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] The Petal of Tranquility
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] The Garden of Relaxation
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] The Taste of Cigarettes
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Tree but Alive
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] The Inspection of Passports
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry
</Document>
