<Document>
  # Resomi

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobResomi" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Warning! This species is not recommended for new players due to major gameplay changes![/color]

  small, upright, raptor-like creatures with four ears.
  Their thin tail is still strong enough to pull things without needing their hands for assistance.

  ## Sounds
  Resomi make sounds akin to common bird noises found on Earth, such as chirping and squawking.

  ## Nexus Technological Hivemind
  Due to a implant that all Resomi are given at birth, they have a neural connection to the Nexus.
  This allows them to communicate with others of their species over a technological network.
  Use the [color=orange]+n[/color] prefix in chat to send a message to all Resomi anonymously.

  ## Age and names
  Resomi are hatched from eggs, and enter eligibility for CC and NT employment at the age of [color=yellow]23[/color] standard galactic years.  
  Resomi can live up to [color=yellow]430[/color] years old.
  Their names are usually nicknames as most other species have trouble pronouncing their native names.
  Resomi station identities will list their nickname first, followed by their pack name. For example, [color=yellow]Tashira, Darkfeathers Pack[/color].
  Some Resomi forego this system and go by other nicknames or names.

  ## Nightvision
  Resomi have a innate nightvision given to them by their eyes.
  This allows them to see in pure darkness farther than any normal handheld lightsource would provide.
  They will have normal vision when wearing any equipment that provides flash immunity.
  Using HUD variants allows you to keep your innate vision, at the cost of losing flash immunity.
  You can configure if you start with glasses or HUD in the loadouts for all relevant roles.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesSecurity" Scale="5" Caption="Security Glasses\nNo Nightvision\nHas flash immunity"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesHudSecurity" Scale="5" Caption="Security Hud\nNightvision\nNo flash immunity"/>
  </Box>
  ## Flash Duration
  Due to their eyes being more sensitive to light, Resomi will be stunned for a longer duration when flashed.
  Flashes will take [color=yellow]2[/color] times as long as normal for other species, lasting up to [color=#ffa500]10[/color] seconds in the case of a localized flash.
  
  ## Health
  Resomi have lower health due to their small stature, falling into a critical state at [color=#ffa500]85[/color] points of damage and dying at [color=#ffa500]170[/color] points of damage.
  Resomi also prefer colder temperatures compared to humans, being roughly akin to Moths.
  Resomi heal airloss from [color=cyan]Ammonia[/color] and [color=cyan]Amoxla[/color], 
  but [color=red]Saline[/color], [color=red]Dex[/color], and [color=red]Dex+[/color] are lethal to them. Remember to remind doctors about this!
  
  ## Claw attack
  Resomi are able to slash at others with their claws.
  These attacks deal [color=red]5[/color] points of Slash damage with a hit rate that is the same as humans fists attack.
  
  ## Weapon Knockback
  Resomi are very lightweight, and as such take so much knockback from large caliber weapons that they get pushed around.
  Resomi also will receive [color=yellow]Stun Damage[/color] from large caliber weapons for each shot.
  In general, the weapons that will give you knockback are [color=yellow]Rifles, Sniper Rifles, Shotguns, LMGs, HMGs, and Grenade Launchers.[/color]
  Look out especially on Rocket launchers, as since they are recoil-less, you will actually get [color=red]pulled forward with the rocket[/color] for a short distance.
  The safest weapons to use that will give you no knockback are [color=green]Pistols and SMGs[/color].
  No slips can help mitigate some of the knockback from firing weapons, but not all of it!
  Also keep in mind that any stamina resistance you have DOES work to reduce the stamina damage from these weapons.

  ## Jumping
  Resomi are able to jump, allowing them to move around station hallways quickly, and to jump ahead of others in a chase.
  This ability has a cooldown of [color=yellow]30[/color] seconds between uses.
  If the Resomi is dragging anything and trys to jump, the object will hold them back accordingly, leading to most of the time the Resomi jumping in place.
</Document>
