<Document>
  # Slime People

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobSlimePerson" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Though commonly thought to be distantly related to Slimes, Slime People share little in common with their potential genetic cousins. Their single-celled bodies are far more complex and mutable, and they tend to retain their shape throughout most of their lifecycle.

  ## Biological Oddities

  Their bodies are incapable of what we might call "normal" cellular respiration using oxygen, [color=#ffa500]instead relying on a constant supply of nitrogen gas, which is exhaled as nitrous oxide.[/color] Nitrogen is of course abundant in NT standard atmospheres, so this is usually not a problem for them.

  Due to their lack of "normal" respiration, Slime People are uniquely adapted for EVA (Extra-Vehicular Activity,) or "space-walks," because [color=#1e90ff]they suffocate 80% slower than other humanoids.[/color] They must be careful not to recieve direct exposure to the vacuum of space, however, as they [color=#ffa500]take damage from pressure 9% faster.[/color]

  Uniquely among NT-accepted species, Slime People possess only two organs - a set of gas sacs, which handle respiration, and a Core, similar to the nucleus of a cell, which handles everything else. Unlike most other species' metabolizing organs, [color=#1e90ff]the Core is capable of processing up to six reagents at a time,[/color] instead of two.

  ## Internal Storage

  As Slime People are largely composed of soft, mutable cytoplasm, they are [color=#1e90ff]capable of storing several small items within their body.[/color] This is a common vector for [color=red]contraband,[/color] but [color=#ffa500]is easily searchable, and Slime People do not typically notice when someone is poking around in there.[/color]

  ## Damage

  As they possess a very simple bodyplan, Slime People take [color=#1e90ff]80% less Cellular damage, 40% less Blunt damage and 20% less Poison damage,[/color] but their thin outer membrane is relatively fragile, which causes them to take [color=#ffa500]50% more Cold damage, 20% more Slash damage and 20% more Piercing damage[/color].

  The outer membrane is adapted to allow for rapid osmosis, which unfortunately results in [color=#ffa500]minor damage when splashed or sprayed with water.[/color] Their body still requires it for hydration, however, so their primary oriface has a much thicker membrane, allowing them to ingest water safely.

  Their cytoplasm, colloquially referred to as "slime blood," [color=#ffa500]cannot be regenerated using iron or copper.[/color] It is considered a delicacy by some, although NT policy forbids drinking the blood of one's coworkers under most circumstances.

  Slime People have the ability to harden portions of their body for short bursts, meaning [color=#1e90ff]their unarmed attacks deal slightly more Blunt damage than those of other humanoids.[/color]

  ## Slime Person Naming Conventions

  Slimes typically use the Human naming convention, but frequently have less plausible names than most Humans, and often include onomatopoeia. Last names are optional.
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Foolp Suub
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Foolp
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Andie Fizt
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Flanna Gleef
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Slime
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry
</Document>
