<Document>
  # Vox

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobVox" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! This species has a severely limiting game mechanic and is not recommended for new players. [/color]

  ## Special Accomodations

  Vox lungs function very differently from most other species. [color=#ffa500]They are only capable of processing nitrogen,[/color] which is converted to ammonia and exhaled.

  Additionally, due to an unusual set of biological circumstances, [color=red][bold]oxygen is highly toxic to them.[/color][/bold] If exposed to oxygen, it will quickly build up in their blood, causing rapid onset organ failure and eventually death.

  Vox [color=#1e90ff]slowly recover from low levels of poison damage[/color] on their own, so long as they are careful not to exceed 20 poison damage.

  This allows them to endure breathing station air for up to thirty seconds at a time without lasting damage, letting them quickly eat, drink, take oral medication, and so on.

  A thirty second oxygen exposure takes them two minutes to recover from.

  If their health does not seem to improve within a minute of oxygen exposure, they should seek medical attention.

  NT has made special accomodations for this species, [color=#1e90ff]including readily accessible nitrogen tanks in dispensers and lockers throughout most stations.[/color] Some stations may even have a "Vox Box," an enclosed nitrogen-rich environment devoid of oxygen.

  ## Damage

  Vox blood is anaerobic, [color=#1e90ff]but is iron-based, allowing it to be metabolized from iron supplements.[/color]

  As they possess talons, their unarmed attacks deal Slash damage instead of Blunt.

 ## Vox Naming Conventions

  Vox typically use a single name made of random syllables, often with repeating patterns.
  Names should not be excessively long or be so repetitive/convoluted as to be unreadable.

  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Hirixashahre
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Xapikrikrik
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Chipikirchitchitchitbecretretrer
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Trololol
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry

</Document>
