<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Ashley Woodiss-Field <ash@DESKTOP-H64M4AI.localdomain>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 BeeRobynn <166929042+BeeRobynn@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 ColesMagnum <98577947+AW-FulCode@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 SX-7 <92227810+SX-7@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Ted Lukin <66275205+pheenty@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 coderabbitai[bot] <136622811+coderabbitai[bot]@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
  # Yowie

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobYowie" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Yowie are a once-thought urban myth, turned newly discovered mystical species of bipedal hairy creature.
  Their body is larger than most other species in stature, with the downside of them [color=#AAFF00]not being able to fit into most Nanotrasen external wear or shoes[/color] (they can barely squeeze into softsuits), or [color=#AAFF00] being able to be carried by others[/color].
  Their fur also allows them to take [color=#baf2ef]less cold damage[/color].

  Their stature makes their unarmed punch deal [color=#ec3a3a]2x the damage[/color] of a human punch.

  They are larger, making them easier to hit in combat, but they take 25% less Blunt, Slash and Piercing damage.
  They also weigh more, allowing them to pull lighter species with ease.

  ## Fuckin' skiz, mate
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Joint" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  From discussions had between our species, it seems historically they were living beside humanity during its existence on Earth in parts of Australia, lending them to develop a thick australian accent with slang included.
  They seem to have spent most of their time experimenting with some of the most dangerous and experimental drugs, and on review, they've built up a bigger tolerance to most chemicals. Uniquely, their liver carries out the task of metabolizing chemicals.


</Document>
