<Document>
 # The Monument
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MonumentCosmicCult1" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MonumentCosmicCult2" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MonumentCosmicCult3" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Before you set about your goals, The Monument must be [italic][color=#4cabb3]Beckoned[/color][/italic] by your cult leader. When first built, the Monument is invisible, intangible, and effectively imperceptible to any non-cultist. Once empowered, the Monument will become both visible and tangible to all individuals aboard the station.

  It is for this reason that the Monument is best hidden from prying eyes, and in a relatively defendable location.

  Entropy may be infused into the Monument to empower it. As you infuse the Monument with entropy, the cult will collectively gain access to more [color=#4cabb3][bold]Influences[/bold][/color] and [color=#4cabb3][bold]Glyphs[/bold][/color], which can be attained by interacting with the Monument.

  Cultists can interact with the monument to purchase additional [color=#4cabb3][bold]Influences[/bold][/color]. Entropy stored in the monument for the sake of purchasing is [italic]per person,[/italic] so one cultist purchasing an ability will not spend any entropy collected by other cultists.

  [textlink="For more on Influences, click here." link="CosmicCultInfluences"]

  ## Beckoning the Unknown
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlushieCosmicCult" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Should you succeed in fully empowering the Monument to the third stage, it will hunger for one last threshold of entropy - fuel to feed the final curtain call. Once enough entropy has been infused, the empowered Monument will glow, signalling that it can now be used to [color=#4cabb3][bold]Beckon[/bold][/color] the Unknown. Any cultist may do so by interacting with the monument.

  Be prepared to defend the Monument when doing so, as just one waylaid action from a single disruptive soul is all it will take to bring this ritual to a sudden, unceremonious halt.

  Once the Monument becomes ready to activate, cultists [bold]must[/bold] activate it before being once again able to access the Monument's store and glyphs - the end [bold]cannot[/bold] be forestalled.

  ## Glyphs
  Glyphs may be [color=#4cabb3]Scribed[/color] by interacting with the Monument. You may also [color=#4cabb3]Unscribe[/color] an unused Glyph in a similar manner at The Monument.

  Be aware that activating a Glyph will sap the health of all cultists aiding in the Glyph's activation!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicGlyphKnowledge" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicGlyphProjection" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicGlyphWarding" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicGlyphBlades" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicGlyphCessation" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CosmicGlyphTruth" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  - [bold]Glyph of Knowledge[/bold] allows a non-cultist brought upon it to be [color=#4cabb3]converted[/color] into a fellow cosmic cultist! Chaplains and individuals with a mindshield cannot be converted using this glyph.
  - [bold]Glyph of Projection[/bold] will allow the cultist using it to temporarily escape their body as a free-floating and imperceptible [color=#4cabb3]Astral Form[/color], allowing the cultist to spy on unsuspecting crewmembers.
  - [bold]Glyph of Warding[/bold] transmutes any spacesuit - hard or soft - into the cosmic cult's special [color=#4cabb3]Entropic Armor[/color].
  - [bold]Glyph of Blades[/bold] randomly transmutes any sharp object into one of the cosmic cult's [color=#4cabb3]Unique Weapons[/color].
  - [bold]Glyph of Cessation[/bold] transmutes a portable atmospherics scrubber into an unanchored [color=#4cabb3]Vacuous Spire[/color].
  - [bold]Glyph of Truth[/bold] allows any non-cultist brought upon it to be [color=#4cabb3]converted[/color] into a fellow cosmic cultist, even if they are a chaplain or protected by a mindshield.
</Document>
