<Document>
  # The Mansus Veil Weakens
  So you're a Heretic? Well, get ready for magic and battle. Grab influences, complete sacrifices, accomplish rituals, and ascend to godhood.

  Your ultimate goal is to ascend and become all powerful, but to do that you must gain knowledge.
  

  ## Starting Knowledge
  - \[ [color=red]Mansus Grasp[/color] \] - A short range spell that channels eldritch power straight to your palm. Upon contact, knocks down and confuses unsuspecting targets.
  - \[ [color=red]Heartbeat of the Mansus[/color] \] - Allows you to sacrifice targets who are in critical or worse condition to the Mansus, gibbing them and rewarding you with one knowledge point; two if your victim was a head of staff.
  - \[ [color=red]Amber Focus[/color] \] - Allows you to transmute a sheet of glass and a pair of eyes into an Amber Focus. This is a small neck-worn item that allows you to cast more advanced Heretic spells while worn.
  - \[ [color=red]Living Heart[/color] \] - Allows you to pinpoint your targets. Plays an audible heartbeat sound, so use it carefully.
  - \[ [color=red]Relentless Heartbeat[/color] \] - Allows you to reroll your target selection, in case you've run out of bodies or want a different approach.

  ## Tips
  - On the Path of Ash, always carry a fire extinguisher or a bottle of water with you! While you can spew out fireballs, you are not immune to them until you ascend!
  - As a [color=purple]Ghoul[/color], your [color=green]Mansus Link[/color] ability is extremely useful for communication. When you use it on someone, they gain a radio channel similar to changelings with :z key to talk privately.
  - Unlike most other solo antagonists, Heretics start weak but grow stronger over time. It would be best not to attract too much attention to yourself until you unlock more powerful spells and equipment.
  - [color=purple]Influences[/color] can spawn in almost any location on the station, ranging from the main hallways and public restrooms to [color=cyan]Command staff offices[/color] and [color=red]restricted security areas[/color] in the Brig. It's best to check every area you can access, public and department.
  - Monkeys and other animals make for great, usually non-suspicious sources of organs or corpses for your heretical rituals.
  - Most summoned ghouls will drop the components used to create them on death. While having them to die is not ideal, you can easily grab the parts and summon another.
</Document>
