<Document>
# Handling Orders

Orders are to be taken and handled as they come in. Orders out of the ordinary or not on the pre-approved list for a department are to be vetted with the Quartermaster.

1.  Orders [bold]not[/bold]on the pre-approved materials list should be accompanied with an acquisition slip.

1a Acquisition slips should match the ID of the person presenting the slip or the department head.

1b Acquisition slips should have a properly filled out reason for the request. The Quartermaster may deny any requisition that does not state an adequate reason.

2. On [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color], [color=#8d1d75]Code Violet[/color] or [color=#ec9ba4]Code Gamma[/color], item request forms or acquisition slips shall not be required for any orders for security and medical respectively.

3. Only Cargo Technicians and the Quartermaster shall handle orders. Non-cargo crew members should never touch the cargo request computer.

4. Orders are not required to be delivered to their recipients. However, the mailing system or normal deliveries may occur on [color=#00a933]Code Green[/color] or [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color].

5. Assistants must fill out an [italic]item request form[/italic] for any request.

6. To be valid the [italic]item request form[/italic] must must state:
- Time of the request.
- Name and title of requestor.
- Quantity of items and reason for request.
- Any special statements or considerations.
- Stamp from the requestor's head if the order is large or contains potential contraband.

7. Copies of all approved invoices are to reviewed by the Quartermaster, stamped for confirmation and stored for future review should the need arise.

8. Upon receipt of 5 or more requests or after 15 minutes, all current invoices should be brought to the Quartermaster for approval and distribution.

9. Once an order has arrived, the cargo invoice should be copied and posted outside of cargo to inform the crew of the delivery.

10. In order to receive their order, the original requestor or department head must be present.

11. Orders for basic materials (glass, steel, plastic & cloth) may be placed by cargo personnel for the cargo department if the material is below a limit of 240 between all lathes and loose resources.
</Document>