<Document>

    # Handling Orders

    Orders are to be taken and handled as they come in. Orders out of the ordinary or not on the pre-approved list for a department are to be vetted with Item Request Forms.

    1. Only Cargo Technicians and the Quartermaster shall place orders. Non-Cargo crew members should never touch the cargo computer.

    2. On Codes Red, Violet, or Gamma, item request forms shall not be required for any orders for Security, and Medical respectively.

    3. Orders are not required to be delivered to their recipients. However, the mailing system or normal deliveries may take place on Code Green or Blue.

    4. Item Request Forms are to be filled out should the requestor's department not match the pre-approved item list.

    5. Passengers must fill out an Item Request Form for any request.

    6. To be valid the order request form must must state:

        - Time of request.
        - Name and title of requestor.
        - Quantity of items and reason for request.
        - Any special statements or considerations.
        - Stamp from the requestor's head if the order is large or contains potential contraband.

    7. All orders should have 3 copies.

        - One copy is to be stored for future review if needed, such as a Security review.
        - One copy is to be placed for the Quartermaster's review.
        - One copy is to be returned for the requestor for proof of their order.

    The order may then be entered fully into the cargo request computer. The entered request should include all relevant information that was provided, including reason for the order, as well as requestor. The request SHOULD NOT be approved. Technicians may not approve requests unless it is an emergency.

    8. Upon receipt of 5 or more requests, or after 15 minutes, all current requests should be brought to the Quartermaster for review and approval. Alternatively, the Quartermaster may use their digiboard, and a cargo technician may approve the paperwork with the relevant stamp.

    7. Once an order has arrived, the order slip that came with the order should be posted outside of Cargo for the requestor's use.

    8. In order to receive their order, the requestor must bring their original request form and present it to the cargo technician or Quartermaster.

    9. Non-cargo personnel may not use the cargo ordering computer.

    10. Orders for the basic materials (glass, steel, plastic, cloth) may be placed by cargo personnel for the Cargo department if the material is below a limit of 180 between all lathes and loose resources.
    Pre-Approved Materials List

    This pre-approved materials list does not mean that you must order the item, rather it means that the Item Request Form may be omitted. Consideration to the station's needs and Cargo's budget still applies.

</Document>