<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Standard Operating Procedure
The Standard Operating Procedure, SOP, is the set of procedures for crew personnel to follow when there is (or isn't) an emergency on the station.
These directives are here to assist you, as a valuable crew member on this station, with knowledge of what to do in these special scenarios.

These procedures are a guideline to assure all actions follow Nanotrasen's best interest. Failure to follow these can result in dismissal and/or demotion from your job position.

<Box>It is [bold]highly advised[/bold] to read over the [bold]Standard Procedures[/bold], [bold]Legal[/bold], and your [bold]Job Department[/bold] SOP!</Box>

## What Does This Define?
The SOP outlines several procedures for alert levels, Chain of Command (command succession), treatment of prisoners, identification of threats, and much more.
Adherence to these guidelines is expected but the guidelines are malleable to multiple scenarios. Should you choose to deviate from these guidelines, you must justify your actions when asked.

  <Box>
    [bold]NOTE:[/bold] Blindly following SOP while ignoring context is a [italic]ridiciously bad idea[/italic] and is not suggested. [bold]Context is King![/bold]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    Further note that any references to "This Station" or "Station" are assumed to be the station you are working on during this shift. You may find this on your PDA.
  </Box>

## General Station SOP
The following links are for general knowledge of the station.
- [textlink="Hiring, Promoting, Transferring" link="Hiring SOP"]
- [textlink="Firing, Demoting, Terminating" link="Demoting SOP"]
- [textlink="Chain of Command" link="Succession"]
- [textlink="Legal" link="Legal SOP"]
- [textlink="Emergencies" link="Emergencies SOP"]
- [textlink="Alert Levels" link="Alert Levels"]

## General Department
The following links are for general department SOPs. These will guide you to the folder entry.
- [textlink="Cargo Department" link="Cargo SOP"]
- [textlink="Command Department" link="Command SOP"]
- [textlink="Engineering Department" link="Engineering SOP"]
- [textlink="Medical Department" link="Medical SOP"]
- [textlink="Science Department" link="Science SOP"]
- [textlink="Security Department" link="Security SOP"]
- [textlink="Service Department" link="Service SOP"]

</Document>
