<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Atmospheric Technician SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#c8a404][bold]Atmospheric Technician[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. Atmospheric Technicians are permitted to re-pipe their region to suit their needs but must maintain life support to distro.

2. Atmospheric Technicians are permitted to make mixtures, but they must have a use and must be beneficial to the station and/or its engines.
<Box>Failure to follow this may result in Termination or in severe cases Contract Nullification.</Box>

3. Atmospheric Technicians are permitted to cool Plasma and store it for later use in Radiation Collectors. Likewise, they are permitted to cool Nitrogen or Carbon Dioxide and store it for use as coolant for the Supermatter Engine;

4. Atmospheric Technicians are not permitted to take the axe out of its case unless there is an immediate and urgent threat to their life or urgent access to crisis locations is necessary.
<Box>The axe must be returned to the case afterwards, and the case locked.</Box>

5. Atmospheric Technicians are not permitted to tamper with the default values on Air Alarms, but must fix them and/or change their values for emergency situations. [bold]This does not include isolated sections for burn chambers, mixture chambers, et cetera.[/bold]
<Box>They are, however, permitted to create small, acclimatized rooms for species that require special atmospheric conditions (such as Vox), provided they receive express permission from the Chief Engineer.</Box>

6. Atmospheric Technicians must periodically check on the Central Alarms Computer, in periods of, at most, thirty (30) minutes.

7. Atmospheric Technicians must respond promptly to piping and station breaches.
<Box>Failure to report within fifteen (15) minutes will be considered a breach of Standard Operating Procedure, unless there are no spare Atmospheric Technicians to report, or an Engineer has arrived on scene first.</Box>
<Box>All Hazard Zones must be cordoned off with Engineering Tape or holobarriers, for the sake of everyone else.</Box>

8. Atmospheric Technicians are held to the same guidelines and standards as [color=#c8a404][bold]Station Engineer[/bold][/color]s but have elevated access and their own rules for Atmospherics.

</Document>
