<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Rouge2t7 <81053047+Sarahon@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Execution Procedures
These are the procedures that [bold]must[/bold] be followed by Security and Command when performing executions on any personnel on the station.

1. Prisoner's security status must be set to "*Execute*", and their relevant crimes entered into their sec record.
<Box>If they are crew but do not have a sec record, create a record in their name then set it as before. If they are not crew, this step can be skipped.</Box>

2. Prisoners must be cuffed, and their ID must be terminated. Refer to [bold]Dismissal/Demotion Policies[/bold].

3. Prisoners must be stripped of all belongings. Said belongings must be placed in one of the prisoner gear lockers, and the prisoner equipped with standard prisoner uniform and headset.

4. Prisoners must be clothed in a Prison Uniform and Shoes.

5. Prisoners must be allowed their final words.

6. A Chaplain may be present if requested, and allowed by the Captain and/or Head of Security.

7. It is advised, but not required, to have medical personnel in attendance to verify death.

8. Authorization must be given by the Captain. If one is not present, follow the chain of command.
<Box>Should the Captain or appropriate acting captain be unable to provide authorization, it must come from Central Command. Without authorization, executions are murder.</Box>

9. Though not obligatory, it is recommended that all executed prisoners be considered for cyborgification post-execution.

10. Kill on sight orders are classified as executions, however due to the often chaotic situations in which these occur, security records must be updated (per point 1) within a reasonable amount of time after the order is given or carried out.

11. If medical personnel have been assigned to security, best effort should be made to inform them of any performed execution so that medical records of the prisoner may be updated.

</Document>
