<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Punishment Procedures
This is a list of procedures for punishing those accused of crimes. These are standard punishments and should be followed unless an emergency prevents such cases.

## Brigging Rules
No prisoner is to be held for longer than ten (10) minutes in Processing if no evidence against them is readily available.

Should the ten (10) minutes expire without any evidence of any crimes coming to light, the prisoner is to be released. Otherwise, proceed with the following guidelines.

## Brigging Guidelines
1. The prisoner is to be cuffed, and brought to their cell.

2. The prisoner is to be stripped of all belongings, save for their uniform, headset, PDA and shoes. Vox are to retain their internals.

3. The timer for the cell is to be set, and the charges declared.

4. The prisoner is then to be uncuffed. If they are a violent risk, they may be buckle cuffed, flashed and then have their cuffs removed.

5. Prisoners attempting to break the lights in the cell are to be flashed.

6. Prisoners attempting to break the windows of the cell are to be flashed and their timers reset.

7. Removal of the prisoner's headset may ONLY occur if the prisoner is using the headset to constantly flood any communication channel with irrelevant/inane information and/or calls of "Shitcurity", or if the prisoner is seriously attempting to incite violent action against Security and/or Command via continuous calls for violence.

8. After searching has been done on PDA, clothing, and headset, they are to be returned unless they are contraband or have been tampered with. In such cases, they should be replaced.

9. Prisoners should never be deprived of equipment that is necessary for their vital operations.
<Box>This includes batteries for IPCs, N2 Gas Tanks and Masks for Voxes, and regular equipment as stated above (PDA, Headset, Clothes).</Box>

</Document>
