<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Search Procedures
This is the list of procedures that should be followed when performing searches on station personnel and/or in Departments.

1. On [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color], a search requires probable cause and/or approval from the Captain and/or Head of Security.
<Box>Probable Cause is defined as any circumstance that creates reasonable suspicion that a crime was committed (eg, direct accusation from a crewmember, witnessing the crime directly, prints on a crime scene, presence in a restricted area with high value items, etc).</Box>
<Box>Approval simply requires permission from the relevant person - verbal or over radio is enough.</Box>

2. On [color=#388c34]Green Alert[/color], searches should be conducted without cuffs, and the searched personnel must hand over requested items.

3. Searchees who refuse may be cuffed for the search.

4. Any other item in the searchee's possession may be asked for, including but not limited to bags, belts, jackets, headsets, and PDAs.

5. On [color=#1b67a5]Blue Alert[/color] and above, a search can be done without probable cause.
<Box>This can be done by cuffing the searched, and forcibly removing their bags and emptying their pockets.</Box>

6. Refusing a legal search is considered resisting arrest (on [color=#1b67a5]Blue Alert[/color] or higher).

7. Security may only perform surgery to search for illegal implants if the searched personnel is a confirmed EoC or has been confirmed to have stolen an item that can no longer be located.
<Box>In addition, if there is reasonable suspicion of illegal implant possession, the Captain and/or Head of Security can issue a warrant for an implant search if they deem it necessary.</Box>

8. Recommended but optional: After searching someone, their security status should be set to RELEASED, and add a note that they were searched but nothing was found.
<Box>This helps prevent security wasting time by repeatedly re-searching the same person, and makes it easier to tell who has not yet been searched.</Box>

</Document>
