<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 4-1 - Maintaining relationships between rounds

  Character relationships are encouraged to form between rounds. However, you must emphasize that such relationships must be fostered across a hypothetical history where these characters have worked dozens or perhaps hundreds of shifts where nothing blew up.

  Each round of Space Station 14 happens independently to each other, and each round is the worst day of your character's life. You are free to "canonize" events that have happened in shifts, so long as it is contextualized in a far more mundane setting than what may have actually happened.

  Additionally, you must be conscious that any actions your character takes is acting on good faith. Is this behavior informed by by the dozen potentially canon times they messed with you or greeted you warmly, which establishes pattern of behavior between shifts; or is it informed by the time that they murdered you or stole from you for an objective, which is non canon and existed only in that tiny bubble that was a previously played shift? You can never remember a time where another character was an antagonist.

  Lastly, remember that all characters in a round have players behind them, who are all intending to have fun and tell an interesting story. Forming cliques that exclude characters that are new or around infrequently should be heavily discouraged. If you play a character who tends to be very aggressive or hostile, it may be worthwhile to check in with the other player through OOC means (keeping within the bounds of [textlink="Core Rule 5" link="RuleC5"] and [textlink="Core Rule 14" link="RuleC14"]!) to ensure that you have been received well and have not negatively impacted the round.

 ## Acceptable
  - I refused service at cargo to John Doe for a personal request because he's an asshole and I'm disinclined to give him any favors, because previous rounds have shown that our working relationship is antagonistic.

 ## Unacceptable
  - I refused service at cargo to Jane Doe for a personal request because whenever I've seen her prepare as an antagonist, she acts like she's acting right now, and I could already see coming what she'd use this request for.

 # Metafriending and Metagrudging
  This section provides additional information on a concept that is prohibited by multiple metashield items that are never revealed IC. Giving a person or character preferential treatment based on something that your character should not know is considered metafriending. Treating a person or character negatively based on something that your character should not know is considered metagrudging.

  ## Metafriending Examples
  These are all examples of things that are prohibited by at least one metashield item that is never revealed IC.
  - Giving a character additional access or a job because you are friends with the player who is playing that character.
  - Trusting a character because you are friends with the player who is playing that character.
  - Not fighting a character because you are friends with the player who is playing that character.
  - Ignoring your objective to kill a character because your character and theirs became friends in a previous round.

  ## Metagrudging Examples
  These are all examples of things that are prohibited by at least one metashield item that is never revealed IC.
  - Not giving a character additional access or a job because you are mad at or don't like the player who is playing that character.
  - Not trusting a character because you are mad at or don't like the player who is playing that character.
  - Starting a fight with a character because of something that they did last round.
  - Starting a fight with a character because they killed you while you were playing a different character.
  - Targeting or harassing a character based on anything which that character did outside the current round.
  - Targeting or harassing a character based on anything which the character's player did while not playing the character.

</Document>
