<Document>
# Roleplay Rule 4-2 - Metashield regarding antagonists

  ## Implanted Implants

  Implanted implants are shielded.

  Implanters themselves and un-implanted implants are not shielded. This prohibits implant checking.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - discovering a non-NT implanter, used or unused
  - discovering a non-NT implant box
  - discovering use of a non-NT implant by anyone
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Chameleon Items

  Chameleon items are shielded.

  Being suspicious of an item being fake or stolen is not shielded, but testing items or calling them chameleon is covered by this shield.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - seeing someone else cause any chameleon item to change
  - finding holographic nanomachine fibers
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Stealth Items

  The fact that an item can be something other than what its visual appearance and examine description indicate is shielded.

  This shield protects stealth items, including protecting them from being tested.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - seeing the item behave differently than the expected behavior for the item
  - seeing the item used for its hidden purpose
  - experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - discovering an unlocked uplink

  ## Traitor

  The existence of Syndicate agents who infiltrate and sabotage the station is not shielded.

  ## Thief

  While uncommon, the existence of kleptomaniacs who steal anything that is not bolted down is not shielded.

  Knowledge of what items are possible thief targets is shielded, but knowledge that some items are valuable or would be dangerous in the wrong hands is not shielded. (ex: Captain's ID, Chief Engineer's magboots)

  ## Initial Infected ('Zombies')

  The existence of viruses that reanimate the dead is common knowledge, and not shielded, though the exact details of the phenomenon in popular media are played up and frequently incorrect.

  The existence of Romerol, a reagent that triggers a zombie infection, is shielded.

  Ambuzol and Ambuzol plus, medications that stop the progression of or vaccinate against a zombie infection, are not shielded.

  There are many reasons that your coworkers may arrive to work feeling sick; coughing or otherwise being ill [bold]DOES NOT[/bold] reveal that they are an Initial Infected.

  ## Ninja

  The existence of Ninjas and the Spider Clan beyond being a pop culture mainstay is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - the Ninja is witnessed cloaking, uncloaking or teleporting. Spotting an actively cloaked Ninja does not count.
  - you witness an uncloaked Ninja who is aggressive or otherwise actively completing their objectives (emagging doors, tampering with computers)

  ## Changeling

  The existence of cannibal shapeshifters being real is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - you are the Research Director or Chief Medical Officer
  - you witness the Changeling eat or shapeshift
  - the Changeling assaults you using its abilities
  - you witness the Changeling use an ability that cannot otherwise be explained

  The unique quality of Changeling blood to react violently in a centrifuge is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Research Director or Chief Medical Officer

  The ability to prevent the revival of a Changeling by cremating them is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any the following:
  - you are the Research Director or Chief Medical Officer
  - you have witnessed a Changeling revive

  ## Heretics

  The existence of functional magical circles beyond their prevalence in pop culture is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Chaplain

  The existence of Heretical magic being real is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - you are the Chaplain or Research Director
  - you witness a Heretic drawing a magic circle or performing a ritual
  - you witness a Heretic cast a spell, or use an ability that cannot otherwise be explained
  - a Heretic ascends

  The ability of certain items to serve as a magical focus allowing a Heretic to cast spells is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Chaplain or Research Director

  The exact details of and material requirements for a Heretic to perform rituals is shielded.

  Reality fractures, while rare, are known to be temporal-spatial abberations and not scientific anomalies. However, the ability for Heretics to channel reality fractures is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Chaplain

  ## Revolutionaries

  The existence of union organizers and prospective mutineers is not shielded. The concept of a Syndicate-backed mutiny is also not shielded.

  The ability to use a flash to "convert" someone to the revolution is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - you witness a conversion
  - the revolution reveals itself

  ## Nuclear Operatives

  The existence of Nuclear Operatives beyond a myth that no one would act on is shielded.

  The fact that the nuke disk must be protected and could be used by a bad actor to try to destroy the station is not shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is any of the following:
  - discovering a blood-red hardsuit
  - discovering a nuclear operative's shuttle
  - a War Ops announcement
  - being a nuclear operative

  The exact, granular details of what a nuclear operative squad would likely bring and how to counter them is shielded.

  The revealing condition for this shield is the following:
  - you are the Head of Security

  Common, broad knowledge of game mechanics (like common weapon types, stunning vs lethals) is not shielded.

  ## Minor antagonists

  All life able to be encountered by salvage technicians are not shielded. This includes space carp, xenos, space ticks, etc.

  Closet skeletons are not shielded.

  Space dragons are a form of interstellar animal and the likelihood of one arriving at or attacking the station is extremely low.

  Rat kings are an invasive species and are fair game to shoot dead.
  Rat kings fall under [textlink="Rule 11-1, Escalation Involving Animals" link="RuleR11-1"].

  The existence of Revenants is shielded until a Revenant is directly witnessed, its Animate ability is witnessed, or you are the Chaplain.

  The Syndicate recruiter is not shielded. The Syndicate attempting to poach staff from Nanotrasen is considered common knowledge, though recruiters are not considered crew nor visitors and can be handled at the discretion of Security.

</Document>
