<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 John Willis <143434770+CerberusWolfie@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Aiden <28298836+Aidenkrz@users.noreply.github.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later
-->

<Document>
# Cargo Technician SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#846326]Cargo Technician[/color] of this station.

1. Cargo Technicians must ensure that every approved order is delivered within 15 minutes of having been placed and approved.

2. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to handle restricted crates (crates for Security/Command).

3. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to order items for sole personal use with the supply department account without express consent from the Quartermaster.
<Box>Exception is made if there are more than [bold]7,500 spesos[/bold] available and no outstanding orders. Cargo Technicians may not deplete the entire department account balance for this.</Box>

4. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to order non-essential items using the supply account (such as cats, or clothing) without express consent from the Quartermaster.

5. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to force and/or break open locked crates.
<Box>Exception is made for Abandoned Crates found by Salvaging.</Box>

6. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to authorize non-departmental orders (such as a Medical Doctor asking for Insulated Gloves) without express permission from the Quartermaster.

7. Cargo Technicians are to ensure and verify that the personnel ordering in the request form is a crew member and is correct identification and shows the correct reason in the request.

8. Cargo Technicians must ensure at least one copy of every Order Form (ie, the forms produced by the Requests Console) is kept inside Cargo until the order is finished.

9. Cargo Technicians must send back all crates that have been ordered, with accompanying manifest on the crate.

10. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to ask for spesos in exchange for legal cargo crate orders or autolathe requests from crew members.

11. Cargo Technicians are not permitted to trade items and/or favors in exchange for items with regular personnel without express consent from the Quartermaster.

12. Cargo Technicians are not to keep any illegal items that are flushed down Disposals, and must deliver them to Security.
</Document>
