<Document>   
# Space Law 

This is just a guideline and you aren't forced to follow it to the letter, but if you don't you should expect certain boys-in-red to come at you with cuffs and a stun-baton (hopefully) on.

Within [bold][color=#313dc4]NanoTrasen[/color][/bold], stations operate under [bold][color=#a83232]Space Law[/color][/bold]. [color=#fcdf03]All persons aboard the station are beholden to this law and expected to follow it.[/color]

<Box> 
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BookSpaceLaw" Caption="Book of Space Law"/> 
</Box> 
## Accessory and Enemy of the NanoTrasen

[color=#fcdf03]Accessory:[/color]
- Accessory charges can be given to anyone who assists a criminal in committing a crime or escaping from security. The sentence for accessory charges can be the same as the original criminal up to and including execution, though the HoS and Warden are allowed to give a lesser charge. Intent or knowledge of the original crime is not needed.

[color=#a83232]Enemy of the NanoTrasen:[/color]
- Current enemies of Nanotrasen currently include: The Syndicate, Terminators, Space Ninjas, and Revolutionaries. Deconversion should always be the top priority whenever possible. Execution of revolutionaries is only authorized when deconversion is not possible or poses too significant of a risk. For enemies of the corporation who pose too great a threat to detain, immediate execution is authorized.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ImageNukie" State="nukie" Caption="Syndicate"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ImageNukie" State="terminator" Caption="Terminator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ImageNukie" State="nukie" Caption="Space Ninja"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ImageNukie" State="nukie" Caption="Revolutionary"/>
</Box>
## Crimes and Sentencing
Minor Crimes
XX1 - Physical harassment: 
- Repeatedly making unwanted, non-harmful physical contact with another person (e.g. shoving, pulling, grabbing).

XX9 - Obstruction of justice: 
- An act that corruptly or by threats or force, or by any threatening letter or communication, influences, obstructs, or impedes, or endeavors to influence, obstruct, or impede, the due administration of justice.

XX4 - Vandalism:
- Vandalism is the action involving deliberate destruction of or damage to the station or private property. The term includes property damage, such as graffiti and defacement directed towards any property without permission of the owner.

Minor Trespass:
- Being in an area which one does not have access to.

Minor Assault: 
- Using physical force on someone without causing serious injury.

Possession, drugs:

X13 - Accessory

X10 - Insubordination
- The act of willfully disobeying an order of one's superior, security, or others in authority during station emergencies. Refusing to perform an action that is unethical or illegal is not insubordination, nor is refusing to perform an action that is not within the scope of authority of the person issuing the order.

</Document> 
