<Document>
  # Air Alarms
  The Air Alarm is a device that enables central monitoring and control over all relevant Atmos devices linked to it.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirAlarm"/>
  </Box>

  Using the Air Alarm, Atmos can quickly and efficiently manage the atmosphere in a given area.

  A room will often have an Air Alarm mounted on the wall, for quick control over multiple devices in that room.

  You can see how to link devices in the [textlink="Link" link="Networking"] guide.

  ## User Interface
  Interacting with an Air Alarm will bring up a menu with 3 sections:
  - Top: The current status of the air alarm. This includes the current pressure and temperature of the area the air alarm is monitoring.
  - Middle: Lists of linked [textlink="Air Vents" link="AirVent"] and [textlink="Air Scrubbers" link="AirScrubber"], as well as all sensors reporting back to the air alarm.
  - Bottom: Buttons to control air alarm operating modes, as well as the ability to toggle the automatic changing of modes.

  ## Alarm Status
  Air alarms quickly communicate the status of the area they are monitoring through the color of the light on the device:
  - [color=green]Normal[/color]: The area is safe to breathe in.
  - [color=yellow]Warning[/color]: The area is starting to deviate from the desired atmosphere, and is becoming unsafe.
  - [color=red]Danger[/color]: The area is no longer safe, internals and/or hardsuits are required.

  Air alarms will automatically drop (close) linked [textlink="firelocks" link="FireAndGasControl"] when the [color=Red]Danger[/color] status is reached.
  These [textlink="firelocks" link="FireAndGasControl"] will automatically raise (open) when the status returns to [color=green]Normal[/color].

  Air alarms have [textlink="signal" link="Networking"] outputs for each of the three statuses, which can be used to trigger other [textlink="signal" link="Networking"] devices when the status changes.

  ## Sensors
  All [textlink="Air Vents" link="AirVent"] and [textlink="Air Scrubbers" link="AirScrubber"] have a built-in sensor, which reports back to the air alarm.
  These sensors can be adjusted in the [bold]Sensors[/bold] tab of the air alarm menu.

  An air alarm's status is directly determined by the thresholds on each sensor.
  If a sensor reports a pressure, temperature, or gas composition outside the set thresholds, the air alarm will change its status accordingly.

  These thresholds can be adjusted and disabled as needed.
  For example, if you are monitoring a room that naturally has a low temperature (such as a freezer) or a high temperature (such as a burn chamber), you can adjust the temperature thresholds to match the expected values.

  An air sensor can also be constructed and [textlink="linked" link="Networking"] to an air alarm.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirSensor"/>
  </Box>

  This is useful for monitoring areas that you don't have an air vent or scrubber in already.

  ## Operating Modes
  To control connected devices quickly, air alarms feature operating modes, which quickly changes the behavior of all linked devices to achieve a desired effect.
  - None: Disables all devices linked to the air alarm.
  - Filtering: [textlink="Air Vents" link="AirVent"] will be enabled with their external bound set to standard atmospheric pressure. [textlink="Air Scrubbers" link="AirScrubber"] will be enabled and scrub all waste gasses normally.
  - Filtering (Wide): Same as Filtering, but all linked [textlink="Air Scrubbers" link="AirScrubber"] will enable their WideNet mode.
  - Fill: [textlink="Air Vents" link="AirVent"] will be enabled with their external bound set to max pressure, [color=orange][protodata="GasVentPump" comp="GasVentPump" member="MaxPressure"/] kPa[/color]. [textlink="Air Scrubbers" link="AirScrubber"] will be disabled.
  - Panic: [textlink="Air Vents" link="AirVent"] will be disabled, and [textlink="Air Scrubbers" link="AirScrubber"] will be set to siphon mode.

  Air alarms will automatically switch between the Filtering and Filtering (Wide) modes based on the current status of the area they are monitoring.
  - If the area reaches [color=red]Danger[/color] status or above, the air alarm will switch to Filtering (Wide) mode.
  - If the area reaches [color=green]Normal[/color] or [color=yellow]Warning[/color] status, the air alarm will switch to Filtering mode.

  This behavior can be disabled by toggling the "Auto" box in the bottom section of the air alarm menu.

  Relevant tips on how to fix [textlink="spacing" link="Spacing"] and [textlink="fires" link="Fires"] can be found in the relevant guides.
</Document>
