<Document>
  # Antimatter Engine (AME)
  The Antimatter Engine is a short-term support generator for the station, providing a sizable chunk of power for a limited time.

  It's mainly used to assist engineers in starting up bigger engines like the Singularity Engine or Tesla Engine, by supplementing the station's batteries with partial power to extend their runtime.

  ## Construction
  <Box>Required parts:</Box>
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeController"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeJar"/>
  </Box>

  To assemble an AME, start by wrenching down the controller on the near end of a HV wire. Most stations have exposed HV wiring or designated spots to wrench an AME controller to the floor.

  From there, start putting down a 3x3 or larger square of AME parts in preparation for construction, making sure to maximize the number of "center" pieces that are surrounded on all eight sides.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmePartFlatpack" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Once this is done, you can use a multitool to convert each AME part into shielding, which should form a finished AME configuration.

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeController" Caption=""/>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeShielding" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]An example of a one core setup[italic][/color]
  </Box>

  From there, insert a fuel jar, set the fuel rate to [color=#a4885c]twice the core count or less[/color], and turn on injection. Any more than this ratio will eventually result in the engine [color=#ff0000]overheating[/color] and, shortly afterwards, [color=#ff0000]exploding[/color].

  ## Upgrades
  You can upgrade the AME by installing more cores, which can be done by ordering more AME shielding flatpacks from [color=#a4885c]Cargo[/color], and adding them to the existing AME configuration.

  The more cores you have, the more power the AME can output. However, extreme AME upgrades are generally not recommended due to diminishing returns in power generation.


</Document>
