<Document>
  # Atmospheric Network Monitor
  The Atmospheric Network Monitor is a computer that shows information on monitored [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"] across the station.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerAtmosMonitoring"/>
  </Box>

  It is a useful tool for quickly gauging the tempreature, pressure, and gas composition of station [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"], as well as how they spread throughout the station.

  ## Listed Networks
  The Atmospheric Network Monitor displays a list of all monitored [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"] on the station.

  Each network is color-coded and named based on the name and color of the Gas Pipe Sensor that is monitoring it.
  To change the name or color of a network, you can rename it with a labeler, or change the color using a spray painter.

  Clicking on a network will show detailed information about the network, as well as highlighting the network on the station map.

  This information includes the molar amount of the gas in the entire network, as well as the composition of the gas in the network.
  This can prove extremely useful for monitoring important networks like the Distro pipenet, which can not function correctly if below certain pressures.

  ## Station Map
  The Atmospheric Network Monitor displays the location of all [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"] on the station map, as well as any pipe-based devices.
  Note that the pipe network doesn't need to have an attached Gas Pipe Sensor to be visible on the map.

  These devices are colored on the map based on their color on the station, which can help identify seperate [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"], and the devices that are connected to them.

  Pipe based devices are grouped together on the map's legend based on their function:
  - A [bold]Network Opening[/bold] is a device that connects a pipe network to the station's atmosphere. Think [textlink="Air Vents" link="AirVents"], [textlink="Passive Vents" link="PassiveVent"], and [textlink="Air Injectors" link="AirInjector"].
  - An [bold]Air Scrubber[/bold] is just an [textlink="Air Scrubber" link="AirScrubber"].
  - A [bold]Flow Regulator[/bold] is a device that controls the flow of gas through a pipe network. Think [textlink="Gas Pumps" link="Pumps"], [textlink="Gas Valves" link="Valves"], and [textlink="Gas Mixers/Filters" link="MixingAndFiltering"]. The arrow on the device indicates the direction of gas flow. This also often determines where a pipe network is seperated or split.
  - A [bold]Thermoregulator[/bold] is any device that does something to the temperature of the gas in a pipe network. Think [textlink="Thermomachines" link="Thermomachines"], [textlink="Radiators" link="Radiators"], and even Medical Cryopods.

  ## Gas Pipe Sensors
  Atmospheric Network Monitors collect data on [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"] through Gas Pipe Sensors.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeSensor"/>
  </Box>

  By default, the station should have gas pipe sensors on all major [textlink="pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"]. Examples include the Distro and Waste networks.

  If you wish to monitor a new network, you can construct a gas pipe sensor and it will automatically be visible on the Atmospheric Network Monitor.
  Make sure you construct the sensor on the pipe network you want to monitor.
  [textlink="Pipe networks" link="PipeNetworks"] can easily be seperated by a simple Gas Pump or Valve, which can cause the sensor to report data on a completely different network.

</Document>
