<Document>
  # The Ocean and You

  Flooding is an inevitability of living under the water. Whether it be the horrors of the abyss finding their way in through a damaged window, a wall giving in to pressure, or nefarious activities.
  In the event of a flood, there are a few things to keep in mind.

  ## Drowning

  For most, lungs are NOT meant to inhale water. However, water can and WILL find it's way in. In that event, it's natural to panic. 
  Be prepared to keep calm and act fast. Equip a breathing apparatus and activate your internals, they will automatically draw water out of your lungs and expel it through the outlet.
  Water is freezing cold and will rapidly destroy your lungs, meaning that activating your internals immediately will prevent a rapid and horrible death.

  ## Pressure

  The ocean depths are very high pressure, and this pressure will cause serious damage to your body even if you are breathing air. 
  Emergency pressure suits can be found in lockers and equipped to provide protection from this pressure. They will not protect from cold, however.

  ## Cold

  Seawater is cold. Very, [bold] very [/bold] cold. So cold, in fact, that it will rapidly outright kill you if exposed for too long. If you are immersed in seawater, you need to act fast.
  Odds are you have minutes before hypothermia takes hold. Find a way out of the water if you can, if not, find a warm article of clothing such as a jacket to try and fight off the freezing temperatures.

  ## Hull repairs

  Floods will continue to leak until the hull has been patched. To do this, block the breach with whatever airtight structure that you have on-hand. 
  Inflatible walls and doors are good options. Engineering is also equipped with foam grenades that can rapidly seal a breach. If one is thrown, make sure to keep distance from it. The foam can trap unassuming bystanders easily.

  ## Draining

  Sweetwater is equipped with drain pumps across the facility. When a breach is detected, they will immediately get to work purging it from the halls.
  This can be sped up by using manual scrubbers to gather the water.

  ## Visitors

  In the event of a hull breach, there is a non-zero chance some visitors may find their way inside Sweetwater. 
  If you are near the breach site and hear unidentified scuffling, clicking or growling: [bold] run [/bold].
  
</Document>
