<Document>
  # Gas Mining and Storage
  Gasses are often permanently used. Whether they are lost to [textlink="space" link="Spacing"] or used in a burn chamber, the station needs to be able to produce more gas to replace what is lost.
  It also needs to store this gas in a safe and efficient manner.

  ## Gas Miners
  Gas miners are used to replenish the station's gas supply. They are found in the gas storage tanks in Atmospherics.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMinerOxygenStation"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMinerNitrogenStation"/>
  </Box>

  Gas miners constantly produce room temperature gas and push it into the exposed atmosphere. They require no power to function, and never stop working unless they have reached the defined [bold]cutoff pressure[/bold].

  You can see more information about the gas miners by inspecting them using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ExamineEntity"][/bold][/color].
  Try inspecting the gas miners presented above.

  Gas miners come in tiers, with the larger versions having a higher pressure cutoff than the smaller versions.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMinerNitrogen" Caption="300 kPa"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMinerNitrogenStation" Caption="1000 kPa"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMinerNitrogenStationLarge" Caption="4500 kPa"/>
  </Box>

  If gas miners are ever unanchored from the station, they can be reanchored using a regular wrench.

  ## Gas Storage
  Gas storage tanks are used to store gas produced by the gas miners, and to make it available to other processes. They are found in Atmospherics.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReinforcedPlasmaWindow" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasOutletInjector" Rotation="270" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasMinerOxygenStation" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPassiveVent" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WallReinforced" Rotation="0" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]An example of a small gas holding tank[italic][/color]
  </Box>

  Various atmos processes insert and remove gasses from the gas storage tanks.
  For example:
  - The gas miner provides fresh gasses to the gas storage tanks, if there is room.
  - The recyclernet injects reclaimed gasses into the gas storage tanks for reuse.
  - Setups like the distronet and burn chamber remove gasses from the gas storage tanks.

  Gas storage tanks are designed to be able to be measured using a [textlink="Gas Analyzer" link="AtmosTools"].
  Because the outflow vent is a [textlink="passive vent" link="PassiveVent"], you can use a [textlink="gas analyzer" link="AtmosTools"] to measure the gas content of the [textlink="pump's" link="Pumps"] input, which is drawing from the gas storage tank.
</Document>
