<Document>
  # Gasses
  Gasses are a critical part of the station's operation.
  You may know them as the stuff you breathe, but they are also used in many other ways.

  Gasses have certain properties that make them useful for different tasks.
  Atmospherics can also synthesize exotic gasses from other gasses, which can be used for special purposes.

  ## Oxygen
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OxygenCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OxygenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoubleEmergencyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExtendedEmergencyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A common gas, used by most species on the station to breathe.

  Oxygen is an oxidizer, which means it supports combustion.
  This makes it both useful when fusing gasses in a burn chamber, and dangerous when mixed with flammable gasses.

  ## Nitrogen
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrogenCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoubleEmergencyNitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExtendedEmergencyNitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyNitrogenTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  An inert gas, used in part with oxygen to create a breathable atmosphere.

  Nitrogen is very stable and comprises most of a standard breathable atmosphere.

  Some species like Slimes breathe nitrogen, with the Vox species requiring strictly nitrogen to breathe.

  ## Air Mix
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AirTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A mixture of gasses that is breathable to most species on the station.
  It consists of 21% oxygen and 79% nitrogen.


  ## Carbon Dioxide
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CarbonDioxideCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A waste gas produced by most species on the station. A common byproduct of combustion.

  Despite seeming useless, some departments use it in their line of work.

  ## Water Vapor
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WaterVaporCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A common gas, produced by the burning of plasma and other processes.

  Water vapor has a good specific heat capacity compared to other gasses, making it useful for moving heat around.

  ## Plasma
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A highly flammable gas that is used in many processes on the station.

  Engineering uses this gas to generate power and create exotic gasses.

  Burning it generates a lot of heat, as well as gas byproducts such as carbon dioxide, water vapor, and tritium, depending on the efficiency of the burn.

  Plasma gas also has a good specific heat capacity, making it useful for moving heat around.

  ## Tritium
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TritiumCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  An extremely flammable radioactive gas that is used in the creation of frezon.

  Tritium is produced when burning plasma in a burn chamber, and can be used to create frezon gas in a complicated mixing process.

  The efficiency of tritium fusion depends on various factors such as burn richness and temperature.

  ## Frezon
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FrezonCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A highly sought after gas, due to the difficulty in creating it and its many properties.

  It has an extremely high specific heat capacity, making it excellent for moving large amounts of heat around.

  Frezon can combine in the air with nitrogen to create nitrous oxide, alongside cooling down the air significantly to below freezing temperatures.

  Frezon is very complicated to create, requiring a mix of tritium, oxygen, and nitrogen, all tuned precisely to create the gas.
  If you're looking to create this gas yourself, here's what you need to know:
  - Frezon is produced by the combination of oxygen, tritium, and nitrogen.
  - Tritium and oxygen are mixed at a ratio of around 1:8.
  - Nitrogen is required as a catalyst for the reaction. The amount of nitrogen consumed is dependent on the efficiency of the reaction.
  - The frezon reaction only occurs at cryogenic temperatures, below 73.15 K. The efficency of the reaction (how much frezon is produced) is dependent on the temperature. The closer to 73.15 K, the more frezon is produced, and the less nitrogen is consumed.

  Remember, atmospherics is all about experimentation and process optimization. Try it until you get it right!

  ## Nitrous Oxide
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrousOxideCanister" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyFunnyOxygenTank" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A recreational and waste gas, produced by slimes and the combination of frezon and nitrogen.

  ## Ammonia
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmmoniaCanister" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  A gas produced by the decomposition of bodies.

  Can be condensed to create ammonia, which can be used to make space cleaner.

</Document>
