<Document>
  # Network Configurator
  The network configurator allows you to manipulate device lists, link devices together and configure accesses for airlocks through door electronics.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NetworkConfigurator"/>
  </Box>
  The configurator has two modes: List and Link. You can press [color=gray]Alt+Z[/color] or [color=gray]Alt+Y[/color] to switch between them.

  ## List Mode
  In list mode you can click on network devices to save them on the configurator and then on a network device that has a device list like the [color=#a4885c]Air Alarm[/color].

  When clicking on a device like the Air Alarm, a UI will open, displaying the list currently saved on the device and buttons to manipulate that list.

  You can:
  - Replace the current list with the one saved on the configurator
  - Add the list on the configurator to the current one
  - Clear the current list
  - Copy the current list to the configurator
  - Visualize the connections to the devices on the current list

  Pressing [color=gray][keybind="ActivateItemInHand"][/color] opens the list saved on the configurator where you can remove saved devices.

  ## Link Mode
  With link mode, you can click on a device that is capable of device linking and then click on any other device that is either a sink or source.

  For example, first clicking on a source, like a [color=#a4885c]signal button[/color], and then on sink, like a [color=#a4885c]small light[/color], opens a UI that displays the source ports on the left side and the sink ports on the right.

  Now, you can either click [color=gray]Link Defaults[/color] to link the default ports for a source + sink combination, or press on a source port and then a sink port to connect them.

  An example of a default link for the aforementioned combinaton of devices would be:
  <Box>
    [color=cyan]Pressed 🠒 Toggle[/color]
   </Box>
  When you're done connecting the ports you want, you can click on [color=gray]OK[/color] to close the UI.

  You can quickly link multiple devices to their default port by first clicking on a device that can be linked and then using [color=gray]Alt+Left Mouse button[/color] on the devices you want to link together.

  ## Airlock Access
  To configure an airlock's access, simply take the airlock's door electronics and interact with it using a network configurator (or multitool). Select the accesses you want, insert the door electronics into an airlock frame, and construct to finish!
</Document>
