<Document>
  # Pneumatic Valve
  The pneumatic valve is a bidirectional valve controlled via a pressure input.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PressureControlledValve"/>
  </Box>

  The pneumatic valve has 3 connections: input, output, and control.
  The "input" side will be the input/output connection with the highest pressure, and can switch sides, making the valve bidirectional.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeStraight" Caption="Input/Output"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeStraight" Caption="Control" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PressureControlledValve" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloorTileItemSteel" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeStraight" Caption="Input/Output"/>
  </Box>

  The valve will [color=green]open[/color] when the pressure on the output side is lower than the pressure on the control side by [color=orange][protodata="PressureControlledValve" comp="PressureControlledValve" member="Threshold"/] kPa[/color].

  The valve will [color=red]close[/color] when the pressure of the output side reaches the pressure of the control side within [color=orange][protodata="PressureControlledValve" comp="PressureControlledValve" member="Threshold"/] kPa[/color].

  For example, a pneumatic valve with a control pressure of 500 kPa will open when the output pressure is 500 kPa - [color=orange][protodata="PressureControlledValve" comp="PressureControlledValve" member="Threshold"/] kPa[/color] or lower, and it will close when the output pressure is 500 kPa - [color=orange][protodata="PressureControlledValve" comp="PressureControlledValve" member="Threshold"/] kPa[/color] or higher.

  The valve's control pressure is determined by a pipenet connection, and as such can be adjusted on the fly by a [textlink="pump" link="Pumps"] or another source of pressure control.

  ## Differences to Pumps

  The pneumatic valve is different from a [textlink="pump" link="Pumps"] which moves gas via work.
  The pneumatic valve is a passive device that moves gas based on the higher pressure of the input gas, and as such it can sometimes fill volumes faster than a [textlink="pump" link="Pumps"] can.

  For example, a pneumatic valve with a control pressure of 500 kPa will fill a volume faster than a pressure [textlink="pump" link="Pumps"] set to 500 kPa.
  However, the [textlink="pump" link="Pumps"] will be able to maintain the pressure in the volume more accurately.

  The pneumatic valve can be used in a variety of applications, for example:
  - To automatically vent gasses in a burn chamber based on control input
  - The filling of a volume quickly, based on a customizable control pressure

</Document>
