<Document>
  # Portable Generators

  The "P.A.C.M.A.N." line of portable generators are used to provide emergency or supplemental power to key rooms, areas, or even departments.
  They are easy to set up and maintain, and can be used to power critical systems and areas in the event of a power outage.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorJrPacman" Caption="J.R.P.A.C.M.A.N." />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorPacman" Caption="P.A.C.M.A.N." />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorSuperPacman" Caption="S.U.P.E.R.P.A.C.M.A.N." />
  </Box>

  # The Junior

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorJrPacman" Caption="J.R.P.A.C.M.A.N." />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeldingFuelTank" />
  </Box>

  The J.R.P.A.C.M.A.N. can be found across the station in maintenance shafts, and is ideal for crew to set up themselves whenever there are power issues.
  Its output of up to [color=orange][protodata="PortableGeneratorJrPacman" comp="FuelGenerator" member="MaxTargetPower" format="N0"/] W[/color] is enough to power a room or two, which can prove invaluable in a place like Medbay or Chemistry in the Medical Department.

  Setup is incredibly easy: wrench it down above an [color=green]LV[/color] power cable, give it some welding fuel, and start it up.

  Welding fuel is the only fuel source the J.R.P.A.C.M.A.N. can use, and it can be found in welding fuel tanks across the station, commonly in maintenance areas.

  # The Big Ones

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorPacman" Caption="P.A.C.M.A.N." />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlasma" />
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PortableGeneratorSuperPacman" Caption="S.U.P.E.R.P.A.C.M.A.N." />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetUranium" />
  </Box>

  The P.A.C.M.A.N. and S.U.P.E.R.P.A.C.M.A.N. is intended for usage by engineering for larger power outages and supplementing power in the event of a deficit.
  Bootstrapping larger [textlink="engines" link="SingularityTeslaEngine"], powering departments, and so on.

  The S.U.P.E.R.P.A.C.M.A.N. boasts a larger power output (up to [color=orange][protodata="PortableGeneratorSuperPacman" comp="FuelGenerator" member="MaxTargetPower" format="N0"/] W[/color]) and longer runtime at maximum output, but scales down to lower outputs less efficiently.

  They connect directly to [color=yellow]MV[/color] or [color=orange]HV[/color] [textlink="power cables" link="VoltageNetworks"], and are able to switch between them for flexibility.

  The S.U.P.E.R.P.A.C.M.A.N and P.A.C.M.A.N require uranium sheets and plasma sheets as fuel, respectively.
</Document>
