<Document>
  # Power
  Power is the lifeblood of the station.
  Without it, the station will quickly fall into chaos.
  Engineers are responsible for maintaining the station's power grid, ensuring that power is supplied, distributed, and all departments are satisfied.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SingularityGenerator" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TeslaGenerator" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AmeController" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SMESBasic" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SubstationBasic" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="APCBasic" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  There are many different aspects to Space Station 14's power system simulation, as well as Engineering's intended gameplay.

  Some important information to keep in mind includes:
  - Station [textlink="generators" link="Generators"] are tiered and follow a hierarchy. The lower the tier, the less they are sustainable, but the easier they are to setup. The higher the tier, the more sustainable they are, but the more complex they are to setup.
  - Space Station 14 features [textlink="voltage networks" link="VoltageNetworks"], which distribute power across the station and are stepped down in voltage by machines, so they can be used by other machines.
  - Power [textlink="generators" link="Generators"] have [textlink="ramping" link="Ramping"], which means they take time to match the grid's demand to their supply.

  ## Starting Out
  At the start of the shift, the station is running off of purely [textlink="battery" link="PowerStorage"] power.
  This will at most last 5-10 minutes, depending on the station's power draw.

  To extend this, you can start up the station's [textlink="Antimatter Engine" link="AME"], or [textlink="AME." link="AME"]
  This will extend the runtime of the station's batteries by a significant amount, giving you more time to setup the station's higher-tier [textlink="generators." link="Generators"]
  You can extend this even further by setting up [textlink="solar panels" link="SolarPanels"], which generate power for free.

  After setting up the [textlink="AME" link="AME"] and [textlink="Solars" link="SolarPanels"], you should be generating a decent amount of power.

  Now that you've bought yourself time, you can focus on setting up higher-tier [textlink="generators" link="Generators"] like the [textlink="Singularity Engine" link="SingularityEngine"], which can provide power for the rest of the shift.

</Document>
