<Document>
# Gravitational Singularity Engine

The Gravitational Singularity Engine can yield infinite power, with no fueling required. It can also destroy the whole station with equal ease. It uses a Particle Accelerator to fire high energy particles at a Singularity Generator to form a singularity. The singularity then pulses radiation which is absorbed by Radiation Collectors.

## Setting it up

The Gravitational Singularity Engine requires 4 subsystems to work properly:

## Gravitational singularity generator
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SingularityGenerator"/>
</Box>
The generator should be anchored at the center of the containment area since this is where the singularity will appear at.

## Containment field generators and emitters
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emitter"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentFieldGenerator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentField"/>
</Box>
The emitters connect to MV cables and fire lasers as long as they have power and are turned on.
Fire emitters at containment field generators to activate them.
If two containment field generators are active, in range and in the same cardinal axis, a containment field will appear.
The containment field will repell the singularity, keeping it from escaping, and yield a little bit of power every time anything bounces off of them. 
Emitter lasers and containment field can cause damage, avoid touching them when active.

## Radition collectors
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RadiationCollector"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaTank"/>
</Box>
They connect to HV cables and generate power from nearby radiation sources when turned on. 
Radiation collectors require a tank full of gaseous plasma in order to operate.
Continous radiation exposure will gradually convert the stored plasma into tritium, so replace depleted plasma tanks with fresh ones to maintain a high power output.

## Particle accelerator

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEndCap"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox" Caption="PA computer"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorFuelChamber"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableHV"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorPowerBox"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterStarboard" Caption="Starboard Emitter"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterFore" Caption="Fore Emitter"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterPort" Caption="Port Emitter"/>
</Box>

The Particle Accelerator (PA) is a multi-tile structure that launches accelerated particles from its emitters. Its emitters should always face the gravitational singularity generator.
Some stations already have an unfinished PA. To complete, first ensure there is HV cable beneath the PA power box, anchor all parts, then add LV cable to each part.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableApcStack"/>
</Box>
Then use a screwdriver to screw back the panels.
Scan parts using the PA control computer to check if it's operational. If it shows up as incomplete, examine for what's missing.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox"/>
</Box>

## Turing on the Gravitational Singularity Engine

[color=#a4885c]Do not[/color] turn the PA on unless all other subsystems are working properly.

Turn power on using the PA control computer. Set strength to an appropiate level. Currently the only appropriate level is [color=#f0684d]1[/color], anything above that will ensure that singularity grows too strong to handle.
The higher the output stength is set on PA control computer, the bigger the singularity will be.

The PA will now draw power from the power net and start firing particles at the Gravitational singularity generator. 

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile" Caption=""/>
</Box>

A singularity will soon appear at the position of the Gravitational singularity generator.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Singularity"/>
</Box>

If no particle is hitting the singularity generator, the singularity will start to slowly decay until it disappear.

## Safety
Singularity emits radiation around it, so always keep a distance. Consider getting radiation shielding gear beforehand. Seek medical attention if experiencing health issues.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitEngineering"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClosetRadiationSuit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterSuitRad"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GeigerCounter"/>
</Box>

A singularity might move around, but the containment field will repel it.
If a singularity escapes its containment field, often referred to as a "singuloose," it will attract and then consume everything in its way.

In such circumstances, there is little to be done other than running in the opposite direction.
</Document>