<Document>
  # Singularity Engine
  The Singularity Engine is a powerful generator that uses a contained singularity to produce energy for the station.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SingularityGenerator"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Singularity"/>
  </Box>

  It generates power by collecting the radiation emitted by the singularity using Radiation Collectors and gaseous plasma.

  ## Starting the Singularity Engine
  To start the Singularity Engine, engineers must follow these steps:
  - Place the Singularity Generator in the middle of the containment field. Some stations start with the generator already in place, while others require engineers to bring it from cold storage.
  - Turn on the four Containment Field Generators.
  - Turn on and lock the Emitters.
  - Confirm that the Containment Field Generators have created a Containment Field around the Singularity.
  - Turn on the Radiation Collectors. These require plasma to produce power. They might not come fueled, so be sure to refill them.
  - Construct the Particle Accelerator.
  - Turn on the Particle Accelerator Control Computer and set the power level to the desired power level.

  Once these steps are complete, the Singularity Engine will start producing power for the station.
  Be sure to monitor the singularity's power level and containment field to prevent it from escaping and destroying the station.
  Check in to refill the collectors often, as they will run out of plasma over time.

  ## Containment Field
  To prevent the singularity from escaping and destroying the station, engineers must contain it within a Containment Field.

  It is suggested to use a max size containment field for the singularity. Any smaller and the singularity may outgrow its field and escape.

  Containment pylons should be arranged in a square, with 7 tiles of spacing between each pylon.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentFieldGenerator" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentField" Caption="" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentFieldGenerator" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  ## Power Levels and Decay
  Because singularities emit radiation, they decay, losing power over time.

  To counter this decay, the Particle Accelerator emits particles that collide with the singularity, feeding and sustaining it.

  Singularities have defined power levels, which determine their radiation output.
  Engineers can increase or decrease the singularity's power level by adjusting the power level on the Particle Accelerator Control Computer.

  Particle Accelerators normally operate between power levels 1 and 3, which translate to a power level of 1 to 3 on the singularity.

  Power levels also determine how big the singularity is, with higher power levels sustaining larger singularities capable of producing more power.

  ## Producing Power
  The Singularity Engine produces power by capturing the radiation emitted by it using Radiation Collectors.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RadiationCollector"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaTank"/>
  </Box>
  They require gaseous plasma to function. The plasma containers attached to the collectors must be filled with plasma to produce power.

  You can turn on the collectors by interacting with them using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="Use"][/bold][/color].

  You can also eject the tank by interacting with the collector using [color=yellow][bold][keybind="AltActivateItemInWorld"][/bold][/color].
  From here, you can refill the tank with plasma using a plasma canister and reinsert it into the collector.

  The maximum power the radiation collector can produce is determined by:
  - The amount of radiation it is capturing (which is effectively the Singularity's power level),
  - and the amount of plasma it has in its connected tank.

  Over time, the collector will drain the tank of plasma, which reduces it's effective power output.
  Eventually, the tank will be empty, and the collector will stop producing power. Be sure to refill the tank often!

  ## Radiation Protection
  The singularity emits a massive amount of radiation, which can kill crew members who are not wearing proper protection.
  Be sure to wear a radiation suit or an engineering hardsuit when working near the singularity.
  This won't completely negate the radiation, but it will reduce the damage you take.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitEngineering"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClosetRadiationSuit"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterSuitRad"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GeigerCounter"/>
  </Box>

  The Chief Engineer has a special hardsuit that negates all radiation damage, which allows them to work near the singularity without fear of accumulating radiation damage over time.

  ## Singularity Properties
  The Singularity has several properties, which both make it dangerous and useful for power generation:
  - It has a strong gravitational pull that can suck in objects and crew members.
  - It has an event horizon, which can permanently destroy any object that touches it, whether it be a crew member or station equipment. Any object swallowed by the singularity is lost forever, and feeds the singularity.
  - It constantly emits radiation that can harm crew members who aren't wearing proper protection.
  - The singularity can decay over time, losing power and radiation output.

  ## Loosed Singularity (Singuloose)
  If the singularity escapes its containment field, it will begin to consume the station, destroying everything in its path.
  The more it consumes, the larger it grows, making it harder to potentially contain it again.

  The singularity can be destroyed by firing antiparticles at it using a Portable Particle Decelerator, but this is a risky and dangerous operation that requires careful planning and execution.
  Often multiple decelerators firing at once are needed to destroy a singularity.

  Portable Particle Decelerators can be either researched and made by the Research Department, or they can be bought from Cargo.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponParticleDecelerator"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
