<Document>
  # Singularity / Tesla Engine

  The Singularity Engine / Tesla Engine can yield [color=#a4885c]infinite power[/color], with no fueling required. It can also [color=red]destroy the whole station[/color] with equal ease. It uses a Particle Accelerator to fire high energy particles at a Singularity Generator to form a singularity or ball lightning.
  The singularity then pulses radiation which is absorbed by Radiation Collectors, or the ball lightning then zaps nearby tesla coils and grounding rods to provide power.

  # Setting it up

  Both engines requires 4 subsystems to work properly; two are shared between both engines:

  ## Containment field generators and Emitters
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emitter"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentFieldGenerator"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentField"/>
  </Box>
  The emitters connect to MV cables and fire lasers as long as they have power and are turned on.
  Fire the emitters at enabled containment field generators to activate them.
  If two containment field generators are active, in range and are in the same cardinal axis, a containment field will appear.
  The containment field will repel the singularity or tesla, keeping it from escaping, and yield a little bit of power every time anything bounces off of them.

  The emitter lasers and the containment fields can also cause damage and/or cause you to be sent flying into deep space; [color=#a4885c]avoid touching them[/color] when active.
  It is recommended to [color=#a4885c]lock the emitters[/color] with [keybind="AltActivateItemInWorld"/], to prevent any break-in no-gooders from loosing the singularity or tesla by simply switching off the field.

  Teslas can have significantly smaller containment fields than singularity containment fields; adjusting field size is recommended, as the tesla becomes easier to keep watch on in a simply 3x3 field setup.

  ## Particle accelerator

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEndCap" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorFuelChamber" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableMV" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorPowerBox" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterStarboard" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterFore" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterPort" Caption="" Margin="0"/>
  </Box>

  The Particle Accelerator (PA) is a multi-tile structure that launches accelerated particles from its emitters. Its emitters should always face the generator.
  Some stations already have an unfinished PA. To complete it, first ensure there is a MV cable beneath the PA power box, anchor all the parts, and then add an LV cable to each part.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableApcStack"/>
  </Box>
  Then use a screwdriver to screw back the panels.
  [color=#a4885c]Scan parts[/color] using the PA control computer to check if it's operational (the PA will not function if you do not scan it!). If it shows up as incomplete, examine what's missing.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox"/>
  </Box>

  The other two subsystems are unique to each other:

  ## Gravitational singularity generator or Ball lightning generator
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SingularityGenerator"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TeslaGenerator"/>
  </Box>
  The generator should be anchored at the center of the containment area, since this is where the singularity/tesla should appear at.

  ## Radiation collectors or Tesla coils
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RadiationCollector"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaTank"/>
  </Box>
  The radiation collectors connect to HV cables and generate power from nearby radiation sources when turned on.
  Radiation collectors require a tank full of gaseous plasma in order to operate.
  Continous radiation exposure will gradually convert the stored plasma into tritium, so replace depleted plasma tanks with fresh ones regularly to maintain a high power output.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TeslaCoil"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TeslaGroundingRod"/>
  </Box>
  The tesla coils connect to HV cables and provide a stream of power after being zapped by the ball lightning.
  However, tesla coils usually do not fully absorb the lightning strike, and the grounding rods are required to prevent lighting from arcing to and obliterating nearby machines.
  Do note that one grounding rod is not a foolproof solution; get [color=#a4885c]at least 4 rods[/color] around the containment field to make it mathematically unlikely for the tesla to escape.
  As the ball lightning zaps tesla coils, they will degrade from wear; make sure to [color=#a4885c]weld them[/color] every now and then to keep generating power.

  ## Turning on the Engines

  [color=red]Do not[/color] turn the PA on unless all the other subsystems are working properly and there is enough power to start the engine.

  Turn power on using the PA control computer. Set the strength to an appropriate level. The higher the output stength is set on PA control computer, the bigger the singularity will be.

  Currently, the output power does not affect the ball lightning, beyond giving the ball lightning extra orbs around it.

  The PA will now draw power from the power net and start firing particles at the generators.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticlesProjectile" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A singularity or ball lightning will soon appear at the position of the Gravitational singularity generator.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Singularity"/>
    or
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TeslaEnergyBall"/>
  </Box>

  If no particles are hitting the singularity, the singularity will start to slowly decay until it disappears.
  This is not the case for the tesla; feel free to disconnect the PA after the tesla has been set up.

  ## Safety
  The singularity emits a large amount of radiation around it, so always keep a distance from it. Consider getting [color=yellow]radiation shielding gear[/color] beforehand. Seek medical attention if you are experiencing health issues.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitEngineering"/>
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClosetRadiationSuit"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterSuitRad"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GeigerCounter"/>
  </Box>

  The singularity might move around, but the containment field will repel it.

  The tesla creates large bolts of lightning around it, so make sure to wear insuls before approaching it. If you aren't, and it zaps you, pray that the ball lightning doesn't stunlock you and eventually send you into crit.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHandsGlovesColorYellow"/>
  </Box>
  If a singularity or tesla escapes its containment field, often referred to as a "singuloose" or "tesloose" respectively, it will attract and then consume everything in its way, growing larger as it does so, or it will begin to obliterate every machine in its path, and shock all crew personnel.

  In such circumstances, there is little to be done other than running in the opposite direction.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponParticleDecelerator"/>
  </Box>
  However, if science has happened to research [color=#D381C9]Portable Particle Decelerators[/color], or if cargo can order them in time, you may be able to stop the singularity from eating the whole station.
  Good luck on the tesla, though; it is merely too powerful to recontain after breaching.
</Document>
