<Document>
  # Thermomachines
  Thermomachines are devices that manipulate the temperature of gases within a pipe network or exposed atmosphere.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SpaceHeater" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineHeater" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineFreezer" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  They are essential for maintaining the temperature of gasses for various applications.

  All thermomachines work by using electrical power to preform work on the atmosphere to either heat or cool it. The amount of work they do is directly related to the amount of power they consume.

  Thermomachines also have an efficiency coefficient, which determines how much work they can do per unit of power consumed.

  To prevent overshooting their target value, thermomachines will scale back their heating/cooling power as they approach the target temperature. However, they will still consume the same amount of electrical power, even when idle.

  All thermomachines have a target temperature tolerance of 2 K, meaning they will stop heating or cooling when the temperature is within 2 K of the target temperature.

  ## Space Heater
  The space heater is a portable temperature control unit that preforms work to heat or cool gas in the atmosphere it's exposed to.
  It's a simple and effective way to maintain the temperature of a room, without having to build a pipenet or other system.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SpaceHeater"/>
  </Box>

  They can be commonly found in Atmospherics, although the relevant machine board can be printed at a circuit imprinter, commonly found in Science.

  The space heater can cool to as low as -10°C (263.15 K) and heat to as high as 40°C (313.15 K).

  It also has three power settings, which determine how much power it consumes and how much work it does.
  - Low: 1750 W
  - Medium: 3500 W
  - High: 7000 W

  For space heaters, heating is 100% efficient, while cooling is only 90% efficient.

  Botany or science will often request these to maintain the temperature of their plants or department.

  ## Pipenet Thermomachines (Freezer and Heater)
  Pipenet thermomachines are more powerful stationary temperature control units that can be used to heat or cool gas in a pipenet.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineHeater"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineFreezer"/>
  </Box>

  They draw 5000 W of power and can heat or cool gas in a pipenet to as high as 593.15 K (320°C) or as low as 73.15 K (-200°C).

  Heaters are 95% efficient, while freezers are 390% efficient. That's almost 4 watts of cooling for the power of 1! Bluespace technology at its finest.

  You can swap the mode of the thermomachine by deconstructing it and using a screwdriver on its board. The board can be printed at a circuit imprinter, commonly found in Science.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineFreezer" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineFrame" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ThermomachineFreezerMachineCircuitBoard" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Screwdriver" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ThermomachineHeaterMachineCircuitBoard" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineFrame" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineHeater" Caption=""/>

  </Box>

  ## Thermomachines from Hell
  Science can research more powerful thermomachines, aptly called hellfire heaters and freezers. These machines are much more powerful than their standard counterparts, but they also consume more power.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineHellfireHeater"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineHellfireFreezer"/>
  </Box>

  These machines draw 40,000 W of power and can heat or cool gas in a pipenet to as high as 1193.15 K (920°C) or as low as 23.15 K (-250°C).

  However, they also leak 15% of their energy to the surrounding environment, heating or cooling the exposed atmosphere respectively. This is 6000 W of heat or cooling, which can be dangerous if not properly managed.

</Document>
