<Document>
  # Turnstiles
  Turnstiles are used to control access to different areas of the station in one direction without allowing people to gain access by "tailgating" another user.

  These structures are most commonly used as access control structures for GenPop prison configurations.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Turnstile" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Turnstiles can be used by colliding with the turnstile from the correct entry direction.
  Inspection of the turnstile will show an arrow that points to the side of the turnstile in which entry is allowed.

  If access levels are configured on the turnstile,they will only grant entry if you have an ID card with the correct access level.
  The ID card must be in your hand or in your ID slot.
  In the case of having multiple IDs, the turnstile will check them all when you try to open it.
  This behavior is also the same for IDs in a PDA.

  The access level required to pass through the turnstile can be modified using an Access Configurator,
  or by using a Multitool on the door electronics for the turnstile (which requires partial deconstruction).

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AccessConfigurator" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Multitool" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorElectronics" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Turnstiles do not block gas flow, and may be paired with [textlink="firelocks" link="FireAndGasControl"] to protect
  and seal off areas in case of a [textlink="hull breach" link="Spacing"] or a [textlink="fire." link="Fires"]

  ## Bolting
  Turnstiles can be bolted to prevent passage and bypassing via tools. When this occurs, the turnstile will display
  red lights on the top of the turnstile frame.

  Turnstiles cannot be set to emergency access mode.

  ## Remote Control
  The bolts of turnstiles can be controlled remotely, either by the station AI or by using a Door Remote.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlayerStationAiEmpty" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]The Station AI, which has remote control over all airlocks and turnstiles.[italic][/color]
  </Box>

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteEngineering" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteCommand" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteMedical" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteService" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteSecurity" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorRemoteResearch" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]Precious door remotes. With unlimited power...[italic][/color]
  </Box>


  Department heads usually get door remotes for their respective department.

  They can bolt turnstiles with line of sight using these remotes.

  ## Linking
  Turnstiles have no [textlink="device link" link="Networking"] functionality.

  ## Wiring
  Turnstiles have internal wiring under their maintenance panel, which can be opened using a screwdriver.
  Each wire controls some aspect of the turnstile's functionality.
  When you either pulse, cut, or mend the wire, it will affect the turnstile in different ways.

  The lights next to the wires will indicate the status of the wire:
  - A steady light indicates that the system is functioning as normal.
  - A flashing light indicates that the system is malfunctioning. It is either not working or is behaving not as intended.

  Below is a list of the wires and their functions:

  [color=#a4885c]Bolt Wire (BOLT)[/color]
  - [color=yellow]Pulse the wire[/color]: Bolts or unbolts the door.
  - [color=red]Cut the wire[/color]: Bolts the door.
  - [color=green]Mend the wire[/color]: Does nothing.
  - [italic]Note: The bolts will be unable to actuate if the solenoid is bypassed or malfunctioning.[/italic]

  [color=#a4885c]Solenoid Wire (SOLN)[/color]
  - [color=yellow]Pulse the wire[/color]: Bypasses the solenoid for a short time.
  - [color=red]Cut the wire[/color]: Bypasses the solenoid.
  - [color=green]Mend the wire[/color]: Restores the normal function of the solenoid.
  - [italic]Note: The turnstile mechanism can be forced with tools while the solenoid is bypassed or malfunctioning![/italic]

  [color=#a4885c]Log Wire (LOG)[/color]
  - [color=yellow]Pulse the wire[/color]: Temporary disables turnstile logging.
  - [color=red]Cut the wire[/color]: Disables turnstile logging.
  - [color=green]Mend the wire[/color]: Re-enables turnstile logging.

  [color=#a4885c]Bolt Light (BLIT)[/color]
  - [color=yellow]Pulse the wire[/color]: Turns the system off temporarily, or turns it back on.
  - [color=red]Cut the wire[/color]: Prevents the bolt light from turning on, which communicates if the door is bolted or not.
  - [color=green]Mend the wire[/color]: Turns the system back on.

  [color=#a4885c]AI Access Light (AIA)[/color]
  - [color=yellow]Pulse the wire[/color]: Does nothing.
  - [color=red]Cut the wire[/color]: Disables AI access. The AI can no longer bolt the door.
  - [color=green]Mend the wire[/color]: Re-enables AI access.

  ## Security

  Just like [textlink="airlocks" link="Airlocks"], turnstiles can be [textlink="upgraded" link="AirlockSecurity"] to protect the
  internal wiring of the turnstile.

  ### Increasing Physical Security

  A basic turnstile can be upgraded to protect its internal wiring with steel plating.

  To upgrade a basic turnstile with steel plating, you will require the following materials:
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Screwdriver" Caption="Screwdriver"/>
    </Box>
    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetSteel" Caption="2 steel sheets"/>
    </Box>
    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Welder" Caption="Welder"/>
    </Box>
  </Box>

  To perform the upgrade:
  -	Use the screwdriver to open the turnstile maintenance panel.
  -	Add the steel sheets to the turnstile.
  -	Weld the steel sheets into place.
  -	Close the maintenance panel using the screwdriver.

  ### Adding Electrical Deterrence

  Since the turnstiles are often used in GenPop prison configurations, a little electrical deterrence is often used to
  prevent tampering with the turnstile's sensitive wiring.

  You can add an electrified grille to a turnstile. This upgrade can be performed on a basic turnstile, or on a turnstile
  previously upgraded with steel plating.

  To upgrade a turnstile with an electrified grille, you will require:
  <Box HorizontalAlignment="Stretch">
    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Screwdriver" Caption="Screwdriver"/>
    </Box>
    <Box>
      <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PartRodMetal" Caption="2 metal rods"/>
    </Box>
  </Box>

  To perform the upgrade:
  -	Use the screwdriver to open the turnstile maintenance panel.
  -	Add the metal rods to the turnstile.
  -	Close the maintenance panel using the screwdriver.
  - Ensure that active electrical cable is routed directly under the turnstile.

  [bold]Warning! It is not recommended to attempt reversal of this modification without first turning off the power
  or wearing proper personal protective equipment.[/bold]
</Document>
