<Document>
# Security SOP

These procedures apply to all security members, unless otherwise stated in their specific SOP

1. Long guns shall not be taken outside the brig on [color=#00a933]Code Green[/color]. Long guns are any firearms that are not pistols or revolvers.

2. A maximum of 1 long gun (with permit) and 1 sidearm (pistol or revolver) may be carried on [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color] or above. Only a sidearm and disabler may be carried on [color=#00a933]Code Green[/color].

3. Long guns will be issued on a permit basis on [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color], and are allowed to all security personnel on [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color]. Disabler SMGs are not considered long guns.

4. Weapons must remain holstered unless in active pursuit or on [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color].

5. Security personnel are required to state the reason for an arrest before any action may be taken against a suspect. This does not apply on [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color], or if a suspect flees when approached.

6. Security personnel must attempt to bring suspects to the brig uncuffed. This does not apply on [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color], or if a suspect has already fled or become uncooperative.

7. Security personnel may not request entry to a department, unless in pursuit of a suspect, or on [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color] or [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color].

8. Searches may be conducted randomly on [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color] and [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color], and on [color=#00a933]Code Green[/color] with an applicable warrant. Crew refusing searches on [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color] or [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color] may be detained.

9. All security personnel must wear at least one piece of an official security uniform at all times. An official security uniform is defined as: The security jumpsuit/skirt, the senior security jumpsuit/skirt, the security winter coat, the trooper uniform, or job specific variants of these for the Warden, Head of Security or Brigmedic.

10. Security personnel should refrain from wearing hardsuits or magboots unless an imminent threat or massive station damage is present.

11. Security personnel may forcefully relocate crew members to their departments on [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color], [color=#8d1d75]Code Violet[/color], [color=#acb20c]Code Yellow[/color] or [color=#ec9ba4]Code Gamma[/color].
</Document> 