<Document>
  # Cryogenics
  Cryogenics can be a bit daunting to understand, but hopefully through a quick run through of this diagram, you'll learn how to work it! So, let's go over what each part does:

  - Air in: Air comes in here through the distro or an air tank, giving those inside something to breathe, and the freezer something to chill.
  - Gas pump: Limits the network pressure, so those in the tube aren't crushed.
  - Freezer: Chills the air, and by extension, patients in the tube, so Cryoxadone can activate.
  - Gas filters: Removes waste gas (Carbon Dioxide and Nitrous Oxide) from the loop, so patients don't suffocate.
  - Air out: Waste gasses go here, either into a storage tank, or into the waste network.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeBend" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeStraight" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeStraight" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeBend" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CloningPod" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="0"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasThermoMachineFreezerEnabled" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="0"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeBend" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="180"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasFilterFlipped" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasFilterFlipped" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeTJunction" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="180"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeTJunction" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="180"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeTJunction" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="270"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPort" Margin="-3" Caption="Air out" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeTJunction" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="180"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeBend" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="270"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPort"  Margin="-3" Caption="Air in" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPressurePump" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="90"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GasPipeBend" Caption="" Margin="-3" Rotation="270"/>
  </Box>

  Not every network will look like this, but hopefully, it's enough to give you the basic gist of how cryogenics functions.

  An important thing to note: winter clothing (and hardsuits) will make cryogenic treatment less, or completely, ineffective. Be sure to remove cold-preventative clothing before placing people in the pod.

  ## Using the Pod
  Once things have been set up, you're going to require a specific medication: Cryoxadone.
  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Cryoxadone"/>
  </Box>
  Cryoxadone heals all damage types when a patient is chilled (except Suffocation and Genetic damage!), and can either be pre-adminsitered (with a pill), or loaded into the cell directly with a beaker.
  Do note; as patients won't begin to heal until they've been chilled to the appropriate temperature, it may be worthwhile to wait a bit before placing a beaker inside the pod.

  ## Additional Information:

  - The standard pressure for a gas pump is 101.24 kpa. Cryoxadone works at under 170K, but it is standard practice to set the freezer to 73K for faster freezing.
  - In the event that a patient has excessive Suffocation damage, or has been afflicted with Genetic damage, mix in the related chemical below in order to keep healing them:
  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Dexalin"/>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="DexalinPlus"/>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Doxarubixadone"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
