<Document>
# Medical Doctor
It's time to heal. Or at least, try to heal, anyway. Medical Doctors are the primary caretakers of every boo boo and ouchie crewmembers get on the station, be it a small scratch, or boiled skin.

This guide will give you a basic outline of the treatment options you have available, triage, and other avenues of care.

## The Basics
There are two ways to tell what's ailing someone: Taking a scan (with a health analyzer or a medical PDA), or examining them, with a shift-click, and clicking the heart symbol.

Using a health analyzer is often more powerful than examination, as some things (such as poison, or radiation) don't show up on examination. However, using an analyzer has its drawbacks, as it makes noise and uses up a battery.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignExamroom" Caption="examine patient"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalPDA"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalInternPDA" Caption="intern PDA"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldHealthAnalyzer"/>
</Box>

## Medication and Treatment Options
Before we go any further, it's probably a good idea to go over damage types, and what will heal them. The wiki has more extensive info available, but these are commonly used.

An important note: Most medication has an overdose level, which will cause harm to your patient. Chemicals also take time to metabolise in pill form, if you want things to act quickly, use a syringe.

- Brute Damage: Bicaridine or Bruise Packs
- Burn Damage: Dermaline or Ointment
- Toxin (Poison): Dylovene
- Toxin (Radiation) Hyronalin or Arithrazine
- Airloss: Dexaline or Inaprovaline
- Bloodloss: Dexaline (Examine the patient, if pale, they still need blood or iron.)
- Bleeding: Tranexamic acid and Gauze (Bleeding can also be cauterized with burn damage.)

Many stations are stocked with kits in storage, and all medics have some equipment in their starting belt.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitFilled"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitBruteFilled" Caption="brute kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitRadiationFilled" Caption="radiation kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitBurnFilled" Caption="burn kit"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedkitToxinFilled" Caption="toxin kit"/>
</Box>

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmergencyMedipen"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bloodpack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Gauze"/>
</Box>

## Basic Treatment and Triage
Examine your patient, and note down the important details: Are they alive? Bleeding? What type of damage?

If alive, treat them as best as you can. Patients are in critical condition at 100 damage, and dead at 200. Keep this in mind when choosing how to treat them. Emergency Pens and Epinephrine are often used to keep patients stable.

If possible, buckle them to a medical bed, if you need time to treat them, strap them to a stasis bed instead. Just keep in mind that metabolism (and by extension, healing chemicals) are slowed to a crawl when on stasis, they'll need to be taken off of it for the medicine to be effective. (But Blood Packs, Ointment, and Brute packs all work as normal.)
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalBed"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StasisBed"/>
</Box>
## Assessing Corpses
You can't save them all, sometimes, death happens. Depending on the [color=#a4885c]status[/color] of the body, there are a few things that can be done.

1. Do they have a soul attached? You can tell if, when examining, the following phrase is displayed: "Their soul has departed." If this isn't displayed, there is still a player who can be revived.

2. Is the body rotting? If it is, sadly, they'll have to be cloned. A rotting body can't be brought back with a defibrillator. (See Cloning)

3. If they have a soul, and aren't rotten, it's possible to revive them. Consider storing the body in a morgue tray if you don't have enough time to revive someone, as the body will rot if you wait too long.

## Revival
Not counting airloss, Defibrillator's can be used to revive patients under 200 total damage. Chemicals don't metabolise in the dead, but brute packs and ointment can still patch them up. Use them to bring their numbers down enough for revival.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Brutepack"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Defibrillator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment"/>
</Box>

</Document>
