<Document>

## Character Records

Entries can only be written in the character customization menu and not during
a round. It is not required that you make any records or entries; interact with
this feature as much or as little as you want!

You can create records for your characters in the records tab of the character
creator. Simply fill in the values and save. Entries should typically be
written from the perspective of a CentComm official or other supervisor.

The records available from all records computers include height, weight, age,
species, pronouns, job (in-round), and place of residency.

## General/Employment Entries

Employee Entries should include your character's education, previous jobs, and
anything that you think Nanotrasen would log about your character's past that is
employment-related. This also serves as a catch-all for any non-medical, non-security
entries that are on file.

The other records available here are the length of time your character has worked at
Nanotrasen in years, and if your character has been approved for work.

## Medical Entries

Medical Entries should include anything a doctor should know before treating
your character; major surgeries, prescriptions, and any psychological evaluations.

The other records available here are allergies/drug allergies, other medical
concerns—such as if you play with random unrevivable and wish to detail such with a lore
explanation—and instructions for what to do with your character's corpse.

## Security Entries

Security Entries should include any major arrests/incidents your character has
had in the past or while working with Nanotrasen. Minor incidents should
generally be avoided.

Other records available here are identifying features, plus the standard Criminal
Records Computer data for gameplay.

## Accessing Records
You can access the records of your crewmates in-game from their respective consoles.
These consoles are typically found in their respective departments!

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerMedicalRecords" Caption="Medical"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerCriminalRecords" Caption="Security"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerStationRecords" Caption="Station"/>
</Box>
</Document>
