<Document>
# Gravitational Singularity Engine

Gravitational Singularity Engine can yield infinite power, no fueling required. It can also destroy whole station with equal ease. It uses a particle accelerator to fire high energy particles at a singularity generator to spawn a singularity. The singularity then pulses radiation which is absorbed by radiation collectors.


## Setting up the Gravitational Singularity Engine

The Gravitational Singularity Engine requires 4 subsystems to work properly:

### Gravitational singularity generator
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SingularityGenerator"/>
</Box>
Gravitational singularity generator should be anchored at the center of the containment area. This is where the singularity will spawn at.

### Containment field generators and emitters
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emitter"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentFieldGenerator"/>
</Box>
The emitters connects to MV cable and shoot lasers indefintely when turned on. Aim emitters at containment field generators, and turn them on. If all containment field generators are active, a containment field will appear.
The containment field will repell the singularity, keeping it from escaping. The emitter lasers and containment field can cause damage, avoid touching them when active.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ContainmentField"/>
</Box>


### Radition collectors
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RadiationCollector"/>
</Box>
Radiation collectors connect to HV cable, and generate power from radiation when turned on.

### Particle accelerator
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterLeft"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterCenter"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEmitterRight"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorEndCap"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorFuelChamber"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorPowerBox"/>
</Box>

The Particle accelerator is a multi-tile structure that spawns and controls the singularity. The 3 PA emitters should face the Gravitational singularity generator, and be followed by PA fuel chamber,PA power box and PA end cap. 
To make it operational, anchor all parts down, add LV cables to every part.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CableApcStack"/>
</Box>
Then use a scrwdriver to screw back the panels.
Scan parts using the PA control computer
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ParticleAcceleratorControlBox"/>
</Box>
to check if it's operational. 

## Turing on the Gravitational Singularity Engine

[color=#a4885c]Do not[/color] turn the PA on unless all other subsystems are all working properly.

Turn power on using the PA control computer. Set strength to an appropiate level.

The PA will start firing particles towards the Gravitational singularity generator. 

A singularity will soon appear.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Singularity"/>
</Box>

##Safety
Singularity emitts radiation around it, always keep a distance from it.

If a singularity escapes its containment field, it's called a "singuloose". It will attract and then consume everything in its way.

In such circumstances, there is little to be done other than running in the opposite direction.
</Document>
