<Document>
  # Section A: Core Rules
  
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.
  
  [color=#a4885c]1. Engage with the rules in good faith, and respect admin decisions.[/color]
  
  The rules are not perfect. They attempt to communicate what the administration team intends to allow and disallow, but there are likely loopholes that can be "lawyered". Do not attempt to manipulate the interpretation of rules to suit your personal goals, or to degrade the experience for other players.
  
  - Admins can disregard and override any and all of these rules if they deem it in the best interest of the current round, server, and/or community at large.
  - Rules can be bent if it's funny, but watch out. If you want to bend a rule, always ask an admin for permission first through the use of AHelp.
  - Admin actions and interpretations of the rules can be contested through AHelp. Administrators will ban players they believe are an overall negative impact to the community, and will be held fully accountable if they exercise this privilege.

  [color=#a4885c]2. Don't be a dick.[/color]
  
  Don't do anything with the intent of negatively affecting another player's experience of the game. Killing players is allowed in some situations, even though it may negatively affect them, and dying is a part of SS14's gameplay, but you should not do anything to deliberately make another player have a bad time.
  
  - If you are impacted negatively by another player, or you are worried that your actions have negatively impacted another character beyond the bounds of what is reasonable in roleplay, you may choose to use the LOOC (Local Out Of Character) chat channel to check in with each other, and make sure that everyone is comfortable. Alternatively, you may contact an admin via AHelp.
  - Do not interact negatively with AFK ("SSD") players. Interactions to complete antagonist objectives, or duties like security searches/arrests, are always allowed.
  - Hate speech, bigotry, discrimination and harassment will not be tolerated.

  [color=#a4885c]3. Erotic roleplay (ERP) and overt sexual content are strictly prohibited.[/color]
  
  Romantic relationships between characters are acceptable (though they should never become the focus of a round/gameplay, see [textlink="Roleplay Rule 4" link="RoleplayRules"]). Erotic content is not allowed under any circumstances.
  
  - This includes comments not explicitly sexual in nature, but that contain words, phrases, or ideations that are deemed inappropriate by administration or players. Raunchy humour and insults are given some leeway; otherwise, this rule is strictly enforced.
  - If roleplay reaches a point where it has become sexual and/or uncomfortable, immediately stop and contact an administrator through AHelp.

  Examples:
  - [color=#449944]Good:[/color] Typing 'cum' in OOC chat
  - [color=#449944]Good:[/color] Making a reference to characters dating
  - [color=#449944]Good:[/color] Being affectionate in a mutually consensual way
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Emoting sexual acts
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Conversations of a predominantly sexual nature
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Emoting defecation or related acts

  [color=#a4885c]4. Do not exploit the game.[/color]
  
  Do not use exploits, cheats, macros or alt accounts.
  
  - This includes third party applications, known glitches and bugs, and any other applicable software to gain an advantage, avoid intended game/server mechanics, or harm server infrastructure.
  - Stream-sniping (the act of watching another player livestream the game while playing the game yourself) is strictly prohibited.
  - Any and all instances of the above will be met with an appeal-only ban. Please report bugs in the issues section of the GitHub.

  [color=#a4885c]5. Do not use dead chat or OOC chat for excessive complaining.[/color]
  
  SS14 is a game about dying. Discussing your own death and the status of your body to the exclusion of all else is not pleasant for other members of dead chat. Remember that this is just a game, and take a break if you find yourself upset.
  
  - If you believe another player has acted inappropriately or in violation of server rules, contact an admin through AHelp. 

  [color=#a4885c]6. Use AHelp to report rule violations.[/color]
  
  If at any time you suspect that someone is breaking the server rules, press F1 or the 'AHelp' button in the lobby to open the AHelp menu. Please give a moderately detailed report, including the names of involved parties where possible.
  
  - All AHelp messages are relayed to admins via Discord, even when they are not in game. Your AHelp not receiving a response does not mean it was not acted upon.
  - AHelp can also be used to ask for gameplay clarifications, or request admin intervention in the case of game-breaking bugs or glitches. If you are contacted by an admin through AHelp, it does not mean you've done something wrong.
</Document>