<Document>
  # Section C: Metashield
  
  This page will discuss a list of various information or items protected by our rules. Something that is "shielded" cannot be known by your character during a round until ANY of the "breaking" conditions happen. This also means your character cannot act upon shielded information. Doing so before the shield is broken is referred to as metagaming.

  Anytime a shield is broken, it applies for the remainder of the round, in all other instances, unless explicitly specified otherwise.

  ## Always Shielded:
  - Current gamemode, and any antagonists that could exist as a result.
  - Events experienced as a different character.
  - Any and all information related to the player of a character, or certain strategies a player may use as an antagonist.
  - Any information revealed while your character is in critical condition, asleep, dead, or a ghost.
  - Any information your character knew before death, if you become a ghost role mid-round.
  - The exact cause of your death. For the purposes of this shield, if you enter critical condition but are resuscitated before dying, you can remember what caused you to fall unconscious.
  - Events from prior rounds. NOTE: Events can be discussed, but they should not hold any bearing on the current round.

  ## Sometimes Shielded:
  [color=#a4885c]As an entity lacking crew-level intellect (such as an animal), the understanding of station functions, and how they may be sabotaged.[/color]
  This includes damaging or destroying critical infrastructure solely to gain a meta-tactical advantage.
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Being a Mouse Operative, Syndicat, or Ancestor Reinforcement.
  - Being uplifted through the use of Cognizine or Subjuzine.

  [color=#a4885c]The idea that certain High-Risk Items are desired specifically by the Syndicate, and are therefore likely targets of theft by Syndicate agents or other bad actors.
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Being a Traitor.
  - Being told of an item's status by a Traitor. This only applies to that particular item.
  
  Crew should protect High-Risk Items due to their status as valuable items, not due to their status as objectives.

  [color=#a4885c]The existence of Nuclear Operatives, beyond ludicrous propaganda that nobody would act on.[/color]
  This includes their goal of utter station destruction via a nuclear bomb.
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Discovering a Syndicate Hardsuit, or any variants.
  - Discovering a Nuclear Operative Shuttle
  - Being a Nuclear Operative.

  [color=#a4885c]The existence of implants used by the Syndicate.[/color]
  Implant checks cannot be performed unless there is adequate evidence or authorization from a member of Command, as outlined within Standard Operating Procedures.
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Discovering a non-NT implanter, identifiable by the black-and-red color scheme of the implanter itself.
  - Discovering a non-NT implant box.
  - Discovering or witnessing use of a non-NT implant.
  - Experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible.
  - Discovering an unlocked Uplink.

  [color=#a4885c]The existence of "chameleon" items, pieces of clothing or technology that can change their appearance.[/color]
  Even while this shield is active, the suspicion of items that may be fake or stolen is not shielded.
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Seeing any chameleon item change its appearance.
  - Finding holographic nanomachine fibers.
  - Experiencing a situation where absolutely no explanation is possible.
  - Discovering an unlocked Uplink.
  
  Testing clothing for chameleon status is always prohibited; items that are clearly chameleon can, however, be confiscated by Security.

  [color=#a4885c]The existence of items that have uses or functionality other than what their external appearance or examinable information would claim.[/color]
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Seeing the item behave differently than the expected behavior for the item
  - Seeing the item used for its hidden purpose
  - Experiencing a situation where absolutely no other explanation is possible
  - Discovering an unlocked Uplink.
  
  Stealth items should not be "tested" for their functionality, but items that are clearly producing some sort of stealth effect can be confiscated.

  [color=#a4885c]The idea that Syndicate agents, or other bad actors, have certain goals they have been tasked with accomplishing on the station, ranging from sabotage, to theft, to murder.[/color]
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Being a Traitor, Nuclear Operative, Space Ninja, Changeling or Heretic.
  - Being told of an antagonist's goals. This only applies to the goals that have been revealed to you.

  [color=#a4885c]The fact that Syndicate agents may possess a program, referred to as an Uplink, used to receive equipment from the Syndicate.[/color]
  These Uplinks are typically contained within PDAs, and may be "locked", preventing access and visibility. You have no way of confirming an Uplink exists within a PDA unless you see it yourself.
  
  [color=#ff0000]Breaking conditions:[/color]
  - Being a Security role.
  - Being a Command role.
  - Being a Traitor.

  ## Never Shielded:
  - The idea that the Nuclear Authorization Disk must be protected at all costs, and that it can be used to destroy the station by bad actors.
  - The fact that the Syndicate is hostile to Nanotrasen, and will occasionally deploy covert agents to spy on, sabotage, and assault Nanotrasen assets and associates.
  - The fact that the Syndicate possesses equipment of a similar grade to that accessible by NanoTrasen, such as firearms, armour, shuttles and silicons.
</Document>