<Document>
  # Server Rules
  <Box>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobFinfin" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  This is Impstation, the unofficial SS14 server for fans of RTVS. You must be at least 20 years old to play on this server. This server is an English-speaking community. You are free to use other languages in-character, but all discussion in out-of-character channels should be in English.

  This is a medium roleplay server. While playing the game, please enjoy telling an   interesting story alongside your fellow players while embracing the game's mechanics.

  Space Station 14 is a disaster simulator. Many rules are designed to require roleplay, and not all rules are intuitive. Please take the time to read and understand the rules before you play. Game admins will treat you as if you have read the rules, even if you have not. If you have any questions about the rules, please use the admin help menu by hitting F1 in-game or clicking the "AHelp" button in the lobby.
  
  Impstation's rules are divided into 4 categories. Use the text links below to navigate.

  ## Section A: Core Rules
  [textlink="Link to the Core Rules" link="CoreRules"]
  
  These rules apply at all times, including between rounds.
  - 1. Engage with the rules in good faith, and respect admin decisions.
  - 2. Don't be a dick.
  - 3. Erotic roleplay (ERP) and overt sexual content are strictly prohibited.
  - 4. Do not exploit the game.
  - 5. Do not use dead chat or OOC chat for excessive complaining.
  - 6. Use AHelp to report rule violations.

  ## Section B: Roleplay Rules 
  [textlink="Link to the Roleplay Rules" link="RoleplayRules"]
  
  These rules only apply during a round. 
  - 1. Roleplay a normal character.
  - 2. Use realistic character names.
  - 3. Communicate in-character.
  - 4. Play the role you are given.
  - 5. Do not prioritise "winning" over roleplaying.
  - 6. Follow reasonable escalation.
  - 7. If you die and get revived, you cannot use knowledge gained while dead or in critical condition.
  - 8. Do not metafriend or metagrudge.
  - 9. Do not behave like an antagonist unless the game tells you that you are one.
  
  ## Section C: Metashield
  [textlink="Link to the Metashield rules" link="MetashieldRules"]

  ## Section D: Command, Security, Antagonist, and Silicon Rules
  [textlink="Link to the Additional Role Rules" link="AdditionalRoleRules"]
</Document>