<Document>
        # Code Blue

        ## Called by:

        Any two Command members, HoS, or Captain.

        ## Conditions:

        There is a suspected threat on-board the station, or at a nearby location in space. This includes any evidence of hostile activity that has not damaged the station or crew. This may also include multiple eye witness testimonies.

        OR

        Confirmed Code Red threats have been properly handled or subsided on their own. It is recommended that, after 10+ minutes on Code Red without any hostile activity, Code Blue be called.

        ## Security:

        1. Weapons may be visible.
        
        2. Armory weapons are permitted outside of the brig on a selective basis. Should all of sec be required to use armory weapons, red alert should be called .
        
        3. Random searches are encouraged. Security personnel may detain any personnel refusing a random search to conduct the search.

        ## Secure Areas:

        1. Secure areas require an access permit, unless required by a staff job.
        
        2. Secure areas: Security department, EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator, All Engineering areas beyond the lobby, Vault, and areas requiring command access.
        
        3. Secure areas may be bolted if attempted unauthorized access is likely based on previous evidence.


        ## Engineering:

        1. A thorough check of all power sources is heavily encouraged.
        
        2. A thorough check of all atmospheric systems is required.

        ## Medical:

        Emergency access is recommended to be disabled from all medical entrances.

        ## General Crew:

        1. Personnel are to report any suspicious activity to the nearest member of Security, or use common radio if urgent.
        
        2. Personnel are highly encouraged to exercise caution, all crew should follow simple safety procedures (such as not going through Maintenance alone).
        
        3. Visitors to the station such as refugees are recommended to stay in public areas, for their safety.
        
        4. The Vault is not to be opened by non-command members. Exceptions for repairs, or storage of critical items will be made. All other access is by permit only.
        
        5. All personnel are highly recommended to set their suit sensors to coordinates.

        ## Command:

        1. A role-call of all department personnel should be conducted. Any missing members should be reported to security.
        
        2. A disabler or flash should be carried at all times.
        
        3. Non-security Command members may request with permit further armament.
</Document>