<Document>
        #  Code Red

        ## Called by:

        Any two Command members, or Captain.

        ## Conditions:

        There is a confirmed, hostile threat on-board the station or nearby in space. This threat should pose active, recognizable, danger to the station and/or crew at large.

        ## Security:

        1. Random searches are fully permitted and recommended. Security personnel may detain any personnel refusing a random search in order to conduct said search.
        
        2. Security personnel are to cooperate fully with any Central Command Staff (such as Emergency Response Teams) in order to eliminate the threat to the station.
        
        3. The security SOP will detail armament, armory, and safety procedures.

        ## Secure Areas:

        1. Secure areas require an access permit, unless required by a staff job.
        
        2. Secure areas: Security department, EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator, All Engineering areas beyond the lobby, Vault, and areas requiring command access.
        
        3. There are no restrictions on bolting Secure Areas. Secure Areas may be left bolted or unbolted at the discretion of Command personnel.
        
        4. Secure areas are not to be entered by non-command, unless required by their job.

        ## Medical:

        It is recommended that medical entrances be set to emergency access to allow crew members to heal themselves in emergencies.

        ## General Crew:

        1. Personnel are to follow the instructions of Security staff, so long as they are within the bounds of Space Law and are not acting against the general well-being of the station and its crew.
        
        2. Personnel are advised to shelter in place and comply with security's orders.

        ## Special Situations

        ## Confirmed Revolution

        1. All personnel are to comply with orders from Security, so long as said orders are lawful. Failure to do so is grounds for detainment and inspection of possessions, as well as possible Mindshield Implantation, at the discretion of the Head of Security, or Acting Head of Security.
        
        2. All personnel that are convicted of Medium Crimes or higher are to receive mandatory Mindshield Implantation. Similarly, if the number of suspected revolutionaries is more than twice the number of loyalists, the Head of Security or Acting Head of Security may order random implantation of crew members.
        
        3. Lethal force is fully authorized if the number of active revolutionaries is more than twice the number of loyalists, and said revolutionaries are actively hostile.

        ## Declarations of War

        1. All weapons restrictions are lifted.
        
        2. Cargo should focus on requesting as many weapons as possible. Security is to be prioritized for distribution, but regular personnel may also be armed.
        
        3. Science is to conduct research ASAP. This is not negotiable. Science should work in tandem with Cargo in order to fabricate the weapons and equipment required to defend the station.
        
        4. Barricades, glass, and traps are recommended to counter the threat.
        
        5. The Evacuation Shuttle may be called at the discretion of Command. If the station is not damaged after the fighting has subsided, it is recommended that the crew finish the shift.
</Document>