<Document>
        # Code Gamma

        ## Called by:

        Central Command. Use a Communications Console or Fax Machine in order to explain the situation. Remember, Gamma is rarely called, for good reason. Having a well-written, concise fax that explains the situation to the best of your ability, as well as why it deserves Code Gamma being called, signed and stamped by the Captain or Acting Captain, goes a long way towards ensuring Gamma is provided. Remember, this is for extreme emergencies only.

        ## Conditions:

        There is an existential threat to the station and crew, without central command intervention the station is likely to be lost.

        However, this threat is not dire enough to trigger destruction of the station.

        ## Security:

        1. Martial Law is enacted. Standard Operating Procedures and space law are suspended. Security personnel have authorization to perform any necessary actions to save the station. Personnel interfering with emergency procedures may be detained, and Security are cleared to use lethal force in response to any physical threat. Assault of Command, ERT, or Security, may be punished with immediate field execution.
        
        2. Random searches are fully permitted, allowed and encouraged. Security personnel may detain any personnel refusing a random search in order to conduct said search.
        
        3. The Armory should be deployed, and Security are to secure its contents and distribute them to Security personnel in order to handle the threat. Non-Security personnel (including members of the Legal Sub-Department) are not to receive armory weapons unless issued by the Warden, Head of Security, or Captain.
        
        4. Security personnel are to cooperate fully with any Central Command Staff (such as Emergency Response Teams) in order to eliminate the threat to the station.

        ## Secure Areas:

        1. Secure areas are limited to command, security, and Central Command personnel.
        
        2. Secure areas: Security department, EVA Storage, Tech Storage, Gravity Generator, All Engineering areas beyond the lobby, Vault, and areas requiring command access.
        
        3. Secure areas should be bolted down, but may be left unbolted by order of command.

        ## Medical:

        It is recommended that medical entrances be set to emergency access to allow personnel to heal themselves in emergencies.

        ## General Crew:

        1. All personnel are to set their suit sensors to coordinates.
        
        2. Personnel must shelter in their departments or closest safe area, unless specifically requested by Central Command personnel, Security, or Command members.
        
        2a. Exceptions will be made for crew who may have skills exceptionally useful. (Such as engineering, atmospheric, or medical personnel.)
        
        3. Visitors to the station are to remain inside the Bar, Library, or Dormitories.
        
        4. Personnel are to follow the instructions of Security staff, so long as they are within the bounds of Space Law and are not acting against the general well-being of the station and its crew. Failure to do so may lead to their arrest for Creating a Workplace Hazard.
</Document>