<Document>
# Antagonists

Antagonists are a drving force during a round of space station 14, usually creating conflict and defying the crew. Antagonists goals can vary, but they usually require some thievery, sabotage, or murder.

## Various Antagonists

Antagonists can take various forms. These include:
- Elite nuclear operatives, with the goal of infiltrating and destroying the station.
- Sneaky traitors disguised as normal crew, who assasinate crewmembers and steal high value items.
- Several non-humanoid creatures, who usually just try to bring down as many crewmembers as they can. 

## How to deal with them
Antagonists are a major threat to the station, and usually must be taken down through lethal or nonlethal means.

Traitors have access to an arsenal of dangerous gear. This gear is contraband, and possesion of it is enough to warrent a search or an arrest by security. If a potential traitor poses a threat, whether they are attacking people or possesing a lethal weapon or bomb, they should be taken down accordingly. Remember to follow escelation rules!

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRevolverPython" Caption="Syndicate python, "/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="C4" Caption="C-4 explosive, "/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emag" Caption="Electromagnetic sequencer"/>
</Box>


Nuclear operatives, or nukies, are usually a gang of 3-5 people in blood-red hardsuits. They are a station-wide threat. If you see theem you should tell as many people as you can so the station can prepare for a fight.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitSyndieCommander" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitSyndieElite" Caption="Several possible nukie hardsuits"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitSyndie" Caption=""/>
</Box>


Nonhuman critters like spiders, rat kings, and slimes will usually be attacking everybody, so prepare to use lethal force when you see one.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobGiantSpider" Caption="Giant Spider"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatKing" Caption="Rat King"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobAdultSlimesGreen" Caption="Slime"/>  
</Box>

</Document>
