<Document>
  # Minor Antagonists

  Most if not all Minor Antagonists are ghost-controlled roles that gives dead people new ways to cause chaos around the station. They are spawned by random events.

  # Revenant

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRevenant" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ectoplasm" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A Revenant is given powers to haunt the crew and steal life essence from them.

  ## Essence

  - Your [color=#a4885c]essence[/color] is your very own life force and a way to use abilities for a cost, don't let it drop to 0.
  - To gain [color=#a4885c]essence[/color] you first inspect various souls for their worth. More worthy souls grant more essence.
  However merely checking their worth isn't enough for collecting [color=#a4885c]essence[/color]. You must siphon it either when the victim is critical, dead, or sleeping.
  - A good start is to go to medical or dorms but be wary, you are vulnerable to attacks when you siphon a soul. Taking damage reduces your [color=#a4885c]essence[/color]! So plan your attacks wisely.

  ## Shop And Powers

  - Using [color=#a4885c]stolen essence[/color] gotten from siphoning souls, you can gain skills for mischief such as environmental destruction, electrical disruption, and electrocution through the shop.
  - Using powers leave you vulnerable to attacks for some time, plan ahead and prepare before attacking.

  # Rat King

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatKing" Scale="2.4" Caption="Normal Rat King"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatKingBuff" Caption="Buff Rat King"/>
  </Box>

  A Rat King is a giant rat capable of setting a nest and creating rats to do their bidding (usually to get food).

  ## Abilities

  Abilities come at a cost to the Rat King's hunger. Simply eating replenishes it.

  <Box>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMouse" Caption="Normal Mouse"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobRatServant" Caption="Rat Servant"/>
  </Box>
  - Raise an Army of [color=#a4885c]Rat Servants[/color].
  - Conjure a cloud of ammonia.

  # Space Dragon

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDragon" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  A Space Dragon is a giant dragon that creates space carp rifts and eats the crew.

  ## Abilities

  - Devour critical or dead victims.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCarp" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CarpRift" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCarp" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  - Summon a Carp Rift that periodically spawns [color=#a4885c]Space Carp[/color].

</Document>
