<Document>
  # Nuclear Operatives
  
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"OPERATIVES STANDBY. YOUR OBJECTIVES ARE SIMPLE.[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]DELIVER THE PAYLOAD AND GET OUT BEFORE THE PAYLOAD DETONATES. BEGIN MISSION."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterContrabandEnlistGorlex" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  You've just been chosen to be a nuclear operative for the [color=#ff0000]Syndicate[/color]. You have one goal, to blow up one of Nanotrasen's finest vessels with a nuclear fission explosive.

  ## Operatives
  Your team will be made up of several different roles, which are:
  - [bold]Operatives[/bold], standard soldiers who can take up the grunt work.
  - The [bold]Agent[/bold] who works with reagents to make medicines or chemical weapons.
  - The [bold]Commander[/bold] who draws up the plan and leads the team.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitSyndie"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitSyndieMedic" Caption="agent's hardsuit"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitSyndieCommander" Caption="commander's hardsuit"/>
  </Box>

  If you have been selected as the Agent or Commander but don't feel ready, one of your teammates can take responsibility.

  ## The Disk

  Each operative starts with a [color=cyan]pinpointer[/color], which you should turn on and keep with you at all times. It will always point to the [color=cyan]nuclear authentication disk.[/color]
  The disk belongs to the [color=yellow]Captain[/color], who will almost always have it on them. Follow the direction of the arrow on the pinpointer to the disk, and [italic]do whatever it takes to get it[/italic].

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PinpointerNuclear"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NukeDisk"/>
  </Box>

  ## Preparation
  Each member in your squad has been given an [color=cyan]uplink[/color] to purchase everything you will need for the mission, similar to [textlink="Traitors." link="Traitors"]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BaseUplinkRadio40TC" Caption="your uplink"/>
  </Box>

  You can purchase the same kinds of gear Traitors can, but you have higher quality gear available to you and more telecrystals to spend.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponLightMachineGunL6" Caption="Weaponry"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MagazineLightRifleBox" State="icon" Caption="Ammo"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="C4" Caption="Explosives"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterHardsuitJuggernaut" Caption="Wearables"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Stimpack" Caption="Chemicals"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChameleonProjector" Caption="Deception"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emag" Caption="Disruption"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MacroBombImplanter" Caption="Implants"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisSyndicateAssault" Caption="Allies"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesOutlawGlasses" Caption="Pointless"/>
  </Box>

  You'll also have to choose if you want to [color=red]declare war[/color] or not. Doing so grants your team [bold]40 extra telecrystals each[/bold].
  However, the crew will immediately know of your existence and will have plenty of time to prepare for your arrival.

  The [bold]Commander[/bold] is the only person who can declare war. Make your choice quick, [italic]this is a limited-time offer![/italic]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NukeOpsDeclarationOfWar"/>
  </Box>

  ## Getting to the Station
  You've got the plan, you've got the gear. Now, execute.

  Grab a [bold]jetpack[/bold] from your armory and go with your other operatives to the [color=cyan]Syndicate Shuttle[/color].
  Among other things you may need, you'll find an [bold]IFF Console[/bold] on the shuttle. It allows you to hide from other ships and mass scanners when [italic]"Show IFF"[/italic] and [italic]"Show Vessel"[/italic] are toggled off.

  When everyone is ready, FTL to the station and fly to it with a jetpack. Don't forget the code, your pinpointers and the nuke if you're taking it.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="JetpackBlack"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerIFFSyndicate"/>
  </Box>

  ## The Nuke & Arming Procedure
  You have a paper with the [color=cyan]nuclear authentication codes[/color] on your shuttle. [bold]Check to see if the nuke ID matches the one on your shuttle.[/bold] If it doesn't, you'll have to use explosive in the station's vault.

  - Obtain the [bold]nuclear authentication disk[/bold] and insert it into the nuke.
  - Type in the [bold]nuclear authentication code[/bold] and press "[bold]E[/bold]" on the keypad to Enter.
  - To begin [bold]self-destruct process[/bold], press "[color=red]ARM[/color]". After 300 seconds, the nuke will explode.
  - [bold]Defend the nuke[/bold], even if it's at the cost of your lives! The mission requirements do not include your return. 
  - It takes 30 seconds for someone to [bold]disarm[/bold] the nuke. Re-arming it is possible, but the chance of mission success drops if you let it happen.
  - Should the nuke be re-armed, the timer will start from where it left off.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NuclearBomb" Caption="The Nuclear Fission Explosive"/>
  </Box>

  ## Winning Conditions

  The [color=#00ff00]victor[/color] of the round is announced on the round end screen, as well as the scale of their victory.

  [bold][color=red]Syndicate Major Victory![/color][/bold]
  - The nuke detonates on the station.
  - The crew escapes on evac, but the nuke is still armed.
  - The nuke is armed and delivered to Central Command on the evac shuttle.

  [bold][color=red]Syndicate Minor Victory[/color][/bold]
  - The crew escapes on evac, but every operative survives.
  - The crew escapes and some operatives die, but the crew loses the disk.

  [bold][color=#999999]Neutral Victory[/color][/bold]
  - The nuke detonates off the station.

  [bold][color=green]Crew Minor Victory[/color][/bold]
  - The crew escapes on evac with the disk and some operatives die.

  [bold][color=green]Crew Major Victory![/color][/bold]
  - All operatives die.
  - The crew blow up the nuclear operative outpost with the nuke.
</Document>
