<Document>
  # Space Ninja

  The [color=#66FF00]Space Ninja[/color] is a ghost role randomly available mid-late game. If you pick it you will be given your gear, your objectives and the greeting.

  You are a ninja, but in space. [color=#66FF00]The Spider Clan[/color] has sent you to the station to wreak all kinds of havoc, and you are equipped to keep it silent-but-deadly.

  Whether you mercilessly pick off the station's crew one by one, or assassinate the clown over and over, your discipline has taught you that [color=#66FF00]your objectives must be at least attempted[/color]. For honor!

  # Equipment

  You begin implanted with a [color=#a4885c]death acidifier[/color], so if you are KIA or decide to commit seppuku you will leave behind one final gift to the janitor and all your precious equipment is kept out of enemy hands.

  Your bag is full of tools for more subtle sabotage, along with a survival box if you need a snack.

  You have a [color=#a4885c]jetpack[/color] and [color=#a4885c]pinpointer[/color] that will let you find the station.

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PinpointerStation" Caption="station pinpointer"/>

  ## Ninja Suit

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterSuitSpaceNinja" Captain="ninja suit"/>

  Your single most important item is [color=#66FF00]your suit[/color], without it none of your abilities would work.
  Your suit requires power to function. Its [color=#a4885c]internal battery[/color] can be replaced by clicking on it with another one, and [color=#a4885c]higher capacity batteries[/color] mean a [color=#a4885c]highly effective ninja[/color].
  You can see the current charge by examining the suit or in a sweet battery alert at the top right of your screen.

  If you run out of power and need to recharge your battery, just use your gloves to drain an APC, substation or a SMES.

  ## Ninja Gloves

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHandsGlovesSpaceNinja" Caption="ninja gloves"/>

  [color=#66FF00]These bad boys are your bread and butter.[/color]

  They are made from [color=#a4885c]insulated nanomachines[/color] to assist you in gracefully breaking and entering into your destination without leaving behind fingerprints.

  You have an action to toggle gloves. When the gloves are turned on, they allow you to use [color=#a4885c]special abilities[/color], which are triggered by interacting with things with an empty hand and with combat mode disabled.

  Your glove abilities include:
  - Emagging an unlimited number of doors.
  - Draining power from transformers such as APCs, substations or SMESes. The higher the voltage, the more efficient the draining is.
  - You can shock any mob, stunning and slightly damaging them.
  - You can download technologies from a R&D server for one of your objectives.
  - You can hack a communications console to call in a threat.

  ## Energy Katana

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EnergyKatana" Captain="energy katana"/>

  You have sworn yourself to the [color=#66FF00]sword[/color] and refuse to use firearms.
  Deals a lot of damage and can be recalled at will, costing suit power proportional to the distance teleported.
  
  While in hand you can [color=#a4885c]teleport[/color] to anywhere that you can see, meaning most doors and windows, but not past solid walls.
  This has a limited number of charges which regenerate slowly, so keep a charge or two spare incase you need a quick getaway.

  ## Spider Clan Charge

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SpiderCharge" Caption="spider clan charge"/>

  [color=#66FF00]A modified C-4 explosive[/color], you start with this in your pocket. Creates a large explosion but must be armed in your target area.
  A random area on the map is selected for you to blow up, which is one of your [color=#a4885c]objectives[/color].

  It can't be activated manually, simply plant it on a wall or a particularly ugly piece of furniture.
  Can't be unstuck once planted.

  ## Ninja Shoes

  Special [color=#a4885c]noslips[/color] that keep you agile, swift and upright.
  Energy not required.

  # Objectives

  - Download X research nodes: Use your gloves on an R&D server with a number of unlocked technologies
  - Doorjack X doors on the station: Use your gloves to emag a number of doors.
  - Detonate the spider clan charge: Plant your spider clan charge at a random location and watch it go boom.
  - Call in a threat: Use your gloves on a communications console.
  - Survive: Don't die.

</Document>
