<Document>
  # Space Ninja
  
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"Spider of the night, silent is my bite."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>

  You are an elite mercenary that [color=#66FF00]The Spider Clan[/color] has sent to wreak all kinds of havoc on the station. You are equipped to keep it silent-but-deadly.

  Whether you decide to mercilessly pick off the station's crew one by one or stay out of trouble, your discipline has taught you that [italic]your objectives must be at least attempted[/italic]. For honor!

  ## Standard Equipment
  You begin implanted with a [color=cyan]death acidifier[/color], so if you are captured or KIA all your precious equipment is kept out of enemy hands.

  Your bag is full of [bold]tools[/bold] and a [bold]survival box[/bold]. You also carry a [color=cyan]jetpack[/color] and a [color=cyan]pinpointer[/color] that will lead you to the station.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="JetpackBlack"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PinpointerStation"/>
  </Box>
  
  ## Ninja Suit & Boots
  
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesVisorNinja" Caption="your visor"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterSuitSpaceNinja" Caption="your suit"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingShoesSpaceNinja" Caption="your boots"/>
  </Box>

  Your single most important item is [color=#66FF00]your suit[/color], without it none of your abilities would work.
  Your suit requires power to function, which is supplied by its [bold]internal battery[/bold]. It can be replaced, and [italic]high capacity batteries[/italic] mean a [italic]highly effective ninja[/italic].

  [bold]You can recharge your internal battery directly[/bold] by using [color=#66FF00]your gloves[/color]. You can see the current charge by examining the suit or checking the nifty battery alert on your screen.

  Your outfit also includes [color=#66FF00]special boots[/color] that keep you agile, upright and grounded without using energy. You've also got flash protection thanks to your [color=#66FF00]visor[/color].

  ## Ninja Gloves

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHandsGlovesSpaceNinja" Caption="your gloves"/>
  </Box>

  [color=#66FF00]These bad boys are your bread and butter.[/color] They are made from [bold]insulated nanomachines[/bold] to allow you to gracefully break into restricted areas without leaving behind fingerprints.

  You have an action to toggle gloves. When the gloves are turned on, they allow you to use [bold]special abilities[/bold], which are triggered by interacting with things with an empty hand and with combat mode disabled.

  Your glove abilities include:
  - Emagging doors and airlocks.
  - Draining power from [bold]transformers[/bold] such as APCs, substations, or SMESes (higher voltage transformers drain more efficiently).
  - Applying an electrical shock to a mob, stunning and slightly damaging them.
  - Tampering with [bold]station equipment[/bold] to complete [color=#66FF00]objectives[/color].

  ## Energy Katana

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EnergyKatana"/>
  </Box>

  [bold]You have sworn yourself to the sword and refuse to use firearms.[/bold] Luckily, you've got a pretty cool sword.

  Your [color=#66FF00]energy katana[/color] hurts plenty and can be [bold]recalled at will[/bold] at the cost of suit power. The farther away it is from you, the more energy required to recall it.

  While in hand you may also [color=#66FF00]teleport[/color] to anywhere that you can see, [bold]including through windows[/bold]. The charges required to do this regenerate slowly, so keep a charge or two spare in case you need a quick getaway.

  ## Spider Clan Charge
  
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SpiderCharge"/>
  </Box>
  
  [color=#66FF00]A modified C-4 explosive[/color], which can be found in your pocket. Creates a large explosion but [bold]must be armed in your target area[/bold] as it is one of your [color=#66FF00]objectives[/color].

  It can't be activated manually, so simply plant it on a wall or a particularly ugly piece of furniture. Can't be unstuck once planted.

  ## Objectives

  - Download \[9-13\] research nodes: Use your gloves on an R&D server with a number of unlocked technologies. You may have to unlock technologies yourself if there aren't enough to steal already.
  - Doorjack \[15-40\] doors on the station: Use your gloves to emag a number of doors.
  - Detonate the spider clan charge: Plant your spider clan charge at the specified location and watch it go boom!
  - Call in a [textlink="threat" link="MinorAntagonists"]: Use your gloves on a communications console.
  - Set everyone to wanted: Use your gloves on a criminal records console.
  - Survive: Don't die.

</Document>
