<Document>
  # Thieves
  
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"Yoink! I'll be taking that! And that! Ooh, don't mind if I do!"[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingNeckCloakVoid" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Thieves are petty yet crafty [color=green]criminals[/color] who can't keep their hands to themselves. You were forcefully given a [bold]pacifism implant[/bold] after your last arrest, but you won't let that stop you from trying to add to your collection.

  ## Art of the Steal
  Unlike other antagonists, [bold]staying out of trouble is almost a requirement for you[/bold] because of your implant.
  You can only run if [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] picks a fight with you, and because you work alone you don't have any friends to pull you out of danger.

  But against all odds, you'll sucessfully swipe what you want using determination, sleight of hand, a few tools and your [color=cyan]thieving gloves.[/color]

  The pair of gloves you have give you a major advantage: [bold]the ability to take things off of people without them even noticing.[/bold] With a little practice, you can steal their wallet and keep up a conversation at the same time.

  They're also made of the highest quality [bold]holographic chameleon fibers[/bold] you could steal, but while they can take the appearance of insulated gloves you'll still need to find a real pair to keep your hands from burning.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHandsChameleonThief" Caption="your thieving gloves"/>
  </Box>

  ## Tools of the Trade
  You've got two more aces up your stolen sleeves: your [color=cyan]beacon[/color] and your [color=cyan]toolbox.[/color]

  Your [color=cyan]beacon[/color] provides safe passage home for trinkets that may not be easy to carry with you on the evac shuttle. Simply find a secluded part of the station to unfold the beacon, then set its coordinates to your hideout.
  Any shinies near it will be [bold]teleported to your vault when the shift ends,[/bold] fulfilling your objectives.

  However, this will instantly out you if found and make it extremely easy for people to reclaim their "missing" possessions. [bold]Make sure to hide it well![/bold]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ThiefBeacon"/>
  </Box>

  Your [color=cyan]toolbox[/color] contains... well, whatever you remembered to pack. [bold]You can select two pre-made kits[/bold] to help you complete grander heists.
  Approve your choices in a safe place, as the toolbox will dissolve and the gear will drop at your feet.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToolboxThief"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StorageImplanter" Caption="Anatomy"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="C4" Caption="Breacher"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChameleonProjector" Caption="Chameleon"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyStationMaster" Caption="Communicator"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NitrousOxideTank" Caption="Sleeper"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Emag" Caption="Smuggler"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Telecrystal" Caption="Syndie"/>
  </Box>

  ## Centerpiece of the Collection
  Your kleptomania will take you places. One day, you'll feel like stealing a few figurines. Another day, you'll feel like stealing an industrial machine.
  
  No matter. They'll all be a part of your collection within a matter of time.

  You can steal items by [bold]having them on your person[/bold] when you get to CentComm. Failing this, you can steal larger items by [bold]leaving them by your beacon.[/bold]

  Some of the more [italic]animate[/italic] objectives may not cooperate with you. Make sure they're alive and with you or your beacon when the shift ends.

  Things that you may desire include but are not limited to:
  
  <Box>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineGreytider" Caption="Figurines"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PassengerIDCard" Caption="ID cards"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ChemDispenser" Caption="Structures"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCorgiIan" Caption="Animals/Pets"/>
  </Box>
  
</Document>
