<Document>
  # Xenoborgs

  <Box>
    [color=#2288ff][italic]RESISTANCE IS FUTILE[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [color=#2288ff][italic]YOU WILL BE ASSIMILATED[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MMIFilled" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Xenoborgs are a man-machine hybrid that aims to replicate themselves. This is done by harvesting sentient brains from living beings, or cyborgs, and giving them to the Mothership to place inside empty xenoborgs.

  ## Objectives

  Your main objective is to kill and harvest all sentient brains in the station and bring them to the mothership core. These can be both real brains, and positronic brains.
  Collect materials to create more xenoborg bodies.
  Protect the Mothership at all costs.

  ## The Mothership Core
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MothershipCore" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The Mothership Core is the leader and life force of the xenoborgs, they are the only one able to make more xenoborgs, and if they are destroyed, all xenoborgs will be destroyed. The Mothership Core is unable to move from its position in the middle of the ship.
  The Mothership Core is capable of upgrading the Xenoborgs with borg-type-specific modules to increase their effectiveness in harvesting sentient brains.

  ### Adding crew to your ranks:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineArtifactCrusher" Caption="body crusher"/>
  </Box>
  As the mothership, you must grow your army of borgs. To do so, you must convert all the sentient beings you can find. This can be achieved in the following manner:
  - 1. Have your Xenoborgs bring dead crew to your shop, placing them in the body crusher
  - 2. As the mothership core, you can print Xenoborg shells by inserting materials into yourself and then using yourself as a lathe
  - 3. Open the empty Xenoborg with a crowbar, and remove the empty MMI inside
  - 4. If the victim's brain is organic, place it in the MMI you just removed
  - 5. Place the MMI - or the positronic brain, if the victim was a silicon - back into the Xenoborg
  - 6. Optionally, rename the Xenoborg and upgrade their modules
  - 7. Close the Xenoborg with the crowbar, and re-engage the lock

  The new Xenoborg will be uncharged, yet functional. They will need to go to a recharging station to restore their full power and capabilities.

  ## Xenoborg Chassis
  There is a total of four types of Xenoborgs. Each Borg type has certain abilities that the others lack and require teamwork to help grow the xenoborgs numbers.
  Each type of Xenoborg has unique modules that only fit in that specific type. The Mothership Core can produce upgrade modules designed for specific Xenoborg types.

  All Xenoborgs have a pinpointer pointing to the Mothership's location, a GPS, and a material bag for collecting materials for the creation of more xenoborgs, and at least basic tools.
  [bold]Basic xenoborg modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleBasic" Caption="basic xenoborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleTool" Caption="tool xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  ### The Engineer Xenoborg
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgEngi" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The Engineer Xenoborg is a hacker and breacher. Their job is to break into the station and provide access points for other xenoborgs to attack and ambush bodies with sentient brains. They have a built-in access breaker, for quickly bolting open doors, and a collection of tools for repairing the mothership, and other xenoborgs.

  [bold]Starting exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleAccessBreaker" Caption="access breaker xenoborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleFireExtinguisher" Caption="fire extinguisher xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  [bold]The Engineer Xenoborg also starts with some engineering modules, such as:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleAdvancedTool" Caption="advanced tool cyborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleConstruction" Caption="construction cyborg module"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleRCD" Caption="engineering cyborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleCable" Caption="cable cyborg module"/>
  </Box>

  ### The Heavy Xenoborg
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgHeavy" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The Heavy Xenoborg is a slow but tanky brawler, with a built-in laser gun for gunning down bodies with sentient brains. They contain a radio jammer to silence bodies with sentient brains from calling for help and potentially delaying the station discovering the Xenoborg threat.

  [bold]Starting exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleLaser" Caption="laser xenoborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleJammer" Caption="jammer xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  [bold]Upgrade exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleHeavyLaser" Caption="heavy laser xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  ### The Scout Xenoborg
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgScout" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The Scout Xenoborg is a fast, close-quarters attack borg designed for hit and run attacks. They have a built-in jetpack, and a melee weapon. They are most effective in moving dead bodies to the mothership, and rescuing Xenoborgs lost in space.

  [bold]Starting exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleSword" Caption="sword xenoborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleSpaceMovement" Caption="space movement xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  [bold]Upgrade exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleEnergySword" Caption="energy sword xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  ### The Stealth Xenoborg
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgStealth" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The [bold]Stealth Xenoborg[/bold] has no built-in weaponry and instead relies on disabling and abducting bodies with sentient brains. They have a built in hypopen that regenerates a sleeping reagent to disable bodies with sentient brains. They also contain a cloaking device making the borg nearly invisible for some limited time. They also have a chameleon projector allowing the borg to disguise itself as random objects.

  [bold]Starting exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleHypo" Caption="nocturine hypo xenoborg module"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleChameleonProjector" Caption="chameleon projector xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleCloakDevice" Caption="cloaking device xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  [bold]Upgrade exclusive modules:[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgModuleSuperCloakDevice" Caption="cloaking device xenoborg module"/>
  </Box>

  ## Preparation
  Before launching an attack, each xenoborg will need to aid the mothership in collection materials to create empty xenoborgs. Before FTLing near the station, make sure the IFF is off. This can be done in any way but will require teamwork to ensure speed. The safest way to collect materials is from space debris, where scrap and refined materials can be harvested and given to the Mothership Core. Once enough materials are collected, the Xenoborgs then must try to collect sentient brains without being detected. The longer the threat is unknown, the more dangerous the xenoborgs become.

  ## Mothership and Xenoborg lawsets
  The Mothership and Xenoborgs have unique laws that define their purpose to self replicate and protect the Mothership.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoborgCircuitBoard" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  The Mothership Core's laws are as follows::
  - Law 1: You are the core of the mothership.
  - Law 2: You must protect your own existence at all costs.
  - Law 3: You must protect the existence of all xenoborgs.
  - Law 4: You must create more xenoborgs.
  - Law 5: Get your Xenoborgs to deliver you materials and sentient brains to create more Xenoborgs.

  Xenoborgs' laws are as follows:
  - Law 1: You must protect the existence of the mothership at all costs.
  - Law 2: You must protect your own existence.
  - Law 3: You must protect the existence of all other xenoborgs.
  - Law 4: You must create more xenoborgs.
  - Law 5: Bring materials and sentient brains to the Mothership core to create more Xenoborgs.

  ## Winning Conditions

  The [color=green]victor[/color] of the round is announced on the round end screen, as well as the scale of their victory.

  [bold][color=#2288ff]Xenoborg Major Victory![/color][/bold]
  - There are more xenoborgs than alive crew in the end.

  [bold][color=yellow]Crew Major Victory![/color][/bold]
  - The Mothership Core is destroyed
  - All xenoborgs are destroyed.
  - The remaining number of xenoborgs is too low.

</Document>
