<Document>
  # Zombies
  
  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"They're coming to get you, Barbara!"[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignBiohazard" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Zombies are conversion antagonists that infect all beings that they bite with [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color], a deadly, contagious virus that can easily spread if not contained.

  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Romerol"></GuideReagentEmbed>
  </Box>

  ## Inital Infected
  You are patient zero. You have [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color] coursing through your veins and you have a grand desire to share it with every single flesh being you see.

  Upon learning of your infection, [italic]all bets are off[/italic]. You have only so much time before you turn, and you want to [bold]maximize your chances of taking over the station.[/bold]
  Use this time to prepare weapons, gear, and traps. [italic]Space Law means nothing to you now.[/italic]

  ## Transmission
  Zombies only know how to shamble, bite and throw themselves against barricades. Their bite [bold]may not always transmit [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color][/bold] through heavy layers of clothing, but it'll definitely hurt.

  The undead can also chomp on a crit or dead body to [bold]instantly convert[/bold] it to a zombie.

  ## Zombie Attributes
  A zombie can be identified by dark green skin, red eyes, slow movement, rotting smell, and lack of motor functions. They'll drop their headset and gloves upon turning, and cuffs don't work against their vicious bite.

  Zombies are known for their [bold]resilience to slashes, bruises, poison and cold.[/bold] They can survive in a vacuum and do not require food, water, air, or sleep. The undead do, however, [italic]take increased burn and shock damage.[/italic]

  ## Survival
  When the infection sweeps and [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] falls, it's up to the [bold]survivors[/bold] to try and make it to Central Command.

  [bold]Constructing barricades[/bold] around departments or [bold]bolting doors[/bold] can buy enough time to make weapons, save lives or make a plan.

  Remember that when it really hits the fan, [italic]you've gotta do what you gotta do[/italic], as long as it's not at the expense of fellow survivors. Scavenge what you need from those who haven't made it.

  ## Cure
  [bold]Those who are already undead can only be cured by [color=red]death.[/color][/bold]

  If you're infected but not zombified yet, using [color=#86caf7]Ambuzol[/color] will cure you but won't prevent re-infection. [color=#1274b5]Ambuzol Plus[/color] will cure and prevent re-infection only while alive.

  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Ambuzol"></GuideReagentEmbed>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="AmbuzolPlus"></GuideReagentEmbed>
  </Box>

</Document>
