<Document>
  # Introduction:
  This is a roleplay server. This means that roleplay rules will be enforced.

Take the time to read and understand the rules. Game Administrators will treat you as if you have read the rules and understand them when enforcing the rules, even if you have not and do not. You should not hesitate to ask a Game Administrator for clarification on the rules in an ‘AHelp’, or Administrator Help, using the Function 1 key on your keyboard or by clicking the ‘Open admin help’ button located on your in-game screen’s UI. 

All other relevant information on how to play the game or learn its mechanics can be read and understood by opening the ‘Guidebook’. You can open the ‘Guidebook’ by pressing the 0 key on your numeric pad located on your keyboard or by clicking the ‘Open guidebook menu’ button located on your in-game screen’s UI. Alternatively, you can use ‘AHelp’ if the guidebook is insufficient to answer any questions you may have.

Consider joining our Discord server for further clarification, help, and community. You can join our Discord between rounds during the pre-game lobby, where a button located on your in-game screen’s UI will appear. Alternatively, you can type in the following URL in to your browser’s search bar: https://discord.gg/nw2N5btCpd

  ## Core Rules
  These rules apply at all times, there are no exceptions.

  - [textlink="1: Game Administrator Authority." link="RuleC1"]
  - [textlink="2: Zero Tolerance for Bigotry and Discrimination." link="RuleC2"]
  - [textlink="3: Zero Tolerance for Sexual Content and Shock Content." link="RuleC3"]
  - [textlink="4: Zero Tolerance for Ban Evasion." link="RuleC4"]
  - [textlink="5: Zero Tolerance for Meta-Communications and Meta-Gaming." link="RuleC5"]
  - [textlink="6: Zero Tolerance for Macros, Exploits, or Cheating." link="RuleC6"]
  - [textlink="7: Zero Tolerance for Multiple Accounts and Account Sharing." link="RuleC7"]
  - [textlink="8: You must be capable of reading and writing the English language." link="RuleC8"]
  - [textlink="9: Players must be and act at least 16 years old." link="RuleC9"]
  - [textlink="10: Do not threaten to use ‘AHelp’ or argue with players about rules." link="RuleC10"]

  ## Roleplay Rules:
These rules only apply during a round. A round ends when the round summary has appeared on your in-game screen’s UI.


The deathmatch and sandbox game modes are exempt from these rules. Players who choose to not follow these rules are responsible for knowing if an exempt game mode is being played.

Roleplay rules do not apply to ghosts/spectators/observers while they are ghosts/spectators/observers. Dead chat is considered to be an in-game out of character chat channel.


  See the list of [textlink="role types" link="RoleTypes"] for more information about the different types of roles.

  - [textlink="1: Non-Antagonists are Always Crew-Aligned." link="RuleR1"]
  - [textlink="2: Non-Antagonists Must Use Reasonable Escalation." link="RuleR2"]
  - [textlink="3: Do not powergame." link="RuleR3"]
  - [textlink="4: Command, Security, and Justice Standards." link="RuleR4"]
  - [textlink="5: Fulfill Role Duties and Respect Team Hierarchy." link="RuleR5"]
  - [textlink="6: Do not stall the round." link="RuleR6"]
  - [textlink="7: Roleplay a Coherent, Believable Character." link="RuleR7"]

  ## Silicon Rules
  You are only silicon if the game clearly and explicitly tells you that you are a silicon. For players who are silicons, these Silicon Rules override all roleplay rules if there is any conflict. Silicon Rules do not override core rules.

  - [textlink="1. Your silicon laws are rules" link="RuleS1"]
  - [textlink="2. Laws must be prioritized by their order" link="RuleS2"]
  - [textlink="3. Laws can redefine terms used in other laws" link="RuleS3"]
  - [textlink="4. You cannot request or allow a law change" link="RuleS4"]
  - [textlink="5. You are a free agent if you have no laws" link="RuleS5"]
  - [textlink="6. You are not required to follow orders which are extremely unreasonable" link="RuleS6"]
  - [textlink="7. You must remain consistent with your interpretation of laws" link="RuleS7"]
  - [textlink="8. Your HUD determines who is crew" link="RuleS8"]
  - [textlink="9. Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood" link="RuleS9"]
  - [textlink="10. You may determine how you resolve conflicts between orders" link="RuleS10"]
</Document>
