<Document>
  # Silicon Rule 9 - Harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood
  Unless a law defines harm, harm only refers to physical harm. You may choose if voluntary harm is considered harm as long as you stay consistent. Not considering voluntary harm to be harm is recommended. There is no distinction between direct and indirect harm.

  If you have a law that does not allow you to harm, then that law does not allow you to take an action that causes any harm.

  If you have a law that requires you to prevent harm, then that law requires that harm be prioritized by immediacy and likelihood. Guaranteed immediate harm takes priority over highly likely future harm.

  If you have a law that both requires you to prevent harm and that does not allow you to harm, then that law prohibits causing even minor harm to prevent harm. If you have a law that does not allow causing harm, and separate one that requires preventing harm, then they are prioritized by their normal law priority.

  ## Examples
  These examples assume that your have a law that both prohibits causing harm and that requires you to prevent harm. Additionally, they assume that you do not have a higher priority law that overrides the harm law, and that you have decided that you will not consider voluntary harm to be harm for the round.
  Laws typically specify who you cannot harm and who you have to prevent harm against. In these examples, you are the only person who the law doesn't require you to prevent harm against and you are the only person who the law allows you to harm.

  Acceptable:
  - Taking no action to aid someone who is in psychological distress.
  - Taking no action to prevent boxing matches between voluntary participants.
  - Calling security to a fight.
  - Attempting to get the people in a fight to consent to the fight when you realize that you cannot prevent the fight without causing harm.
  - Denying a passenger access to the armory because it is likely to lead to harm

  Prohibited:
  - Hitting someone once to stop them from fighting
  - Harming someone who is trying to kill you
</Document>
