<Document>
  # Cargo
  Cargo technically does not exist as a department but rather is a job that all crew are meant to do at trade stations.
  Cargo's job is simple:
  - Salvage objects when possible
  - Sell the unneccessary items at trade stations
  - Order important items at trade stations
  - Give all profits to the captain

  ## Trade Stations

  In order to order, sell, and relax, you will first need to go to a trade station. Trade stations are marked on warps with the [color=#a4885c]\[BASE\][/color] tag.
  Ask your pilot, captain, or the person driving the ship, politely to warp to a trade station to begin your ordering.

  ## Ordering
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerCargoOrders"/>
  </Box>
  Every transaction you make will begin at a [color=#a4885c]cargo request computer[/color], from which you can make orders for specific products. Making any order requires [color=#118C4F]credits[/color], the currency of the station. To make an order, click the "request" button next to whatever you need, type an appropriate reason for why you're ordering it, and hit "approve" when it appears below the request list.
  In order to put money into the cargo computer, you will need to access a [color=#a4885c]shared ship account console[/color], exclusive only to trade stations. Your captain will insert the money inside for spending, and anyone can withdraw it. Beware, stealing ship money is illegal and can get you arrested - there is no law on the Edge, it all depends on your captain.

  ## Selling
  So, you want to order something, but don't have the money for it? You just need to sell something! Almost everything on the station has economic value, which an [color=#a4885c]appraisal tool[/color] can read out to you.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AppraisalTool"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CargoPallet"/>
  </Box>
  After finding something worth selling, place it on one of the shuttle's cargo pallets. The next time the shuttle is sent to a trading post, the item will be sold and the money will be directly transferred back to the station's bank account. You can also make even more money by completing [textlink="bounties" link="CargoBounties"] or selling valuable items from [textlink="salvage" link="Salvage"].

</Document>
