<Document>
  # Cargo
  The supply department, more commonly known simply as Cargo, is in charge of keeping the station stocked up on necessary resources, such as fuel and raw materials. Though, they are not restricted to simple goods, and can order a wide variety of different items from off-station. The point is, it's Cargo's job to get the rest of the station what they need.

  ## Ordering
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerCargoOrders"/>
  </Box>
  Every transaction you make will begin at a [color=#a4885c]cargo request computer[/color], from which you can make orders for specific products. Making any order requires [color=#118C4F]spesos[/color], the currency of the station. To make an order, click the "request" button next to whatever you need, type an appropriate reason for why you're ordering it, and hit "approve" when it appears below the request list.

  ## Piloting
  Orders are shipped to the station via the [color=#a4885c]Trade Station[/color], and then transported with the cargo shuttle, a remotely piloted shuttle that cargo uses to transport goods back and forth from the trade station. In order to move the shuttle, you must first find the [color=#a4885c]cargo shuttle computer[/color] either on the station, or the shuttle itself.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerCargoShuttle"/>
  </Box>
  After clicking the computer, you should see a radar view of the shuttle. Here are the steps for piloting the shuttle back and forth:

  - First, disconnect any airlocks that are connected to the dock.
  - Then, you actually get to pilot the shuttle. The controls are fairly simple, with [color=#028ed9]"W"[/color] and [color=#028ed9]"S"[/color] being forward and backward, [color=#028ed9]"A"[/color] and [color=#028ed9]"D"[/color] being left and right, and [color=#028ed9]"Q"[/color] and [color=#028ed9]"E"[/color] being rotating left and right; and [color=#028ed9]"spacebar"[/color] being the brake and moving precicely by holding the [color=#028ed9]"spacebar"[/color] while doing other inputs.
  - Then pilot the shuttle to the [textlink="Trade Station" link="TradeStation"].

  ## Selling
  So, you want to order something, but don't have the money for it? You just need to sell something! Almost everything on the station has economic value, which an [color=#a4885c]appraisal tool[/color] can read out to you.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AppraisalTool"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CargoPallet"/>
  </Box>
  After finding something worth selling, place it on the cargo shuttle, and then fly it to the [textlink="Trade Station" link="TradeStation"]. Then sell the item and collect the spesos from the terminal. You can also make even more money by completing [textlink="bounties" link="CargoBounties"] or selling valuable items from [textlink="salvage" link="Salvage"].

</Document>
