<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 5-1
  ## Antagonists must exercise acceptable collateral damage.
  This rule is not intended to disallow reasonable steps taken to complete your objectives. As an antagonist, you can always kill in bona fide self defense. Taking steps to permanently round remove many people who are no longer an immediate threat to you is not permitted, even if it is done to prevent yourself from being discovered.

  This rule is not intended to disallow all antagonist activity unrelated to objectives. Antagonists may cause a level of disruption to the station that is proportional to their objectives, even if it is unrelated to their objectives.

  ## Traitors
  Traitors should only kill people who are either their named objectives or are posing an active threat in self defense. Otherwise, they should not be killing indiscriminately. Killing non-targets to acquire gear or access while not in active conflict with them is also not permitted. Baiting non-targets into conflict solely to get their gear or access is absolutely not permitted.

  Traitors are expected to employ subterfuge and stealth to complete their objectives. They should not be causing massive damage in order to complete their objectives unless it can be fully justified.

  Remember; just because Security and Command are present doesn't mean they're actively a threat until it is abundantly clear.

  Acceptable:
  - Permanently round removing people who you have the objective to kill.
  - Killing active threats to you (usually Security) in self defense.
  - Sabotaging department power to make a steal objective easier to accomplish.
  - Looting gear and/or access from a non-target who was actively pursuing you of which you killed in self defense.

  Prohibited:
  - Killing any non-target who is not an active threat to you.
  - Killing any non-target to acquire their gear and/or access who is not an active threat to you.
  - Permanently round removing people who are NOT your objective(s) to kill.
  - Causing massive station damage that easily results in collateral deaths of multiple non-targets.
  - Setting up an electrified grille in maintenance and using it to kill anyone who walks into it with the hope that one of your objectives will be one of them.
  - Sabotaging power station-wide 10 minutes into the round to make a steal objective easier to accomplish.

  Exceptions:
  - Killing a non-target who is mercilessly holding on to your steal objective. E.g. your steal objective is the CE's magboots but they're wearing them and no other means of pacifying them are available. NOTE: This is a very specific exception and should only be used in very specific circumstances. You MUST NOT round remove the individual (gibbing, etc).

  ## Heretics
  Heretics typically have a quota of sacrifices to make, and often include heads of departments. Naturally, this means they can pick off whomever they wish to fulfil their objectives. Ideally, a heretic should not continue to murderbone once they have fulfilled their quota, but obviously can still kill in self defense.

  ## Changelings
  Changelings require biomass and their objectives are to extract genetic material; so it's practically their entire purpose to kill. There are alternative methods to acquire biomass and genetic material that doesn't require being the direct cause of death for another person, but they are still fully permitted to kill anyone they want to kill. Preferably, Changelings should not be causing massive damage in order to complete their objectives and instead employ a level of subterfuge and stealth; but they are free to target anyone they like.

  ## Malfunctioning Cyborgs & Station AI
  'Malf' borgs and AIs are expected to follow their laws as per the rules. Be aware that your actions will be scrutinised by admins and justification may be asked if its believed the intepretation of the laws is incorrect. As malf silicons do not have explicit kill objectives, any justifable kills due to corrupted laws must NOT round remove anyone.

  ## Nuclear Operatives
  Nuclear Operatives have full license to kill anyone they see. Their entire purpose is to nuke the station and cause as much collateral damage as possible. They can kill anyone they want to kill and cause as much damage as they want to cause.

  ## Blob
  The blob is expected to consume the station. They can kill anyone they want to kill and cause as much damage as they want to cause.

  ## Space Dragons & Carps
  Space Dragons and Carps are naturally expected to attack everyone and cause as much chaos as possible. There's no discussion here!

  ## Ninja
  The ninja is not supposed to kill anyone, as no objectives require it. They can (and often have to, as part of their objectives) sabotage the station and defend themselves if encountered by a threat. A good ninja would be in and out without ever being seen or heard, and without spilling a drop of blood; but can kill in self defense. They must not round remove anyone, however - as they never have a kill objective.

  ## Thief
  Thieves are pacifists. They cannot directly attack anyone and should not elaborately find a way to kill someone indirectly. They can still sabotage department power to make getting their targets easier - and naturally can thieve useful items that may not be their objectives but assist in completing them.

  ## Abductors
  Abductors are expected to kidnap their targets for experimentation, but not kill them. Ideally an abductor should never kill in a round, but they are capable of dealing damage in self defense. Under no circumstances should an abductor instigate violence. They may employ subterfuge and stealth to complete their objectives, such as departmental sabotage to make a distraction or get access easier to their desired kidnap target.
</Document>
