<Document>
  # Roleplay Rule 4
  ## Roleplay as a reasonable, normal person.

  ## Being reasonable
  You are expected to play a character. How in-depth you are with the personal lore of your character is up to you, but they must be a character separate from yourself (the player). Characters may have certain quirks and eccentricities, but should still be able to be reasoned with.

  Antagonists are preferred to be reasonable but are exempt from this part of the rule. They are not exempt from the Character Behaviour rule.

  ## Examples
  Acceptable:
  - Player provided character quirks (as in, not selectable traits) that are not harmful to the round. (e.g. alcoholic, vocal quirks, etc.)
  - Non-essential job holding characters doing petty crimes, but conceding to the law when apprehended.
  - Refusing an unjustifiable order for a justifiable reason (e.g. being told to execute someone for a petty crime, told to cut vital power wiring to cause a station-wide blackout, etc.)

  Unacceptable:
  - Deliberately not engaging with other characters.
  - Refusing a justifiable order for no justifiable reason.
  - Refusing to help other characters in need for no justifiable reason.
  - Performing petty crimes and unncessarily escalating the situation when apprehended. (Self-Antag)

  ## Character behaviour
  - Do not use texting/messaging acronyms (ex: "lol", "wtf", "brb", "lmao", "thx", "sgtm") or emoticons (ex: ":)", "xD") in-character.
  - Do not mention out-of-character (OOC) concepts like game admins or developers in character.
  - Do not use emotes to bypass muted or accented speech.
  - Do not use extremely low effort or impossible emotes.

  ## Examples
  Things you should not do:
  - Say "lol did u c wat just happened" using in-character chat.
  - Say "an admin exploded him" using in-character chat.
  - Emote "can you give me some cheese" as a mouse.
  - Emote "motions for you to order guns" or "asks you to order guns in sign language" as a mime.

  Things you could do instead:
  - Say "haha did you see what just happened?"
  - Say "god blew him up" or "centcomm must have bluespaced a bomb to him"
  - Point at cheese
  - Point at the cargo order console then emote "shoots finger guns"
</Document>
