<Document>
# Speech and Text Channels
Talking is a key part of Space Station 14. You can press [keybind="FocusChatInputWindow"/] to jump to the text box.

The word next to the text box is the [color=#a4885c]text channel[/color] you're about to send the message to, or rather how you're about to say what you've typed.

Local is normal speech at normal volume.

Whisper can only be heard when nearby somebody. You automatically whisper into your radio to send messages over it.

Emotes are gestures that you make. Can be recieved by anyone who is not blinded. You will often see mimes do many emotes.

Whisper messages can be sent by starting your message with [color=#a4885c][keybind="FocusWhisperChatWindow"/][/color] and Emotes can be sent by starting your message with ([color=#a4885c]@[/color]).
You can also cycle through all of these text channels by pressing [keybind="CycleChatChannelForward"/].

People may not be able to make out all of what you're saying if you're standing too far away from them. This is especially important if you're whispering.

## Radio

Your radio allows you to communicate across the entire station and to your specific [color=#a4885c]department[/color].

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetGrey"/>
</Box>

To send a [color=#a4885c]station-wide[/color] message over the radio preface, use the [color=#32cd32]Common[/color] channel by beginning your text with [color=#32cd32]semi-colon (;)[/color].
People standing right next to you might catch bits of your radio message, even if they don't have the access to the relevant radio channel. Watch for eavesdroppers.

## Departmental Radio

You are able to send messages over your departmental radio channels using [color=#32cd32]colon (:)[/color] followed by the department letter as long as you're wearing a headset with your department's encryption key.

Examine your headset to see the department channels available to you.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetEngineering"/>
</Box>

Examining an unmodified engineering headset would show you the prefixes for the [color=#32cd32]Common[/color] and [color=#f37746]Engineering[/color] channels.

It is also possible to use [color=#a4885c]:h[/color]. This hotkey will automatically default to your department radio channel.
For example, if you're a Station Engineer then [color=#a4885c]:h[/color] will default to [color=#f37746]:e[/color].

## Encryption Keys
[color=#a4885c]Encryption keys[/color] give you access to their respective channel.
  
Examining our engineering headset from earlier shows us [color=#32cd32]Common[/color] and [color=#f37746]Engineering[/color] because an engineer's headset starts with those [color=#a4885c]encryption keys[/color].
  
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyCommon"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyEngineering"/>
</Box>
  
You can take out encryption keys by using a [color=#a4885c]screwdriver[/color] on a headset. New encryption keys are put into headsets by clicking on one with an encryption key in your hand.

All command members have extras of their relevant encryption key, but you can also request one at the HoP's office when you're getting your job changed.

## OOC Channels
OOC (out-of-character) channels exist outside of the game world. They are LOOC, OOC and Dead chat.

LOOC is on during the rounds, OOC is typically off until the round ends and you can only see and talk in Dead chat when you are, well, dead.

Do not discuss the current round in the Discord or in OOC if it's on during the round.
</Document>
