<Document>
  # Core Government

  Core Government, shortened to CoreGov or simply CG, is a government that governs the core worlds, specifically the 143 star systems referred to as "the core". They are relatively small territorial wise, however hold great power and technology. They have withstood the test of time, being the eldest faction founded in the year 2160. CoreGov has founded the economy of Credits and invented the the PDA.
  
  ## History
  The Core Government was founded in the year 2160 after incompetent management gave into a mutiny's demand, creating the structure of government that is still followed today. The Core Government is a democratic government that governs the Core, a small region of space (around 18.3LY in length and 23.4LY in width) with around 143 star systems.
  
  ## Chain of Command
  There are 4 types of space that have chain of command.
  - [color=#a4885c]Regional[/color]: Several stars.
  - [color=#a4885c]Stellar[/color]: A single star and it's sattelites.
  - [color=#a4885c]Planetary[/color]: A single planet, it's sattelites and it's state's.
  - [color=#a4885c]State[/color]: A city, country, continent, or anything smaller than Planetary.
  
  All chains of command follow a simple structure. This is a loose explanation, and does not cover the branches in it's entirety - rather their Name, Purpose and Council. The council's purpose is the final say, should there be a major disagreement and multiple head of departments in a branch disagree with each other, it may be forwarded to the council of that branch to receive the final say. The identities of this council must be kept secret for the sake of privacy and secrecy.
  - The [color=#a4885c]Command branch[/color] is a branch that focuses on commanding the other two branches, should the any of the two councils have a disagreement - or at the will of any council member, it may be taken to discussion by the council. If the council's word is the final say, the command council's word is the FINAL say. It is composed of 15 council members.
  - The [color=#a4885c]Legislation branch[/color] is a branch that focuses on the creation, alteration and deprecation of laws, composed of 5 council members that approve and disapprove law proposals. In this case, the council must review all proposals before they go into full effect.
  - The [color=#a4885c]Legal branch[/color]'s purpose is to enforce the law, prosecute and decide the punishment for criminals. It is composed of 5 council members that approve and disapprove cases.
  - Due to a scuffle that the Command council had, a fourth branch was created. The [color=#a4885c]Military branch[/color] was seperated from the Legal branch as there were too many differences in it. However, their two purposes are nearly identical. While the legal branch is to enforce the law, the military branch's purpose is to protect the Core. This branch have 4 main sub-branches, with those being the: Scouts, with the intention to chart the Edge; Army, with the intention to defend Core; Navy, with the intention to patrol the Core; and the Planetary Defense, with the intent to defend the core planets at all costs.
  
  ## Relation with Independents after The War
  After the war, CoreGov and the Independents stayed neutral. CoreGov did not wish to meddle in the affairs of independent crews however would tax independent crews standardly. There have been little to no incidents regarding CoreGov and Independents since the war.
</Document>
