<Document>
  # DNA and Fingerprints

  ## How do I get someone’s DNA?

  You can scan blood puddles, vomit, glasses, bottles, cans and other liquid containers using the [color=#a4885c]forensic scanner[/color] to get DNA of any person.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ForensicScanner"/>
  </Box>
  So be careful before fighting with someone.

  The scanner can also get fingerprint information about who touched pretty much any object. If the possible perpetrator was using gloves, then your scanner will print out which fibers were left on the crimescene.
  Be careful when scanning melee weapons, as the DNA present may be of the victim, not the perpetrator!

  ## I got DNA. How do I recognize whose it is?

  You can print the forensic information of the object you scanned so you won't forget. Now with the paper containing the DNA sample, you can simply find a [color=#a4885c]Station Records Computer[/color] and look for a person whose DNA matches. Same applies to finding whose fingerprint is is.
  Should the [color=#a4885c]Station Records Computer[/color] be unavailable, you can also try linking different pieces of evidence to narrow down suspects.

  ## Taking Fingerprints
  It is also possible to take someones fingerprints while on scene if you make them take off their gloves and appy a forensic pad to their fingers. No need to run back to the [color=#a4885c]Station Records Computer[/color] to check if the chef did it!

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ForensicPad"/>
  
  ## Fibers
  Whenenever people wearing gloves touch anything on the station, they are bound to leave behind some fibers. This complicates things, but nothing is unsolvable for a real detective.

  Ensure that whoever brings evidence (including yourself) is also wearing gloves, so that you can subtract the fiber layers in reverse order of who touched it last to find the fibers of the perpetrator.

  There are up to [color=red]16[/color] different types of fibers possible. Can that stop you from solving the case?
  
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerStationRecords"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
