<Document>
  # Forensics

  There are a lot of tools to help you gather and examine the evidence at your disposal

  # Log probe

  This little add-on to your PDA is incredibly useful, just install the cartridge and your PDA will acquire the ability to scan anything with access (like airlocks) and see who has used them recently.

  You can normally find it inside the detective locker. After inserting it on your PDA, go to the programs tab and the log probe application should be there, to use the application you just have to interact with anything that requires access with your PDA while the application is open and the information will be instantly displayed in it.

  It should be noted that the name shown in the application is not to be trusted 100% of the time since it gets the name from the identification card of whoever used the thing we are scanning, so if for example someone opened an airlock with no card the application would display "Unknown" as the name.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LockerDetective"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LogProbeCartridge"/>
  </Box>

  # DNA and Fingerprints

  ## How to get someone’s DNA?

  You can scan blood puddles, vomit, glasses, bottles, cans and other liquid containers using the [color=#a4885c]forensic scanner[/color] to get DNA of any person.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ForensicScanner"/>
  </Box>
  So be careful before fighting with someone.

  Same scanner can also get fingerprint information about who touched pretty much any object. If the possible perpetrator was using gloves, then your scanner will print out which fibers were left on the crimescene.

  ## I got DNA. How do I recognize whose it is?

  You can print the forensic information of the object you scanned so you never miss it. Now with the paper containing DNA you can simply find a [color=#a4885c]Station Records Computer[/color] and look for a person whose DNA matches. Same applies to finding whose fingerprint is is.

  ## Taking Fingerprints
  It is also possible to take someones fingerprints while on scene if you make them take off their gloves and appy a forensic pad to their fingers. No need to run back to [color=#a4885c]Station Records Computer[/color] check if the butler did it!

  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ForensicPad"/>

  ## Fibers
  Whenenever people wearing gloves touch anything on the station, they are bound to leave behind some fibers. This complicates things, but nothing is unsolvable for a real detective.

  There are up to [color=red]25[/color] different types of fibers possible. Can that stop you from solving the case?

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerStationRecords"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
