<Document>
  # Law
  On the [color=#a4885c]edge[/color], there is no standard "law". By default, your captain states the laws of the ship - however in the case they do not explicitly state any laws, here is a "common code".

  ## Treatment of Prisoners
  All prisoners have a right to stay breathing. That is the bare minimum requirement.

  ## Searches and Warrants
  On green alert, security must obtain a the captain's permission, permission from anyone in that department, or recognize plausible evidence in order to search a person, or department.
  On any other alert, security has full right to search and arrest any department and person that isn't command.

  ## Sentencing
  The Head of Security decides the sentences, if there is no Head of Security, then the highest ranking command member, if there is none, then it falls onto the officer who arrested the target.
  All sentencing requires context from both parties. Please sentence with common sense and fairness.

  ## Crimes
  There are 3 main types of crimes.
  - Minor: Minor crimes are such as petty theft, trespassing, or littering. These can usually be a slap on the wrist to a few minutes in the brig.
  - Major: Major crimes are such as murder, rioting, endangerment, or animal cruelty. At minimum a 3 mininum brig but no more than 10 minutes.
  - Capital: Capital crimes are such as manslaughter, mass destruction, or insulting the captain. Refer to the text above the list.

  ## Minor Crime List
  Minor crimes do not require a trial.
  - Disturbance of Peace: Creating a public disturbance such as placing two handheld radios together.
  - Petty Theft: To take non-vital property of another, or the ship.
  - Possession of Illegal Substances: To possess illegal substances.
  - Trespassing: To enter forbidden areas without explicit permission.
  - Vandalism: To intentionally deface property.

  ## Major Crime List
  Major crimes may have a court trial however it is much simpler if a discussion happened - as trials take up valuable time.

  - Sale of Illegal Substances: To sell illegal substances such as drugs to another.
  - Unpermitted Weapon: To carry an unregistered firearm.
  - Failure to Comply: To not comply with orders from authority, or a superior.
  - Endangerment: To put yourself, and/or others in danger.
  - Animal Cruelty: To inflict unnecessary harm or suffering to animals with a malicious intent.
  - Rioting: To take part in a large group of personnel creating a (potentially unlawful) disturbance of peace.
  - Assault: To intentionally harm one another.
  - Breach of Arrest: To escape arrest with the intention of escaping.
  - Grand Theft: To take vital property of another, or the ship.
  - Secure Trespass: To enter secured forbidden areas without explicit permission.
  - Breach of Custody: To escape cell or custody with the intention of escaping.
  - Kidnapping: To unlawfully restrain someone against their will. A civilian is permitted to restrain a criminal if they pose a threat.
  - Involuntary Manslaughter: Also known as 3rd degree murder, to end the life of another incidentally with no intention to kill.

  ## Capital Crime List
  When in a safe situation, the crew may begin a trial with 3 judges - the Captain, CMO and HoS to decide the punishment. However, in an emergency, the highest ranking command member [color=#a4885c]is able to emplace a punishment such as execution, provided they will do their best to bring them back[/color].
  - Voluntary Manslaughter: Also known as 2nd degree murder, to end the life of another with the intention to kill however with the lack of planning.
  - Murder: Also known as 1st degree murder, to end the life of another with planning and the intention to kill.
  - Prevention of Revival: To unlawfully prevent one from coming back alive.
  - Attempted Murder: To fail to commit voluntary manslaughter, involuntary manslaughter or murder.
  - Mass Murder: To kill more than 3 of one another with malicious intent.
  - Terrorism: To engage in destructive actions with malicious intent.
  - Mass Destruction: To cause massive damage to an area or major station system.
  - Sabotage: To cause a specific system to not work with malicious intent.

</Document>
