<Document>
# Security
Ensuring the safety of both station and crew is number one for [color=#cb0000]Security[/color]. They are ready for any situation, and [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] are on hand to maintain order and control crowds.

They face [textlink="Syndicate Agents" link="Traitors"], [textlink="Nuclear Operatives" link="NuclearOperatives"], [textlink="Zombies" link="Zombies"] and unruly staff.

## Personnel
[color=#cb0000]Security[/color]'s staff is made up of Security Cadets, Security Officers, and the Detective. [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] is run by the Warden and Head of Security.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineSecurity" Caption="Secoff"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineDetective" Caption="Detective"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineWarden" Caption="Warden"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineHeadOfSecurity" Caption="HoS"/>
  </Box>

## Gear
First we have non-lethals a step above simply telling someone to cooperate with instructions. Both the stunbaton and disabler are capable of limiting the movement of an assailant, whereas handcuffs can be applied to deny a criminal free movement and access to their hands.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Stunbaton"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Handcuffs"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponDisabler"/>
  </Box>

## Flashes
[color=#a4885c]Flashes[/color] are an effective tool for dispersing crowds and apprehending particularly evasive targets, with a large area of effect blinding all those without protection.
It is worth noting that flashes can be both used in a large area ([color=yellow]Z[/color] hotkey) and if you attack somebody with it while [color=red]harm mode[/color] is active. Important to note that localized flashes last [color=yellow]2.5[/color] times as long as large area ones.
[color=#cb0000]Security[/color] and [color=#a4885c]some[/color] other members of staff have eye protection from flashbangs and flashes.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Flash"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesSecurity"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GrenadeFlashBang"/>
  </Box>
  
## Lethals
Should the situation dictate, [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] have access to laser rifles, shotguns, handguns and automatic rifles able to put down substancial fire against any who would stand against the station.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponLaserCarbine"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponShotgunKammerer"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponPistolMk58"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRifleLecter"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
