<Document>
 # Rule 4 – Escalation of Force Must Make Sense
 Combat should always follow logical progression—avoid randomly attacking other crew members. Security personnel must adhere to their Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) when handling prisoners and crew members at different alert levels. Player interactions should reflect realistic escalation. Minor disagreements may lead to physical confrontations, but non-antagonists should rarely resort to killing. Ideally, escalation for non-antagonists should follow this order: [color=red] Verbal > Non-lethal > Lethal. [/color] Antagonists are encouraged to roleplay their objectives to enhance immersion and narrative depth.

Actions should start small, and every crew member retains the right to self-defense if attacked. This includes evading or resisting security as an antagonist. However, non-antagonists should not engage in serious harm against security personnel unless absolutely necessary. Round removal such as gibbing, sending to deep space, or excessive damage to a corpse, is expressly banned unless they are an antagonist target.

[bold] Examples of Reasonable Escalation: [/bold]

- Shoving the clown for slipping you
- Punching someone and starting a fist fight over being shoved once.
- Punching or stunning a Security Officer after they attempted to arrest you.
- As a Chef, stabbing someone with your knife until they leave the kitchen after you've repeatedly told them to leave, tried to drag them away and they refuse to comply or make a mess/steal things.
- As a Security Officer, shooting someone with lethals because they're attempting to stun you with a disabler or a stun baton
- As a Security Officer, shooting someone with lethals after they brandish a lethal weapon or firearm with intent to harm.
- As a command member, using your flash on a trespasser after you've told them repeatedly to leave.

[bold] Examples of unreasonable escalation: [/bold]

- Critting the clown for slipping you once
- Stabbing someone to crit with a knife because they shoved you once.
- Shooting a Security Officer with lethals because they attempted to arrest you.
- As a Chef, stabbing someone to death and butchering them in a meat spike because you need meat or they refused to leave the kitchen.
- As a Security Officer, shooting someone with lethals because they punched you, or simply refused your orders.
- As a command member, shooting someone with a firearm after you've told them repeatedly to leave.
</Document>
