<Document>
 # Rule 8 – No Validhunting
 Non-security personnel should not attempt to stop or hunt down antagonists on their own. This goes against a character’s logical roleplay expectations. Security officers and ERT are responsible for protecting the station, and should be contacted whenever reasonable. Officer "Blue Shields" are not considered Security Officers, and may not go out of their way to chase potential threats to the detriment of their charges.

Exceptions will be made for life-or-death scenarios, station-wide threats such as nuclear operatives, and self-defense.

Artificial Intelligence (AI) should not actively hunt antagonists or immediately attempt to shut them down unless their laws permit it or immediate crew harm has been detected. AI behavior should remain reactive rather than proactively searching for threats.

Command should not facilitate valid hunting outside of necessity and should ask security regarding such.

[bold]Examples of Validhunting:[/bold]

- As a Salvage Specialist, buying guns and boarding the station to eliminate Traitors/Changelings/Vampire without orders to do so from Command.
- As an Officer "Blue Shield", chasing an antagonist through maintenance, leaving Command or NT Employees unprotected.
- As an Officer "Blue Shield", chasing a wizard who has not harmed any command members into space.
- As Research Director, ordering a Scientist to hunt a traitor who just killed the Head of Personnel when Security is fully manned and able to handle the situation.
- As an assistant, chasing a traitor into maintenance who you saw attack someone else 10 minutes ago.
- As an assistant, chasing a traitor into maintenance who you saw wearing syndicate contraband.

[bold] Examples of this rule being followed:[/bold]
- As a Salvage Specialist, boarding the station to eliminate station-wide threats ONLY after being asked to assist.
- As an Officer "Blue Shield", defending a command or NT employee from an antagonist until they retreat or you crit them.
- As an Officer "Blue Shield", chasing a wizard into space who has stolen the body of a command member to their ship.
- As an assistant, reporting a person you saw wearing contraband over the radio.
- As an assistant, defending yourself or another person from an attacker until they retreat or you crit them.

</Document>