<Document>
 # Rule 3 – Abide by Medium Roleplay (MRP) Standards
This Starlight server is a Medium Roleplay (MRP) project, meaning players are expected to fully immerse themselves in their character and act accordingly. Every action should reflect how a real person in that role would behave within reason. [bold]You are not meant to play the round to "win" the game[/bold], but rather to engage in roleplay scenarios with other players.

Characters should fear dying and weigh their actions carefully. While players may remember characters and vague interactions between rounds, any information protected by the Metashield—such as the existence of nuclear operatives—must not be remembered.

## Gameplay Violations
- [bold] Powergaming [/bold] – Over-preparing for situations that have not occurred yet, such as a captain bolting their quarters shut preemptively.
- [bold] Metagaming [/bold] – Using out-of-game or previous round knowledge to affect gameplay, such as preparing for nuclear operatives before discovering them in-game.
- [bold] Metagrudging/Metafriending [/bold] – Giving a person or character preferential treatment based on something that your character should not know is considered metafriending. Treating a person or character negatively based on something that your character should not know is considered metagrudging.
- [bold] Mixing IC and OOC chat [/bold] – In-character talk should not be placed in OOC chat, and vice versa during the round.
- [bold] English Only [/bold] - Any form of communication in-game is to be expressed in English exclusively.
- [bold] Metacomms [/bold] - Using outside methods to communicate with other players about the current round is forbidden. The only exception being teaching new players, but you must alert an admin through an Ahelp beforehand.

## Behavior & Roleplay Conduct
- [bold] Self-harm/killing [/bold] – Allowed only in rare circumstances when no other options remain, but should not be dwelled upon or treated casually.
- [bold] End-of-Round Griefing (EORG) [/bold] – The round continues after the results screen. Neither crew nor antags should engage in any form of violence or griefing at this point without in-character justification.
\n - [color=000000] A. Defending yourself is an example of in-character justification, as is sec apprehending known criminals. [/color]
\n - [color=000000] B. Antags cannot complete their goals after the results screen, and so should not seek out any targets.[/color] [bold][color=red]RED MEANS YOU FAILED, IT’S TOO LATE.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] C. Breaking things, Hacking/Emagging and attempting to trespass into the Command briefing in Central Command is not allowed without proper in-character justification. Non-Command trespassers may be executed if they refuse to leave without a valid reason.[/color]
- [bold] Random Deathmatch (RDM) [/bold] – Attacking players without escalation or valid reasoning is prohibited.
- [bold] Memory loss when unconscious [/bold] – Losing consciousness due to forced sleep, vampire trance, critical state, deconversion, or death should cause memory loss regarding those events.
\n - [color=000000] A. While vague details may be retained, characters should not remember names, titles, or specific roles without further investigation.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] B. De-converted Revolutionaries forget what happened while they were brainwashed.[/color]
\n - [color=000000] C. Death should result in complete memory loss of the events leading to it. If revived, characters must piece together what happened through roleplay rather than recalling any prior knowledge.[/color]

## Avoiding Punishment & Fair Play
- [bold] Leaving To Avoid Punishment (LTAP) [/bold] – Logging out after receiving an Ahelp to attempt to dodge a ban is not allowed. Similarly, ghosting after you've been caught by security and then continuing to play, using new life or ghost roles, is not allowed. You may only leave if you are leaving the server. Exceptions will be made for perma prisoners, who may utilize the system within reason. If a player must leave due to real-life reasons under these conditions, they should make an LOOC message to inform the players around them, or state it in Ahelp.
</Document>
