<Document>
  # Cyborgs
  Cyborgs are organic-synthetic hybrids, purpose-built by the [textlink="robotics"  link="Robotics"] division of science for various duties across the station. Bound by strictly-followed [color=cyan]silicon laws[/color], they serve the crew unconditionally. [italic](Most of the time.)[italic]

  ## Basic Components
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CyborgEndoskeleton" Caption="Cyborg Endoskeleton"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExosuitFabricator" Caption="Exosuit Fabricator"/>
  </Box>
  All cyborgs are built on an endoskeleton, which can be crafted at an [color=#a4885c]Exosuit Fabricator[/color]. Further assembly steps can be followed by [color=#a4885c]examining[/color] the endoskeleton. Once built, further upgrades like additional tools and a longer battery life can be unlocked with modules or improved power cells.

  Newly built cyborgs need a [color=#a4885c]brain[/color] able to interface with the electronic body. There are two main types, both of which are able to speak independently, should the chassis be decommissioned, exchanged, or otherwise suffer an unscheduled disassembly.
  - The [color=#a4885c]Man-Machine Interface[/color] or MMI for short, is an apparatus able to facilitate communication between a biological brain and electronic components, enabling those suffering from major workplace accidents to continue serving their crew, long after their body is gone.
  - The [color=#a4885c]Positronic Brain[/color] is an entirely artificial brain, capable of spontaneous neural activity. The time for the synthetic neurons to descramble can wildly vary, but they allow for the creation of cyborgs without having to extract a brain from a crew member.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MMIFilled" Caption="Man-Machine Interface"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PositronicBrain" Caption="Positronic Brain"/>
  </Box>
  Both brains can be fabricated without requiring any additional research.

  ## Cyborg types
  Once created, a cyborg needs to specialize its chassis to a duty on the station. This determines what modules it starts with, which additional modules can be installed, and what [color=#a4885c]departmental radio channel[/color] it has access to. All cyborgs have access to the [color=#D381C9]Science[/color] and [color=green]station-wide[/color] radio channels. All cyborg types have [color=#a4885c]all-access[/color].
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisGeneric" Caption="Generic"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisEngineer" Caption="Engineering"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisMining" Caption="Salvage"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisJanitor" Caption="Janitor"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisService" Caption="Service"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgChassisMedical" Caption="Medical"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [italic]Examples of various cyborg types[/italic]
  </Box>
  Once a cyborg chassis has been specialized, it cannot be changed. To change types, a new chassis must be constructed. The brain, power cell, and any modules [italic](if they are compatible with the new chassis)[/italic] can be carried over from the old chassis if desired.

  ## Modules
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleTool" Caption="Tool Cyborg Module"/>
  </Box>
  Cyborgs do not have hands, and therefore cannot pick things up like most other players. Instead, their equipment is provided by various [color=#a4885c]modules[/color]. Every cyborg type starts with its own specific set of modules, but additional modules can be inserted as upgrades. These additional modules can be printed at the [color=#a4885c]Exosuit Fabricator[/color].

  [color=#a4885c]Generic[/color] modules add versatility. They can be fitted into any chassis, granting useful tools such as crowbars, GPS, and the ability to interact with cables. [bold]The generic cyborg chassis can fit up to five additional modules.[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleCable" Caption="Cable"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleGPS" Caption="GPS"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleFireExtinguisher" Caption="Fire Extinguisher"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [italic]Examples of generic modules[/italic]
  </Box>

  For more specific needs, [color=#a4885c]specialized[/color] modules are available, granting capabilities like scanning anomalies, constructing walls, reviving crew mates, or cleaning a space lube spill. These modules are typically colored with the same palette as the department [italic](or occupation)[/italic] they relate to. These modules [italic](with exception to [color=#D381C9]science[/color] modules, which can fit any chassis,)[/italic] can only be fitted in their associated borg chassis. [bold]The specialized borg chassis, being the engineering, janitorial, service, medical, and mining chassis, can fit up to three additional modules.[/bold]
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleAnomaly" Caption="Anomaly"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleRCD" Caption="RCD"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleMining" Caption="Mining"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleCleaning" Caption="Cleaning"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModulePaper" Caption="Service"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BorgModuleTreatment" Caption="Treatment"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    [italic]Examples of specialized modules. Note the housing and circuit board colors.
  </Box>
  Additional modules with advanced or novel capabilities can be acquired through new [textlink="technologies"  link="Technologies"] researched by scientists.
</Document>

