<Document>
  # Robotics
  The science team has the ability to create several unique types of robots to suit the station's needs. In order to begin, you'll want to research [color=#a4885c]Robotics[/color] technology.

  ## Exosuit Fabricator
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExosuitFabricator" Caption="Exosuit Fabricator"/>
</Box>
  The [color=#a4885c]Exosuit Fabricator[/color] is where you'll be printing out most of the parts for your creations, such as:
  - [textlink="Cyborg" link="Cyborgs"] limbs
  - Mech parts and equipment
  - Proximity sensors

  Operating the exosuit fabricator is the same as every other lathe on the station; simply click the fabricator to open the UI, then click the icon for whatever part you want to print.
  - Are there no recipes? click the [color=#a4885c]sync[/color] button on the UI to check for any new blueprints. If, even then, nothing shows up, you've likely not researched the relevant technology yet!
  - If a recipe appears grayed-out, it's likely due to a lack of materials. To insert new materials (either [color=#99A3A4]steel[/color], [color=#ECF0F1]plastic[/color], or [color=#AED6F1]glass[/color]), simply click the fabricator while holding said material.

  Every station starts with a full suite of robotics equipment by default, but you can make another fabricator if [color=#a4885c]Robotics[/color] technology is available, which will allow you to make the respective circuit board.

  ## Bots
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCleanBot" Caption="Cleanbot"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMedibot" Caption="Medibot"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobHonkBot" Caption="Honkbot"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMimeBot" Caption="Mimebot"/>
</Box>
  [color=#a4885c]Bots[/color] are small, simple automata which can perform simple tasks, such as cleaning. They don't use power cells, but are quite fragile. Making these will require parts which can be made at an exosuit fabricator.

  To make a bot, open the [color=#a4885c]Construction Menu[/color] and go to the "Utilities" category  (or just search "bot") and you'll have the whole list of recipes. In order to assemble the bot, you must have the parts outlined by the recipe close to you and click [color=#a4885c]Build[/color], after a few seconds your newly created silicon servant should appear at your feet!

  ## Mechs
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MechRipley" Caption="Ripley APLU"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MechHonker" Caption="H.O.N.K."/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MechHamtr" Caption="HAMTR"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MechVim" Caption="Vim"/>
</Box>
  [color=#a4885c]Mechs[/color] are giant behemoths of metal designed to carry out a variety of functions respective to their model. They are piloted by players and require power cells to function.

  Each mech requires its own unique set of limbs and parts to create. These can be fabricated at the Exosuit Fabricator, the same as any other part, save for the required [color=#a4885c]circuit boards[/color], which are made at a [color=#a4885c]Circuit Board Imprinter[/color], which can normally be found in the [textlink="science" link="Science"] department.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RipleyCentralElectronics" Caption="Ripley central controls module"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RipleyPeripheralsElectronics" Caption="Ripley peripherals control module"/>
</Box>

  For example, both of the circuit boards above are necessary to create a ripley mech, and cannot be used to make any other mech.

  To start making a mech, print their harness in the fabricator and insert the limbs, you can [color=#a4885c]examine[/color] it to see how to proceed with construction once all limbs are in place.
  - Every mech requires some combination of wires, tool usage, and their own unique circuit boards to construct after the chassis has been assembled. Most mechs have two or more unique circuit boards. For example, the [color=#a4885c]Ripley[/color] mech requires a [color=#a4885c]ripley controls module[/color] board and a [color=#a4885c]ripley peripherals module[/color] board.
  - Mechs require large amounts of material to create - be sure to ask your fellow scientists and cargo personnel for any materials you're missing!
  - The Vim exosuit requires a pair of borg legs and an EVA helmet, regular or syndicate, then a voice trigger and a power cell.

  ## Equipment
    A mech is nothing more than an expensive hunk of metal without their exclusive tools. Equipment can be created at the fabricator, the same as any other part.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MechEquipmentGrabber" Caption="The Hydraulic Clamp, as an example."/>
</Box>
  - To install equipment, just click on the mech with the equipment in your hand.
  - To use equipment, perform the "Cycle Equipment" action until the tool you desire is equipped.
</Document>
