<Document>
# Science
[color=#c96dbf]Science[/color], often called Research and Development, is a job made up of both generating research points to unlock new technologies as well as using said technologies to produce new items at lathes to help out the station.

## Personnel
[color=#c96dbf]Science[/color]'s staff is made up of Research Assistants and Scientists. [color=#c96dbf]Science[/color] is run by the Research Director.

  <Box>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineScientist" Caption="Scientist"/>
   <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineResearchDirector" Caption="RD"/>
  </Box>
  
## Technologies
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerResearchAndDevelopment"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResearchAndDevelopmentServer"/>
  </Box>
The most important thing inside your department is the R&D server, which stores unlocked technologies, and the R&D computer, which allows you to unlock [color=#a4885c]technologies[/color].

Each technology costs [color=#a4885c]Research Points[/color] and unlocks recipes at lathes. Some technologies will also have prerequisites you have to unlock before you can research them.

[textlink="Click here to see a list of technologies." link="Technologies"].

## Disciplines
Technologies are spread over 4 different Disciplines:
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Wrench" Caption="Industrial"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponTetherGun" Caption="Experimental"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerTelevision" Caption="Civil Services"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponXrayCannon" Caption="Arsenal"/>
  </Box>

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerResearchAndDevelopment"/> Use your nearest R&D console to take note of which kind of research is locked behind each Discipline tree.

## Tiers
Each Discipline tree has up to 3 tiers of technologies. At the start the only tier that is open and available for you is tier 1.

In order to progress further, you have to research up to [color=brown]75%[/color] of the current tier to move to the next one. So in order to unlock T2 researches you need to research 75% of T1.

Now [color=green]Tier 3[/color] is where it gets interesting. If you research a T3 tech, you [color=brown]lock out[/color] T3 techs from other Discipline trees. That is, unless... you find some other way around it, probably should ask your [color=purple]Research Director[/color].

## Lathes
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Protolathe"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CircuitImprinter"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExosuitFabricator"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalTechFab"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SecurityTechFab"/>
  </Box>
At a lathe, you can choose a server to allow it print whatever recipes you have unlocked. Recipes require various materials (steel, glass, plastic, gold, plasma) which can be acquired at Cargo or Salvage.

</Document>
