<Document>
# Научный отдел

Научный отдел, часто именуемый "РнД", занимается заработком очков исследований, используемых для изучения новых технологий, которые в свою очередь позволяют создавать полезные для станции предметы на различных станках, принтерах, и фабрикаторах.

## Технологии
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerResearchAndDevelopment"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResearchAndDevelopmentServer"/>
</Box>
	Самыми важными устройствами вашего отдела являются сервер РнД, на котором хранятся все изученные технологии, и исследовательская консоль, который позволяет вам эти технологии открывать.

	Каждая технология стоит определённое число [color=#a4885c]Очков исследований[/color], и их изучение открывает новые рецепты для печати на производственных станках. Некоторые технологии нельзя разблокировать, не изучив технологии им предшествующие.

	## Disciplines
	Technologies are spread over 5 different Disciplines:
	<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Wrench" Caption="Industrial"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Syringe" Caption="Biochemical"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponTetherGun" Caption="Experimental"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerTelevision" Caption="Civil Services"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponXrayCannon" Caption="Arsenal"/>
</Box>

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerResearchAndDevelopment"/> Use your nearest R&D console to take note of which kind of research is locked behind each Discipline tree.

## Tiers
Each Discipline tree has up to 3 tiers of technologies. At the start the only tier that is open and available for you is tier 1.

In order to progress further, you have to research up to [color=brown]75%[/color] of the current tier to move to the next one. So in order to unlock T2 researches you need to research 75% of T1.


Each technology costs [color=#a4885c]Research Points[/color] and unlocks recipes at lathes. Some technologies will also have prerequisites you have to unlock before you can research them.

Information about the different technologies can be viewed [textlink="on the technology guidebook page" link="Technologies"].

## Disciplines
Technologies are spread over 5 different Disciplines:
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Wrench" Caption="Industrial"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Syringe" Caption="Biochemical"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponTetherGun" Caption="Experimental"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerTelevision" Caption="Civil Services"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponXrayCannon" Caption="Arsenal"/>
</Box>

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerResearchAndDevelopment"/> Use your nearest R&D console to take note of which kind of research is locked behind each Discipline tree.

## Tiers
Each Discipline tree has up to 3 tiers of technologies. At the start the only tier that is open and available for you is tier 1.

In order to progress further, you have to research up to [color=brown]75%[/color] of the current tier to move to the next one. So in order to unlock T2 researches you need to research 75% of T1.

Now [color=green]Tier 3[/color] is where it gets interesting. If you research a T3 tech, you [color=brown]lock out[/color] T3 techs from other Discipline trees. That is, unless... you find some other way around it, probably should ask your [color=purple]Research Director[/color].

## Lathes
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Protolathe"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CircuitImprinter"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ExosuitFabricator"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalTechFab"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SecurityTechFab"/>
</Box>
	Воспользовавшись производственным станком (например, протолатом или принтером схем), вы можете синхронизировать его с сервером РнД, чтобы разблокировать новые рецепты для печати. Печать требует различные материалы (сталь, стекло, пластик, золото, или плазму), которые можно заказать в отделе снабжения или попросить у утилизаторов.

</Document>
