<Document>
  # Xenoarchaeology

  Xenoarchaeology is a branch of Science focused on researching alien [bold]artifacts[/bold].

  Unlocking their secrets grants research points and reveals strange, potentially useful, or dangerous effects.

  At round start, Science usually has one or two artifacts in the lab. More can be:
  - Ordered from [color=orange]Cargo[/color]
  - Found by [color=orange]Salvage[/color]
  - Assembled from [bold]fragments[/bold]
  - Appear during certain station events

  ## Artifacts
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComplexXenoArtifact" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComplexXenoArtifactItem" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Artifacts contain [bold]nodes[/bold] arranged in [bold]layers[/bold].
  - Unlocking a node unlocks connected nodes on upper layers.
  - Each node has [bold]triggers[/bold], actions that must be performed near the artifact to unlock a node.
  - When a node is unlocked, its [bold]effect[/bold] will trigger, and the node becomes [bold][color=plum]Active[/color][/bold].
  - Each node has [bold]durability[/bold]: the number of times it can be manually activated after being unlocked.
  - Higher nodes are harder to reach but give more [bold]research points[/bold].
  - Unlocking all nodes provides no special bonus, but every node yields research points.

  ## Equipment
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineArtifactAnalyzer" Caption="Analyzer"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerAnalysisConsole" Caption="Analysis Console"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NodeScanner" Caption="Node Scanner"/>
  </Box>
  - [bold]Artifact Analyzer:[/bold] Stationary device that scans artifacts, sending data to the Console.
  - [bold][textlink="Analysis Console:" link="AnalysisConsole"][/bold] Stationary device that is used to display the node tree. Must be linked to an Analyzer with a multitool.
  - [bold]Node Scanner:[/bold] Small hand-held device that can show the ID of the node currently being activated and whether the artifact is ready to trigger, letting scientist have minimal required knowledge for operating inside chamber near artifact and far without direct access to console.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CrateArtifactContainer" Caption="Artifact Container"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldArtifactContainer" Caption="Handheld Container"/>
  </Box>
  - [bold]Artifact Containers:[/bold] Safely store and transports artifacts and prevent nodes from triggering.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineArtifactCrusher" Caption="Crusher"/>
  </Box>
  - [bold]Artifact Crusher:[/bold] Crushes artifacts into fragments. Four fragments can be rebuilt into a new artifact.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ArtifactFragment" Caption="Artifact Fragment"/>
  </Box>
  - [bold]Artifact Fragment:[/bold] Pieces of destroyed artifacts. Four fragments can be rebuilt into a new artifact using the craft menu.
</Document>
