<Document>
# Xenoarchaeology
Xenoarchaeology is a science subdepartment focused on researching and experimenting on alien artifacts.

## Artifacts
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComplexXenoArtifact" Caption=""/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SimpleXenoArtifactItem" Caption=""/>
</Box>
Artifacts consist of a randomly-generated graph structure. They consist of nodes connected to each other by edges, the traversal of which is the main goal of the scientists working on them.

Each node has two main components: a [color=#a4885c]stimulus[/color] and a [color=#a4885c]reaction[/color]. A stimulus is the external behavior that triggers the reaction. Some reactions are instantaneous effects while others are permanent changes. Triggering the reaction causes the artifact to move to one of the node's edges.

With these basic principles, you can begin to grasp how the different nodes of an artifact are interconnected, and how one can move between them by repeatedly activating nodes.

While it might seem random to an untrained eye, a skilled scientist can learn to understand the internal structure of any artifact.

## Artifact Analyzer and Analysis Console
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MachineArtifactAnalyzer"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerAnalysisConsole"/>
</Box>
The main equipment that you'll be using for Xenoarchaeology is the [color=#a4885c]artifact analyzer[/color] and the [color=#a4885c]analysis console[/color]. You can use these to create reports that contain valuable information about an artifact.

To set them up, simply link them with a network configurator, set an artifact on top of the analyzer, and press the [color=#a4885c]Scan[/color] button.

Using the console, you can extract points from the artifact using the [color=#a4885c]Extract[/color] button. The amount of points you extract is based on how many new nodes have been activated, since last extracting. You can extract multiple times, there is no reason not to!!!

## Assembling Artifacts
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ArtifactFragment" Caption="Artifact Fragment"/>

It is possible to gather multiple artifact fragments and assemble them into a working artifact. You can ask for these from Salvage, they usually find these while mining asteroids or on Expeditions.

</Document>
