<Document>
# Captain

<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ToyFigurineCaptain" Caption="Captain"/>

1. The Captain is not to perform normal Security duties. The captain is authorized to engage criminals in active crimes they have witnessed. The Captain may also assist if security staff is low.

2. Unless on [color=#ff0000]Code Red[/color], the Captain is not to procure armory weapons, unless directly authorized by the Head of Security. Additionally, the Captain may not requisition arms from science or cargo for themselves unless there is a direct threat to station or crew.

3. The Captain should make all reasonable accommodations to appoint a new head of staff should a position become vacant. The new head of staff should be a member of the department if possible.

4. The Captain should work with the Head of Security to ensure that corporate law is being applied properly.

5. The Captain is to remain on station at all times, unless otherwise authorized by command, or leaving with the crew on the evacuation shuttle.

6. The Nuclear Authentication Disk must remain with the Captain at all times. The Captain may also assign this duty to the Head of Security or Blueshield Officer.

7. Central Command contact should be the last resort for the Captain when dealing with head of staff disagreements.

8. The Antique Laser Gun is to stay in its case, unless there is an immediate threat on the station or it is [color=#2a6099]Code Blue[/color] or higher.

9. The Captain is not permitted to wear their hardsuit unless there's an active environmental danger or a threat on their life.

10. While the Captain may choose to alter SOPs in various circumstances, any attempt to fully disregard SOP is to be considered sufficient evidence for contract termination.

11. You may, as Captain, fire a head of staff with reasonable justification.

This list is not comprehensive, but may include:
- Incompetency.
- Criminal activity.
- Industrial negligence.

12. The Captain may not fire any NanoTrasen Personnel (Blueshield Officer, Magistrate, NanoTrasen Representative or the Internal Affairs Agents) without permission from Central Command, unless they are actively detrimental to the station and its crew.

13. The Captain may not hire any staff to a NanoTrasen Personnel position (see above).
</Document> 