<Document>
# Burn
<Box>
[color=Gold]Burn[/color]:
- [color=DeepSkyBlue]Heat[/color]
- [color=DeepSkyBlue]Shock[/color]
- [color=DeepSkyBlue]Cold[/color]
</Box>
Burn damage is the group of damage your patients take from being lit on fire, frozen in space, or shocked by electrical current.

## Treatment
Almost all of the current cures to burn damage target the [color=Gold]damage group[/color], but there is one exception.  The most common methods to cure burn damage are Ointment and a chemical called [color=#3688a3]Dermaline[/color].  In a pinch, a chemical called [color=#bf3d19]Kelotane[/color] can be used, however it is several times weaker than [color=#3688a3]Dermaline[/color]. These methods will cure all types of burn damage.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Ointment" Caption="Ointment"/>
</Box>

The best cure for the Cold [color=DeepSkyBlue]damage type[/color] is a chemical called [color=#ff7db5]Leporazine[/color] because even small doses can have immediate and radically benificial effects.

The most serious type of burn is the caustic burn.  These burns are caused by acid exposure or injestion. The only medicine for these types of burns are [color=#f4dab8]Siderlac[/color], [color=#e0a5b9]Sigynate[/color], or Cryo medicine ([color=#3688a3]Dermaline[/color] will not work).  Ointment is also very weakly effective at healing caustic burns, however you will only want to use it for minor burns.

## Visual Diagnosis
You can diagnose burn damage with a visual health inspection by refering to the following:
<Box>[color=DeepSkyBlue]Heat[/color]</Box>
<Box>25+ [color=DeepSkyBlue]Heat[/color] - [color=orange]They have minor burns across their body.[/color]</Box>
<Box>50+ [color=DeepSkyBlue]Heat[/color] - [color=orange]They have major burns across their body.[/color]</Box>
<Box>75+ [color=DeepSkyBlue]Heat[/color] - [color=orange]They have severe third-degree burns across body![/color]</Box>
<Box>[color=DeepSkyBlue]Shock[/color]</Box>
<Box>50+ [color=DeepSkyBlue]Shock[/color] - [color=lightgoldenrodyellow]They have electrical shock marks across their body![/color]</Box>
<Box>There are no inspection messages for [color=DeepSkyBlue]Cold[/color]</Box>
</Document>
