<Document>
# Chef
A fella has gotta eat, and it's the chef's job to make sure folks have something other than junk to munch on.

First and foremost, you'll need to familiarize yourself with the kitchen, and the tools available to you.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenKnife"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LargeBeaker"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReagentContainerFlour"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodContainerEgg"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCow"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VendingMachineChefvend" Caption="Chef Vendor"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenMicrowave"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenSpike"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VendingMachineDinnerware" Caption="Dinnerware Vend"/>
</Box>

## Kitchen Prep:

It's hard to put into words how to play chef without feeling like you're being given orders, but here are some basics.

- Check what you have on hand when it comes to ingredients, most kitchens have some Flour, Rice, Eggs, Monkey Cubes, and a few other things to get started with.
- Try your hand at mixing up some dough by putting water and flour together in a beaker. (Use the sinks!)
- Check the Wiki (or Food Recipes) guidebook for things you can make, and put all the listed ingredients into a microwave to cook it into a meal.
- Set up mouse traps. Yes, really. It's easy to see all your hard work disappear if you don't take precautions for mice infestations.

Once you're a bit more experienced and familiar with what you can make, it might be best to put together a few menus, or a "cheat sheet" so you can give a list of ingredients to botany.

## Mixing Dough:
Add Flour and Water together in a beaker. (Use the sink for water!)
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LargeBeaker"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReagentContainerFlour"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DrinkWaterBottleFull" Caption="water"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodDough"/>
</Box>
## Making Flour:
Place wheat in a grinder (with a beaker placed inside) and grind it up!
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenReagentGrinder"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LargeBeaker"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WheatBushel"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReagentContainerFlour"/>
</Box>
## Getting Plants:
Ask Botany for what you need, without a botanist, you may need to grow more plants yourself.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignHydro1" Caption=" "/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="hydroponicsTray"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WheatBushel"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignHydro2" Caption=" "/>
</Box>
## Gathering Milk:
Alt-Click on a Cow with a container in your hand. (Beakers, Buckets, Milk Jugs, ect.)
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bucket"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobCow"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DrinkMilkCarton"/>
</Box>
## How to Butcher:
In most cases, you should be able to use a knife directly on a creature that's dead. It's best to do this in the freezer, as the results are... messy.

Monkeys, however, (and other humanoids), need to be dragged onto a meatspike to be butchered.
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenSpike"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="KitchenKnife"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMonkey"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeat"/>
</Box>
</Document>
