<Document>
# Janitorial

You keep things clean, it's a rough job sometimes, but someone's gotta do it. This will walk you through the tools of the trade, and how they're used.

## Basic Equipment
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MopItem"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="JanitorialTrolley"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MopBucket"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Bucket"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TrashBag"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SprayBottleSpaceCleaner"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BoxLightMixed"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SoapNT"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Mousetrap"/>
</Box>

## Additional Equipment
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VehicleJanicart"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WetFloorSign"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Holoprojector" Caption="holosign projector"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LightReplacer"/>
</Box>
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="AdvMopItem" Caption="Advanced mop, ask in R&D"/>
</Box>

## Fluid Acquisition and Disposal
<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WaterTankFull"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Sink"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloorDrain"/>
</Box>

## Tidying up.
Now, onto the (figurative) meat and potatoes. We're here to clean, right? Lets keep it simple. The main tools you'll be putting to use are the trusty mop, a trash bag, space cleaner, and one of the three different buckets.

Mopping: Fill your cart up with water, then, find some puddles! Wet your mop, and wipe them up, the resulting water puddle will dry after a short time. Don't forget the wet floor signs!
- To drain your cart, drag it (with your cursor) onto a floor drain. This will dump all the fluids inside! Floor drains can usually be found somewhere in medical, the kitchen freezer, and of course, the janitor closet.

Trash: Place it in the bag directly, or hold it in your hand. Click -near- trash to scoop -all- nearby junk up, or click on each piece individually. Using the bag on a disposal will empty it.
- Cargo might want some of your trash, it might be worthwhile to check in from time to time!

Space Cleaner: This miracle spray can do two things, clean graffiti, and in a pinch, clean up puddles!
- You might be able to get more of this from chemistry.

## Extra Duties
A good janitor is always on the lookout for a bit more to do, and there are plenty of tools at your disposal. Keep an eye out for broken lights, help the chef take care of mice in the kitchen, and if you're feeling -really- generous, try to restock the vending machines and emergency closets around the station!

##Additional Information:
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="SpaceCleaner"/>
<GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Ammonia"/>

</Document>
