<Document>
  # Devil

  [color=#ac3a0d]A devilish trickster with a silver tongue making deals around the station.[/color]

  A devil is an entity originating from some ungodly dimension far, far away from our own.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PaperDevilContract" Caption="Contract"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingUniformJumpsuitDevil" Caption="Devilish Attire"/>
  </Box>

  Unlike most depictions in media, a devil isn't easy to find at a glance. There's no fire and brimstone, no pitchfork and screaming. The easiest way to tell is that red glow in their eyes, and sometimes the horns or tail.
  [bold] Not everyone with a tail or horns is a devil, that's just specist! [/bold]

  Despite their usually not-so-good intentions, a Devil is still considered crew!
  As a Devil, [color=red][bold] you should not interfere with station affairs unless you are directly asked, or you can make a deal out of it. [/bold][/color]

  Under normal circumstances, [color=red][bold] a crew member making a deal with the Devil should be considered a crime [/bold][/color]

  ## Contracts

  The bread and butter of a devil is their [color=darkred]contracts[/color]. When signing a contract, various effects can be applied onto an entity.

  Contracts are indestructible once signed, there's no going back once pen touches parchment.

  The particular effect of a contract changes depending on which [bold] clauses [/bold] are written on it.
  Effects can be applied to the Contractor, the Devil, or the Contractee, the signer.

  Prefixing a [bold]Clause[/bold] with either "Contractee:" or "Contractor:" will dictate who it applies to.

  A [bold]Clause[/bold] is a concept or thing that one of the parties is giving up, either to the other party or destroying it entirely.

  Example:
    Contractee: Weakness
    Contractee: Soul

  In the above contract, the contractee is giving up their weakness and the rights to their soul.
  Giving up your weakness will grant you massive resistance to all damage types, but giving up your soul could have unforeseen consequences.

  ## Contract Weight

  Every contract has a weight associated with it, which can be viewed by inspecting it.
  Contracts with an uneven weight (below zero) cannot be signed.

  Each clause has its own weight value.
  As a general rule of thumb, the better the clause is for the contractee the higher the weight will be.

  This effectively means you have to balance good clauses with bad clauses.
  [italic] It's important to note that there is no limit on how many bad clauses you can put on one contract, always read the fine-print! [/italic]

  ## Selling your soul?

  Selling your soul is a fickle thing; and usually what most devils are after.
  As a devil, your main objective is to collect as many souls as possible. The more souls you gain, the more powerful you become.

  As a contractee, selling your soul has consequences.
  - Without a soul, you will go [bold][color=red]STRAIGHT[/color][/bold] to hell on death. No more second chances.
  - You cannot make any more deals after selling your soul.
  - You will be marked as "Condemned", which could have other consequences.

  A Devil may want to be wary of the stations security team after purchasing a soul, [bold] as it can be considered prevention of revival. [/bold]

  ## No such thing as no second chances.

  A devil can increase their overall power level by collecting enough souls during the duration of their stay on station.
  Upon reaching the first level, they unlock the ability to create revival contracts.

  These contracts can be used on a corpse to offer that ghost a second chance at life.
  When accepting, they will lose their soul in-exchange for a second chance at life.

  ## Possession?

  A devil unlocks the ability to possess targets at the second level.
  Possession allows them to temporarily take over a targets body and do practically whatever they want.

  However, there are a few things they [italic] cannot [/italic] do:
  - Harm themselves or others.
  - Perform actions related to their implants or clothing.

  You may only possess targets that are vulnerable to it, such as people who have sold their soul.

  ## Won't you shake a poor sinners hand?

  As depicted in many different forms of media, a good old-fashioned handshake is practically unbeatable.
  Shaking hands with a devil will provide you with a quick and easy reward: Full health, and a second life.

  The cost? Well, let's just say it varies.
  You'll lose your soul immediately, and also gain one random negative clause from the list of clauses.

  ## Dealing with the devil.

  Sometimes, in pursuit of finishing their end of a deal, a devil can become quite troublesome for the stations inhabitants.
  Whether this be through it stealing items, or offering ungodly power to the stations enemies; it's clear to see why someone might want to get rid of one.

  Luckily for them, there's several ways to deal with a devil.
  - Pronouncing the true name of a devil will stun them.
  - A bible or holy water will burn a devil to the touch.
  - Chaplains can utilize bibles to banish a devil.

  As one would guess, a chaplain is more effective at facing a devil than most.
  Chaplains cannot be tricked to give up their soul, as they already pledged it to whatever God(s) they believe in.

  When a chaplain uses a bible on critical or otherwise incapacitated devil, they can temporarily banish them.
  For the next couple of minutes or so, that devil will be unable to sustain a material form.

  [bold]When a chaplain speaks a devils true name, it will harm them [color=red]significantly![/bold][/color]

  ## True or fake name?

  When a devil arrives at a station they take the form of a random crew member.
  Whether they are possessed, shape-shifted, or perhaps just a coincidental twin, they'll replace someone on station.

  What's important is that devil's [bold]cannot replace command staff or security members. [/bold]

  In all manners but one, a devil will appear with their false name.
  The only way to view a devils true name is to read a contract they have signed, or ask them directly.

  ## Trickery goes both ways!

  The contractee is not the only person that can be tricked.
  Contract weight is applied [bold] no matter who the effect applies to [/bold]

  This means if you can trick a devil to sign a paper negatively affecting them, you can get some positive clauses for free!

  [textlink="Learn more about each clause." link="DevilClauses"]
</Document>
